OK, and one last thing is you have to initialize the variables.
This is not a dictionary format, right?
So basically we are creating four variables here.
So it should be equal to not Gollan.
And the values of these variables are coming from file.
And we are now carefully placing in method to connect.
OK, so let me run this test and see that will not have any error.
So if any of that connection is not success.
Perfect, the process finished with exit zero, that means nothing exception is strewn with metal.
So that means we have successfully made connection to that server.
Now, what should we do?
What is our next goal?
So first, let's try to execute any command in your server from your Python code.
OK, you have made no connection, right?
Our next goal is to run commands.
And this is like Conexion.
Start connection so far that I will go back to my Linux terminal once.
So let's log, as I easy to use now, sort of asil hyphen, easy to use.
So this will help you to login back as easy to use again, because now we have connected to this user
only.
So do not touch any road related stuff directly.
Come to this user by logging in with your hyphen.
So you will be now part of this game so clear it will be on top.
Now, to see all the files in this location, there is one comment in line, Ellis hyphen.
Yeah, I'm just jealous this will give you the all the files present in this location.
So when you give Ellis.
No file is present.
OK, there are some invisible files also, but to see those invisible files, you have to do with a
hyphen.
With this extension, you will be able to see those invisible files.
Right.
So these are the files which are invisible present in this, but OK now.
I will try to run this comment from my Python code so that I should be able to see this output in my
local system.
OK.
That's what our ultimate goal is, right.
I don't want to hear comments from my Tahmina, from my python.
I will operate now.
Right.
So by default, Python will be accessible here because you locked in securely as easy to happen.
User Guide.
So you are on the homepage.
So whatever comments you get from Python, it will be a dislocation only in the user location.
So now I will go back.
So we have established a connection, right, and now with this object itself, as I said, there is
a method called execute command that's simply passed the command which you want to execute.
OK, so what is the Commonwealth syphoned you now when you run this command as it is successfully connected
to your server, this command will now get executer and this level, OK, and it gives the output right.
So the return type of this execute command is three different variables.
One is still am.
Let me explain what all this.
So some commands require inputs right now, when you go be it easy to have and use it for setting a
password.
It asks you to enter a new password so that you should again enter so that manuell input can be given
through this variable and output.
So whatever you received in the output that gets stored in this study out variable.
OK, and if there are any errors in running the command and those logs will get stored in this variable
like this, all the details once you execute, will get stored on these three variables.
Right now, we know that when you run this command, you will get output successfully.
And this is the output.
Right.
Let me go to the terminal.
These are the files you get.
So those will now carefully get stored in this variable after you run this command.
OK, now, once you get stored everything in this variable now to read all the lines, what you got
in this variable.
So there is a method called read lines.
This will read all the lines.
What you got in your output.
OK, I'll try to print so that you should see your output here.
All right, so let me give one more run and let's see what happens.
Perfect, you'll see that viscously bass line bass profile I see these are present here, Bartrop Python,
you are able to run this command on your server and once you get the output, you are able to get that
output into your python lookup.
OK, how did you do that?
So you executed a command.
The output will get stored here in a file.
So you are reading that file completely with Redlegs matter that will read all the content percent in
this variable file and you are printing it and this is what you got.
OK, great.
So this is now you can play.
Now let me do one thing.
I'll create one new text file here.
So to create any new text file, you can start with the VA space and.
Benmore, fine.
OK, this is like not notepad in windows, go to insert more by selecting a and you can type anything.
Hello, how are you?
And now you save the file with a skip column WQ so that file will be saved.
Now to watch and view the contents of that file, which you just created in Lennix, you can do that
with cat come in.
Cat Command will help you to view the contents present in the file to give him.
Hello, how are you?
Is sprinting right now.
Let's do one thing, this come on, I will give it from my executable command here.
So instead of a seven year, I will come into this line and I'll write one more.
It's very easy.
I guess you just need proper time for Galicians.
That's.
God, and what is that finding them of Eldrick?
OK, so you will run this command in that level now and whatever output you get will start here, right?
So hello, how valuable is one limb?
So let me add another line also.
You can go back to it in that file again with the voice space demo file and insert more and.
I read some number seven 120, so three lines of I'll say it with Escalon WQ and we would get all the
trillions of awesome.
Now I'll come back and I'll run this fight here.
Let's see what happens.
You see that?
Hello, how are you all seven, 120, all the three lanes are actually sent back, but this time they
sent back in the list format.
That's what we needed, OK?
When it sent in the list of format.
Now, if you want to extract the second line, it's very easy for you, isn't it?
So what you can do started that in one variable.
And this is now list of eight in the list, if you want to access the second number, you can see the
index of one.
So zero index would be, hello, how are you?
And first index will be seven and three.
Index will be 120 now printed.
And you should see the output at seven.
Index.
I know why this error, because you should not go to times, read lines matter because you already read
all the lines, what else you have, because in the content with this method, first you read those
three lines, right.
And then again, you ask to read them.
Nothing left.
So it ran into that.
So let's come down this good.
It's good that it failed because this way you can understand what is the actual wrong here.
And now we run again and you should see the seven in your output.
Perfect.
So that's how you can play and the extract the content of your output to back to your system and also
execute commands.
OK, so let's continue in the next lecture.
Thank you.