Welcome, guys, welcome to Back End Automation Testing with Python.
This is your instructor, Rahul Shetty.
So first, we will try to understand why we require this back and automation and how this course will
help you to become Pythonesque did with the knowledge of automation testing on every level of Uber software
lifecycle.
Right.
So firstly, this backend automation came into the limelight from last few years.
It's beginning the most Basinski work wife.
So earlier when we say automation, it's all about end automation, like automating your browsers.
Very one application is rendering, but due to agile practices, faster feedback and more of quality
practices.
Now testing is done in every layer.
It's not only fronton, so testing should be also performed in the middle layer.
Very apposite.
And it's also required in the backend layer where you have SQL Server databases setting and your bank
jobs will also be there.
So to give the faster feedback of how your application is behaving, so now people are depending upon
each and every layer and they have a quality check, get on every layer of your software project.
So this is where backend automation testing comes into beta.
So any type of testing which is not part of your browser automation, comes and fall under this back
in automation, right?
And this is where a state rules comes into picture as a Pythonesque, that you will not be responsible
only for your Frontin automation with Selenia, you should also have knowledge on testing various layers
of your entire project.
So you should be able to perform EPA testing.
You should be able to retrieve the data from your databases with Python code.
And you should also be able to connect to your service by establishing a connection and execute bad
jobs.
So as an estimate, you will be responsible to perform any kind of automation in your End-To-End full
stack project.
OK, so this course will help you to fulfill that gap by teaching all the automation utilities provided
by the python to perform these operations.
And as a switch, this is very important.
So ideally, if you have any real time experience, you can correlate the scenario that there are some
bad jobs which will run in the backend.
So that will have an effect of showing some data on the front end.
OK, so these days people are expecting to test those bad jobs as well by passing the parameters and
see how that bad jobs is responding.
So basically bad jobs give the data in the form of discern XML CSP files.
So one should be able to send parameters to those bad jobs and received a response and pass those days
and find CSP files to see if the outcome is expected and these bad jobs will sit somewhere in the Linux
servers.
So from your local mission, you should create an associates connection to talk to the bad jobs which
are sitting in Linux servers and execute the bad jobs from those Linux servers.
So there is a lot of automation involved here.
So as an astute engineer, you should be able to create a solution for all this process and execute
you your validation on these back and utilities.
OK, and this goes also give us one more utility call scrapping.
So this is also one of the interesting thing, because you can actually scrap your webpage and extract
the content out of it.
This is heavily used for data science projects and I would also cover that.
So that way you will have some additional knowledge of how to scrub the data in Web pages using Python.
Right.
So that's how this is targeted to teach all the utilities.
But do remember, before we start any cost content, we will also have python basics.
If you are not aware of Python, you need not worry because we have exclusive to enough of US content
after this video so that you can learn a python from scratch and then you can start going through this
content.
And one thing you should understand that.
So we will complete this course in different projects.
OK, so in Project one, you will understand about how to patriotisms using Python code and how to read
the different file and write back to disinfects, because this knowledge is important for the API automation.
So when you are performing API automation, you should be able to receive the response.
Mostly response will be in this.
So you should be able to pass the jassam and understand so far that this knowledge is required.
So once we receive that knowledge and then we will go back to API automation.
So that's our Project one.
And next, as a project, I will show how to connect to database and retrieve that data from sequel
tables using Python sequel Connector.
And we will read the data from multiple results from database tables using Python.
And then I will show how to integrate database results to API calls to deliver a decent payload to submit
Europea request.
So this way you will understand how to talk to databases, how to automate APIs, everything using Python
code.
Right.
And that's a project number two.
And next, we'll go to project number three.
Again, this is an independent.
Each project is independent and which will be not connected to previous project because in this course
we will go over many utilities, OK?
And 60 percent, you should have this knowledge because if you work with any bad jobs, the output of
bad jobs will be mostly like CSP files.
So here we will try to understand how to pursue CSB files, how to read and write to files using your
Python code.
And then I will start showing one interesting project again.
By creating one A.W. Islamic server.
Don't worry, I will show you the process, like how to set up one Linux server, you can get it from
Amazon Web Services.
We will launch one Linux service.
And I will show how to establish connection to servers from your local Python using your credit card
paramedical.
And we will send the comments to Linux server to execute your bad jobs.
This will be very interesting and we will download the files from another server to our mission.
See, all this will happen in real time.
So that's why I'm saying if you have real time experience working in any backend work like manual work,
at least you can appreciate about automating all this process.
So generally, all these bad jobs will be insecurely in some of our missions.
So people generally log in manually and do all these activities.
Yes, but you can automate and this is where people are looking now as an engineer, they want Python
Guy to do all these operations.
Right.
And then finally, I will show one special topic, which is a bonus of importance of scrapping.
So if you work with Python, then you should definitely have some light on this one scrapping stuff.
This is heavily used in data science projects, so you can learn more about it in the project.
No.
And one important thing, so initially when I made this to Dorien, so this is confined to explaining
only Python utilities for backend automation work, but with a lot deep dive into any test framework
discussion.
So that is the initial plan I had.
But later on with people and many students, feedback that they need one framework to understand and
automate this API test cases, then I have added ability framework which will help you to design from
scratch and automate all your AP automation test cases using that ability behavior framework.
OK, so I have added that framework after a complete chaos and then again on student feedback, submitted
a framework for API.
Automation is now available for discourse.
You can find that once you have completed this project one and two, and then we will use this framework
to automate API discusses what we discussed.
OK, so this statement is now partially incorrect, so let's go and strike this part.
So but basically the main focus of discourse is all about explaining the core python utilities because
you will learn how to talk and make network connections using patternmaker utility.
You will know where scaping, utilities, CSFI, Excel utilities, aliased connections, API, automation,
database automation.
You will see a lot of backend automation, utilities for bad jobs, automation.
Right.
So that is the main focus of this course.
But I also adorability framework so that you will know how to create and how one backend automation
framework for your API automation.
OK, so this is the superabundance you will get from this goes.
OK, so that's pretty much high level introduction about what you can expect from this back in automation,
but by the end of this course, you can claim yourself as a pilot on Nasdaq and you can apply any jobs
related to Paten automation testing.
So that's it, guys.
So let's get started with Python basics in the next section and take it from the visual.
All the best and see you in the next section.
Thank you.