Welcome back.
So let's come back to our API test, what we have written in our previous sections.
So ad book Paillard, this is the method, right?
So what exactly this method is doing?
So this matter is sending one dictionary back to your work test, isn't it?
This is a dictionary, right?
So you type of body and you'll see what it brings.
It brings a dictionary because that's the format.
OK, so this is a python variable called study and once this dictionary variable reaches here.
So when you're right, Jason equals to that dictionary automatically.
Jason is very smart in converting that dictionary to actually do some format and it submits to your
request.
So that's the concept.
OK, that will automatically taken by this Jason parameter.
But ultimately you are writing one dictionary and giving it to you different value.
OK, so if you read the official documentation.
Here, instead of encoding the dictionary, basically, you can also pass it directly.
That's what we did.
So we directly passed the dictionary.
So this is a dictionary we directly posted using the design parameter and it will be encoded automatically.
So that means basically our our payload should be in decent format when you submit to the request.
You see that that's a decent format.
But here with the dictionary, we are submitting and this encoding is happening automatically right
now.
So our goal is to create this dictionary dynamically now, instead of hard coding the values here,
these values want to come from database.
OK, there could be a scenario in your life project where this input payload should be seeded from a
database.
It could be because of any scenario.
Right.
So if that is a requirement, mostly in backend projects, this API plus database will be commonly used
as integrated software.
Right.
So if that is a requirement of getting the values from Debe, let's see how to do that.
So one thing what we understand here, ultimately, this is a big dictionary, so I will create one
function again and I would call it as.
Build paillard from DBE.
OK, and here so we need to create one big study.
So what I can do.
I will first start with one empty dictionary ad, but this is one of the dictionary initializing, right?
This has nothing in it.
Now, our goal is to start feeding values as a key value base.
OK, so you can start adding key value bits into your dictionary like this and body.
And this is the key, right?
You can say the name and the value.
OK, so if you don't remember how to add values, key values to a dictionary, please.
I taught my Python basic section.
I have clearly explained there like how to create an updated study and add values into it.
OK, I'm just adding all these.
No.
So the value here should be from database, so let's hold on that.
Now let me prepare this case and body ISBN equals to.
Hello, and let me create two more.
It will be interesting, guys, just follow me and you will get it soon.
So fast is all, and the last one is Arta.
OK, so once you create like this at the end, you have to return the dictionary, the term.
Her body.
OK, miss.
Could be rewritten as dictionary little.
OK, you can say it like this, but that will.
That's fine.
You can have it like this.
Do we have any other variable with that body here?
No.
Right.
OK, then that should be fine.
OK, so now our goal is to fit with the database values.
Now.
So here you have to first connect to your database and then give the query.
So let's assume that we need the first Odegaard.
So if you give this query select start from looks, this will return all the results.
Right from that, you can use fetch one to get the first record.
OK, so randomly you need to pick one record from your table and create decent.
OK, so let's first form connection and have that equity, but instead I want to write us one letter
like this.
So get Querrey.
So this matter should basically get me the record.
That's what we need to do.
OK, so this should get me the apple.
So what exactly Regardful written, if you go back to your database validations, you'll see that when
you look at one role will be written.
That's nothing but a couple.
Right.
And when you do that, Rob Foster, the card will be written here in that Apple.
Similarly, in our paillard find to assume that this is the double and Leitman method.
So that should return you the to double so that you can smartly place like this BP of zero, so that
from that table when you have zero, APM will be picked off one lesbian couple of two.
This is how you need to feel.
So now our key point here is to implement this method, which will give you the results.
So you can let it get itself, create function, get committee, let's have it here all, you can buy
it from your configurations.
It's up to you from where you want to get it.
So let me do one thing as this is Beyler related.
Should be right there in.
Where is that data, some configurations let's look at here, because here where we have all the data
business, right.
OK.
Get committee.
So first, you have to form the connection, so get connection is a method which will help you to create
connection, right?
So you blindly call that method and you'll get a connection as a return, as a connection object.
So connection equals to get connection.
OK, next step, you have to create a streamlined concert.
So let's create that cursor and how that object.
Now, you need to execute that.
That's not.
Execute and the query.
So basically this query should not be hardcoded here because it clearly is a method which will create
connection and it will execute query.
It could be any query.
OK, if you hardcourt, that means only you want to post API for test only can use that.
OK, if all the best together should be able to use this get query method to hit query and to get results.
Right.
So let's do one thing I would query here and this query, we will drive it from our actual test.
OK, that should not be hard coded here.
So just follow.
You will get it soon.
So some query, I don't know that it will get executed.
OK, so once you execute this, Kasota will hold all the results right.
From all those results.
Let's fix the first one because we need one Bellegarde so that you can prepare the descent and you will
get that first regarding a row, which is nothing but tuple.
OK, now let's return this double and that's on.
And let's close the connection because our work is done.
So let's not open multiple things.
We open the connection.
We closed because we got our first record tuple and we are returning it.
Awesome.
So right now, that is not going to here.
Let's bring that soon.
OK, now I will go back to post API example and we thought of calling a new method this time.
Right.
New method is a bit paillard from beby.
OK, so let's use that method and the inside.
Let's give our query.
OK, I will define query variable here.
What is our query variable.
So this is the query we are interested.
Right select to start from box.
OK, and I will place this committee here.
OK, now let's try to understand what's happening here.
So this method will get executed and we are sending goriest parameter.
Let's go inside and.
Once we are inside, this great metal is expecting one day, so whatever quality you send from your
method will fall here and from here we will capture and send it here because this mother is expecting
a great quarry, OK?
And this dead body is not in this glass.
So that's why you are getting this error.
So let's import that.
So from which file we have written configurations, right?
Utilities.
Dark configurations.
Import stuff.
OK, now you see that that is gone, so the query, whatever you got from your test is being sent to
your payload and from here it comes here and we are sending it to get perimeter.
So that query will be sent here.
And from here we are executing.
So this is how we connected.
You see that how it is connected to multiple flights so that this method is a unique and it's not hard
coded.
So anyone can use this method with their own queries for that particular test without hard coding.
Awesome.
OK, so this Rick Dunstable, you know what, I guess that's what we have seen, right?
This will return the faster or fatal one.
If you remember, we have that same video when we printed up.
We got a couple.
And now to either throw that law, when you said Roaf, zero in that first item will be picked.
OK, now we will go to Paillard and add Bardy name.
So book name is the first one.
So in that double zero index is a book name so that we are sending instead of this and next I SBN in
that first one.
So first one is I guess being the second one is a third one is Orta.
So first one is Espin and in that double whatever the second one is aisle and third one is Orta.
So that's how we retrieve the results.
And from dateable we will read one by one and we send to our dictionary.
So basically here we just created one dictionary, ultimately one big study we created and we are sending
this dictionary back to your test.
That's what we did here as well.
OK, so here we created this study, but we directly given all the values and we are sending it.
So once you send your big study back to here, as I've shown, it has a mechanism to encode your dictionary
back to you, Jason.
All right.
So this is how now I think you are building a pillar dynamically from the data.
This isn't it looks interesting.
I don't know how this will run.
Let's run this.
And if it fails, we will debug and fix the issue.
OK.
Awesome, guys, I think it worked.
You see that?
Connection successful, and it is successfully added and bookies also successfully deleted, OK, this
insecure request warning is related to last, but verify equals to false as we are suppressing SSL connection.
Is just giving us warning.
All right.
So this looks interesting.
So the new it created is A, B, C and four, three, four, three.
Let's see if it is the right one.
I tolerate any any combination of ISBN, and I'll.
What is that?
Oh, let me call this again.
Is that FBC for three?
Four, three and 43, Purrfect, so this is the water we have successfully added and now that table,
whatever you added, is dynamic and there is no one here.
Do we have those values here?
Nothing disconnected to our database through our python mystical connecter extract.
That value created the dictionary on flight and sent to this dictionary to your best and this and go
back to Gissen and then is submitted to the AP.
That is how we will have to build integrated solution talking starting from your database and to your
best.
OK, and we have smartly done that by building a lot of utilities.
OK, so I hope you noticed that we have not hardcourt anything, any of it.
Everything is driven externally from this.
So you can use this project, it's available for download from next lecture.
You can download it and you can leverage this, OK, it's up to your imagination so you can create some
tables in your database, call them and try to use them in.
Maybe just play it on according to your imagination.
But as I said, in real time, this is how things will work if you are going with python automation
for and stuff.
OK, guys, thank you.