All right, so in this election, we will see some miscellaneous concepts in the testing, like how
to create session manager and how to send and manage cookies, redirection time.
And as I told in the last lecture, how to send attachments through your API calls.
Right.
So let's get started with what is station manager and how do we use that in our API request.
OK, so let me go back to the editor.
So earlier we have written one test enforced API example.
OK, so let's take this example now here of so you hit this end point, GitHub, dot com slash user
saw to hit this end point, you actually need to authenticate yourself, because to get that specific
user, you have to give credentials so that, you know, you got a proper response here in the output
of its data score 200.
OK, so now let's say you want to hit another GitHub API.
So get her a beer.
So let's get started with just 13, you'd have a.
OK, so here I will choose a repositories.
So there are a number of API requests you have in GitHub, so let's say you want to hit this request
list repositories for the authenticated user.
So this is an API, which will give you the list of repositories for the user right now to use this
API.
This is an end.
This is a resource basically slash user slash repos.
So you already have an API GitHub.
Dotcom is the best you are on this Bestival.
You have to add this resource to this end point.
OK, let me show that.
Let's say you are two equals two.
So this is a big and point.
And after this, they were asking to use the slash you use up and slash the rebels, so basically.
This end point will give you the information about a list of repositories for the user you logged in.
OK.
Right.
So for this, you are sequel to Let's Hit the Request.
So this is a get request, right?
Or requests dark.
Get and.
So you just need to pass this, you are an.
OK, right, so you can hear this request, obviously, it will give you the Adam with the four one
four one stands for unauthorized.
So if you get the status of Roven forever AIPA constant.
So that means there is some authentication required, which you have not sent while making your request
to.
So let me get a response equals two and print response.
Dark status scope.
Like, so here I did not stilson any authentication, because if you see here, so this is a list of
repositories for authenticated user of which user you are asking.
So if you don't give the details, how would you have known for the tools that we are asking?
So obviously you will you will have to add this authentication, just like we have done in the previous
lecture based authentication.
OK, so let me comment about all this code.
So this is related to the of a great.
So I will just run this course, first of all, and see what is the output I am getting.
You see that you guard for one as output because you are not authorized.
So let's authorize and give the proper 200 status.
So if we get 200 documents or request access.
OK, so here we tend to use that name in the last the economy.
This is the correct username and you have to send authentication articles to.
Get password.
So now we're on this again.
Selective Service to 200.
But one thing to observe here is it's redundant every time when you make a good call for that user.
Now, here, for example, there are a lot of apps.
You have a list repositories for authenticated user or updated repository get replace the repository
disable alerts.
So, so many apps have that.
If you want to use all this for the average user, you have to end up writing authentication.
So why can't the general generalize this and write it on that globally so that it applies to all GitHub
related words?
OK, so that's the station manager comes into the picture.
So here, if you want to create a session, first of all requests.
So whatever you want to come, you have to start with requests only because from this library only you
have all the matters available.
So requests start session.
You see, that section is a method which will help you to create one session for you so you can just
really see any variable name you can give.
So on this session.
OK, so this session is nothing but like requests only, but it created one session stream for you on
this session as C dot org.
So there is a method available for authentication of equal stuff.
Then you can carefully password authentication as an input to this session.
OK, so now this session is aware that it has to do some authentication.
OK, so now in your actual test you can get rid of requests and you can see it's dark get.
Right.
So what is the difference between a reckless target and session target?
So both are safe, but this shouldn't have a capability and it has knowledge of authentication as well.
So decision equals to request a normal request library plus any other.
It is still configuration you provide as part of your decision.
OK, so here, when you say AC, this will already have authentication knowledge.
So you need not again provide this in your test.
OK, you can directly send with you order so automatically when you make a off target you want to do
so.
This will first authenticate because we have added that property to your session object.
It will have to get and then hit this you are.
So this way you can ever writing it in your all get help.
You are in places OK, because this is a common Faryab request.
So there is no point in repeating it all the time.
So create a section manager like this and your property and reuse this instead of request.
That's OK.
So when you run this again, it should still show you two hundred.
You see that there is no change even after your remote authentication because everything is taken over
by station manager.
You can actually remove here also.
You can also you can read more and you can use that, so just for a sample example.
I'm not changing it.
So this is how we can continue to work on all of have apps using such monitor.
So I hope this helps you to understand how to use this.
I will still use this when I talk about cookies, you can still add cookies to your station manager,
so you need not add cookies to your request every time we are talking minutes later.
Thank you.