Welcome, guys.
So in this section, let us see how to perform AIPA automation testing using Biton.
OK, so far that we have to download one library available by Python.
So the requests library Python.
So when you search for this, you will have something in their official documentation request.
OK, so this library we were using to automate all our API related testing.
So you can just download this from the official website, you need to basically add this package to
your Python request to that seven zero.
So you just need to install requests that it will automatically get the latest version of Python and
it will say to your local Python package.
OK, so you can read the documentation here of how to automate all this.
But don't worry.
I will explain you what all we need to automate.
Right.
So I will go back to my editor and here I would say in style.
So we have configured Python part globally in our system variable rate.
So you can start installing it from any part because there is already a global variable part setup for
this python and.
So fight instead of requests I already have in my mission, so it might tell me that it's installed,
but in your case it will get downloaded when you get this.
OK, so you need to download this package, then only you will be able to use this package and it.
So it's downloading, things are going fine.
All right, so it's successfully installed.
OK, good.
It's trying to index, so let me create one new file on file, and this time I would say a validations.
OK, so you first start with import costs, so this is the first thing you have to give.
So here it complains that unused imports statement because because we have not yet used this variable
anyway.
So that's why you will see this growing body that will go away very soon.
Right now, where is the EPA, so we just thought we have to perform EPA testing right so far.
Let me take one real time example.
Let's go back to our website and Iowa City Academy dot com and come to practice projects.
So here I have given a bunch of apps to practice.
So let's select a library, eBay.
And that will redirect you to one Google Drive page where you have access, I have prepared this API
just for practice.
OK, nice.
So this is the best you all.
So that means this is the server where my appx is hosting.
So I have taken one server and this is the IP address of that server and here where I hosted this library.
So to access this appx basically this is about adding the books into the database and deleting the books
and retrieving the books, using the alternate.
So I will explain what this API does in high level in this lecture, and then we will start automating
from our next lecture.
OK, the first API, what we have used to add book into that database.
So if I provide this endpoint and if I call this API and you have to send the body payload like this,
OK, and the method by this post, then this payload will be sent to this API and that will get stored
back in.
So that way you will get this output in the response from your API.
So when you call this API with this payload, it will get a response saying Bookit successfully added
and it will assign a unique idea for your book.
So that unique idea is a combination of ISBN and.
So similarly, if you want to retrieve the books from your database using the author's name, you can
prevent the other name and that will give you all the books written by that other.
And you can retrieve the book based upon the 80 number.
OK, so first, when you add a book, you get a response like this, right, with 80 captured daily.
And if you want to retrieve the details, that is another AIPA, which you can just need to send that
80 and automatically it gives you the complete book details.
And fourth one is it the first one is adding.
And last you can delete the book by sending this book in as an input and then you get this as a response.
The book will get deleted.
Right.
So these are the bunch of operations we have.
So I have a.
A postman told where I can show you visually how this app works, guys.
One thing you need to understand here, I'm not going in depth to explain what is what is and point
what is requestion response, because that is out of scope of discourse.
In this course, we are only seeing about how to automate manual API testing process.
But if you are not aware of what is API testing, then I would recommend you to watch my YouTube to
the audience because that is one playlist which explains what is API and how does it work in real time.
So you can get the basics there and you can come back to see how to test it.
Right.
Because if I start talking about what is API, that itself will take a few hours of time, which we
will completely get deviated.
So but still, I mean, high level explain what is the API we are going to do in the schools and then
we'll see how to automate it.
Right.
So this is the Adbul and this is the end point where you need to hit you need to call this API from
this end point.
So that book will be added into the database.
So these are the details you have to send as a body, right.
So let me say a real city to the other.
And you can give any ISP and I'll make sure you give the unique combination because the book is already
present with this combination, it will tell you that existing database.
So once you give the readings by the unit and Henders.
Request so that it will talk to back in September and it gives a response like this successfully added.
So using Python we have the automated.
So we have to create one request which have all these details, and we have to submit to the API so
that you will get a response like this back, Anderson.
And you have to pass the Gissen and retrieve the idea out of it.
OK, that's an ebook.
And if you want to get any book by attorney so you can simply give the other name.
So right now you're are a book of Travelocity to write so you can provide an opportunity to sort out
a name and submit.
So it will give you all the books present in the database with this other right.
So in the ad book, ISBN Bases at 227 is what you just added.
So in response, we got back.
Right.
But there is another book also with the same guy.
So like this this is how we get a response.
And here we are using get request for and for and what we are doing post request.
Similarly, you can delete the book so once you get a combination of it.
So take this and you can pass inside the book and the subject and that book will get deleted and you
will get a message.
OK, so book does not exist because you see that around the Economy.com is that you are using, but
previously this is the you are we have used OK, so let's replace it.
I actually have this AIPA in that to serve as one on my own website.
I was at the Academy dot com and I have here as well and both databases are different.
OK, so the database video added book is in the server.
But when you try to retrieve from that server, that's why I'm saying I don't have that book and now
it will give you the correct one because you are hitting a database so bogus, successfully deleted.
All right.
So that's about how you can test manually this library app.
Our goal is to automate this, which we will start from our next lecture because we have already downloaded
this request package, which will help us to automate that.
Right.
Thank you.