Welcome, guys.
So in this module, we will see how to read and write from CSP files.
So this is very important to understand because in back in our server side automation, you will be
running some batch files, which I will be talking very soon.
So you will connect to some Linux machines and you will run some bad files.
So those batch files will generally generate CSFI file or text files.
OK, so how to read texta files?
We have already seen in the Python basic section so you can refer it so that we have already completed,
but we have not yet seen how to read CSB files.
And I would also write back to that file.
OK, so let's try to understand that in this section.
So let me create one new python file.
Ceasefire demo.
It should be very simple, gets any topic in Python is simple, OK, there is no complex involved in
it.
No matter how much deep the concept is, that implementation will be very easy.
So let me create one CSP file first.
You can directly do it from your notepad.
So Delimiter is karma what we can select for the CSFI?
So I can say name and status.
OK, so it's like Laun status, so there are multiple guys who have applied for the loan and their status
is approved or rejected, something like this status resectable and.
Approver.
And.
So basically, I am separating each and every value with comma, so I hope you have basic knowledge
and to be fine.
So if you write like this, even you can open this file from Excel application as well.
Right?
So basically, there are total four rows here.
This is a header name status.
Let me add one more and stop this.
Jim.
All right, so save this file.
And you can say we didn't do a project, only back in automation is a project, right?
So here itself, let's save this project as.
Should we write in utilities?
Yeah, let's build it here, because there are some configuration files present here, right?
Loan app Dart, CSC.
Perfect, so you can.
Minimize that and you'll see that loan and NTSB file is created free, so when you open this so this
is how the same you have written in your notepad issuing here.
So there will be one specific plugin which I already installed.
So it will show up for you to install that.
Once you install and restart your editor, you will have another tab here.
So in that table, Ed, you will see like this.
OK, so you will be prompted to have that plug in once you open this file, you'll see that how nice
neatly it got organized into one table because we have clearly given that it should be separated using
comma delimited automatically, it will choose this delimiter and created a table like this.
OK, now you can open this file in Excel format also.
So copy the path.
And now let's go back to the.
We know Explorer.
You see that it's opening in Excel standard.
Yeah, so this is how it opens up when you try to open.
OK, so this is the CSP file.
So now our goal is to read this file.
So first, let's understand some basics and then do some logical exercises on this file.
OK.
So go back to see us with our demo.
There is already one in the package available in Python to read and write on CSFI files, you just need
to import it, import CEV.
And that's OK.
This is the package available.
OK, so now our goal is to read all the rules of that file.
OK, so that's our first goal.
So to read all the rules first, you have to open that file.
Right.
And you know how to open any file using Python.
You have to start like this with open and take the part of this you can just get.
Coffee pot or coffee pot?
So better we will take a relative, but this is long.
And this will automatically detect that.
Nice, and we have to open this file.
So let's give one object so that this object will have knowledge of the file content because that opens
this file, right?
Now, so there is a method in this package.
So see, as we Darth Vader.
So here you want to read that file, right?
So Reader is a method which will help you to read the content of the CSB file.
OK, so which file to read this file.
So this file is referenced with this object.
Right.
So you can simply give that object as an argument to this reader matter column here.
OK, and you should also tell how should I read basically this is the fine and you should also mention
Delimiter.
You never guess Delimiter is karma because that's how we created we feel.
Right.
So if you go to a text, you see that that's how it divided into tables.
So you have to give the file object, which it has to read and also the delimiter.
These are the two arguments you have to pass for over the other method which is available in CSC package.
OK, so this will become an object which have all the rules.
OK, so but this is a reader object.
This is not a list are tuple or dictionary.
This is a real object.
So not to convert this reader object into list, you can actually see a list of iest reader so that
it will be converted into the list of items and you can print it.
So if you are wondering what happens if I print directly this, let's also see that so I can show you
how the reader object will display.
Awesome.
Yeah, so this is the first program, so now let me run this.
This has to open this long, obnoxiously fine and it has to read all the content, doesn't it?
Rick Santorum's left after.
All right, you see that first output is a real object, it does not have any real data, but then we
converted this radar object into list and this is how we displayed in the list.
There are, again, lists of lists.
Basically, this is the main list inside this.
The first of all, Cayman's first list them some Ranma.
Everything is present here.
OK, now.
If you want to iterate through that complete list so you can directly do it on a relatively narrow object
on it now, fun brought in, see a spirit of object.
But what happens?
So let me comment on this now, let's not equate.
So basically, this horse multiple roles right now.
And.
Let's understand what the reformat fight, let's do that.
Come on, I'll shift into.
OK, now, so that either through each and every rule of this one.
So there is that Excel sheet, which we just open.
OK, so in the first iteration, the law will be having control of this first rule.
And when you say print roll, that will be printed, the second iteration it again, closer to my third
iteration like this, all the rules will be printed in the output because we are iterating through this
reader object and in every iteration, every rule will be picked and we are just printing that rule,
OK.
So this is just a variable.
You can give any variable name here.
OK, same thing.
Now when you run this, this time it will present and print different products because that's how we
are retrieving.
Right.
First of all, second or third row based on the FADELA.
Now, let's do one logic here.
So our goal is to push all these names into one list and all this status into another list.
OK, let's play around this basically.
So I'll create two lists.
So names is one list right now, it's a pretty similar list stats, if it is approved, loans are approved
or rejected.
There are two lists are created.
So when we iterate through every rule, you'll see that this is the list, right.
Rolls the list.
Now, if you want names, how do you axelsson print a roll of zero?
OK, for the first generation, this will be big.
So when you say zero name blueprinted instead of one status will be printed.
OK, so now let me run this again.
And this time it has to print all the names.
You see that it printed all the names, names and all the names are printed, similarly, when you the
one, all the statements will be printed.
So now our goal is to push all the names into this names list and all the stats into the stacks list.
So instead of printing it, I will add to this names list.
So to add a new element into your existing list, because this is our existing list, which is blank.
So I would simply say names DOT is a method which will help you to.
I the name in the list, similarly stats, let's open Ruoff one because of one, we will get the details
about our.
Status, right?
And that's OK.
So basically, we have a president with all the items now once come out of this for loop for lupus iteration
has done this names.
Listen, I will hold all the names and this tax list will hold all the status.
OK, so let's try to print this names.
And also print steps, I'm just showing you how to retrieve the data and store it into list tuples.
So this way you can manipulate and use whatever use case you have.
They let me run this again, perfect, you see that all the names we have securely stored in one list
and all stacks we have securely stored in, you know, the list.
So let's continue our logic in our next lecture.
Thank you.