Welcome, guys.
So in this section, I will show how we can make and I said connection to Linux, a server from your
local mission.
OK, so assume that there is a batch job which is present in your server.
This is different server.
So from your local mission, you have to write the Python code, which should connect, establish connection
to that Linux server through its protocol and then execute the batches of present on that server from
your local python code.
So this is one of the common scenario you will see in backend automation.
So this will end.
Python is heavily used to solve this problem in any project.
So in this section, we're going to see how to achieve and solve this problem with Python code, right.
So far that we need Linux server.
Right.
So when we are making some connection to lambic server and running some bad job, so that means there
should be a Linux server for me to show and for you to practice.
So I will be using A.W. Linux because that comes for free.
Parvenu, though it is free, you will have a minimal charges, which you have to know because if you
download or upload, it will give you some minimal charges.
So I request you to watch the video very next video about charges.
It would be around fifteen hundred to two thousand rupees in Indian currency and around for a dollar
in US dollar.
So about that much cost, it will be incurred if you launch a new A.W., for instance, and solve this
entire assignment.
Ballylee with me.
OK, so if you are okay to do that, so please go ahead, because for me there is no other solution.
So you will not have any server available for free to play around.
So L'Avenir something which is free, but this is about like data transfer.
If you don't learn anything from Internet, that would take some minimal amount of.
What it touches.
So I would recommend you to watch the next video and see how to stop it after you complete your operations.
That is very, very recommended for you to watch.
Next video on this subject.
If you are okay to pay this.
If not, then just watch this video and have this concept in your memory so that you can use whenever
you get in your real time.
OK, so now I will show how to Forslund instance.
You need an account for that and then you can quickly launch it will go for it and then see about what
is the pricing before we actually start with all configurations.
First, let's set up our line somewhere, OK?
Let's go to the official website management console.
Now you can sign up and give all your details great and second, it might ask you credit card details
as well or debit card details you should provide them.
And once you provide and when you sign into your console, let me sign in.
So once you sign in, you will be landing on this page.
So these are the different services are provided by 11 years.
So we are interested in easy to service, so select services.
And here you can select AC2 and then you will be landing on this page.
Right.
So these are running instances, dedicated host, you will see all these here so you can actually direct
launch in.
So to get started launching Amazon, easy to instance, which has a virtual server.
This is what I am talking about.
And in our case, we are interested to have Linux virtual server.
So just start with the launch in Stent's.
And this way, you will be shown multiple images available in Amazon cloud.
OK, so these are different operating systems you have and you can start your server with these operating
systems.
You have Windows, Linux, Ubuntu, the lot of things here.
So here we just need this one, Amazon, Linux, because it have some inbuilt software assessment.
So let's use this 64 bit.
And there are different versions available, like based upon how much memory it should allocate to your
server.
So by default, only three dead is eligible for one version and you don't have any other option to just
choose that option and select next.
And these are a different network related configuration settings.
We are all to go with default settings because our goal here is to just practice as a demo and we are
not doing any networking to make it secure.
OK, so next and storage.
So you can add multiple stories like how much do you need, how much ram sized or how much size gigabytes
you need to store all your data.
So the default, whatever it's showing here, is self sufficient for us to work and play on with this
demo concept.
So just click on next, but not change any settings here.
Right.
So here you can give some tax.
You can see that you can define back with name and give value to that.
So basically name off your server so you can declare a name to a server.
So let's say Jenkins C8 server so that one can identify the next mission.
What we are using is nothing but Jenkins host.
So let us give some related name and that way we can easily identify our salani.
If you have fortified Linux servers running in your alias, you don't know really what is installed.
So you can have that name to your server, which will exactly relate to what that threat is doing.
OK.
Add the tag next.
Configure Security Group.
So here our goal is to launch Jenkins' on this server, right?
So Jenkins will be started on 884.
So by default, that port is not open.
So you have to clearly tell and a rule and stay open for a liati, then only 11 years will open that
port so that you can install them.
And it can be accessible from any other place.
OK, so you need to add that one security rule here and then you can launch it directly with review
and launch button.
OK, so you can just go with all default settings except that name value bid and adding one new rule
of starting and listening to a report of your own lunch.
And just see what I learned here.
Lunch.
Here you go.
So here it is for the first time, when you create any limits or when when you create any other server,
it will ask you to create one keep it bunfight.
What can we call it as dot B?
OK, this is a file which is used to authenticate.
So for the first time and you do this, you will not have keep it because I already have some sort of
in my account.
I have my keep it so you can actually create a new keepit.
Select this option and give keep your name.
And you said download that, keep it OK after that.
Any time when you want to come back and access the server again, everybody else will ask you to upload.
Keep it.
OK, now you create one and download right next time when you want to access it or when you want to
use that Linux server.
So you have to provide this keypad every time to authenticate you are safe.
Right.
So make sure you provide one proper name and download it and make sure you save it securely in your
system again, to access that server again for the next time.
You'll need this.
Keep it.
So for me, for the second, I already have an existing keeper, which is rather personal.
All right.
So I am selecting that and I acknowledge this and launch instances.
And I said it will take a few seconds, two minutes, maybe in one or two minutes, you can see your
instances is running.
Select this link.
Following instances have been initiated.
So right now, instant state is spending, so it will soon come to running state.
So that means you are ready to use this server, but how to access the server?
Now, it's not easy to log in to the server because that is Nandy way more like Windows.
You will not see all that sort of thing.
Linux is all with command prompt.
OK, just do not assume that you will see another operating system where you have all these folders
and you navigate it just by the minute you will be able to access your new virtual machine only with
the terminal.
There is an option to have the UI as well.
That's a different story.
You need to have Ubuntu server and you need to install some more things but not required for us in general.
People will not use any way to access files, folders in Linux.
Everything will go in terminals with comments only.
OK, story is different.
It's not like Windows.
If you are a Mac user, it will be easy for you to grab this concept very fast because Mac also based
upon Linux distributionally.
So it's easy for you to catch up very speed with a comment waterwheels.
But don't worry, I try to teach all the comments from scratch so that no matter even if you are a Windows
user and never saw Linux before, you will be able to follow this course.
OK, I will try my best to give all those for you so that the patience is what I required from you initially.
You may feel everything is new.
That's obvious.
When you are learning something for the first time, you will feel like rocket science.
But slowly, when we are habituated with that, with much practice, we will feel like Lennix is more
easy than Windows Trustme.
OK, now to access your mission.
So there are different softwares to connect to.
To any Linux missions you have to connect through such glemp.
OK, so you have to make a hit.
Execution is what we call contessa's hit.
So you have to connect to your Atlantics missions to a secure shell.
Glemp All right.
And there are different softwares which we call us.
As I said, Scholem's one of them is Putti.
And there is another famous one, which is called Mobb Extoll.
I would recommend using this because these have lesser steps, then put it to connect and communicate
with the other Linux machines.
All these are associated Glenns.
OK, so you can Google very quick to see what this ASUS heads Klank and that will tell you that today
is one of that line and that will be used to connect to your line explanation's.
So, as I said, I will go with this option.
All right, so download.
And there are two versions, home and professional, we can stick to the home version, you can just
download this I already have in my system.
I guess so.
Home edition and.
Yeah, you can just go with whatever version you have, either portable audience that does not make
any difference.
So ultimately you should be able to install it and open that file in your system.
So it's in deep file and then extracted and you will see an option to open the door to actually file.
And this is how you see double click on the audio file, and that will take you to install this software
in our machines.
So once installed, you will see an app like this, you can just type and will be in your search and
you will see the app and double click on that app.
And after that you will see a screen, something like this.
OK, and these are different how rearms which are already in use.
So once you open this.
Select session, and that will take you to the speech and hear what is what type of session you are
using to connect to your next mission.
You have to do essays, Haertsch connection, OK, you see that secure special session.
You want to start with your excellent mission.
So select this option and then it will give this window remote host.
So here you have to provide IP address of your server.
OK, so we just started one instance right here.
If you come down, you will see an IP address to access your next server.
You can copy this and just paste here carefully without any spaces and specify username.
So this will be default.
Easy to hide.
Hyphen user.
OK, if you write any other user name here like your name of something, it will not work.
So user name by default will be easy to hyphen user for all alias Linux machines ok and select advanced
as hits settings.
Remember I told you that we need to.
Have Bumfights not Billiam extension, so that finally will help you to securely authenticate and will
help you to log into your online expression, so you have to select that and upload that thought Benki,
into your system.
Let's do that.
Yeah, I have my liberal partner just open it so that we weren't giving Darton fine.
So basically we were asking that let me I to get to this IP because this is my Linux server and to authenticate
this is my secret key, which will help you to unlock this mission.
Right.
And then click on OK.
And I think that will create you in your window like this, OK?
These two are existing windows in my mission.
Let me close them.
Right, this is another one, but when you open the first time, you will see something like this.
OK, so let me increase the font size.
OK, awesome, great.
So we have successfully connected to one Linux server throw at has hit glenoid and right now you are
in your Linux over.
As I said, don't expect any folders or any Douai items like Windows.
If you are first time watching this, there, of course, are watching Linux.
So you will be a little surprised to see is this the server?
Yes, this is how it looks and this is how you need to play around all the software downloads, everything
you will be doing to Comensoli.
All right, so in the next lecture, I will quickly go over pricing that how would you be charged this
amount and how you should stop the server at the end once you complete this project.
So that is very important.
Guys, please watch it.
And then we will continue with configurations to accept, as I said from the subsequent lecture.
Thank you.