Welcome back.
So now let's try to remove this and point from here, ideally, this is the common end point, which
should come from your global properties level.
OK, so you will test your API in different environments, right?
So sometimes you're tested in a new environment and then once you're deployed in the environment, then
you will have another endpoint because APIs and that environment will be hosted on another server and
then you will move to Prague.
And if you want to test this APIs in Prague and probably will have another environment.
So basically this will change based upon which environment you run your aviator's.
So this should be globally driven so that, you know, you can change any time the value of it, so
that it will update all your best guesses.
OK, so to do that, I will introduce a new concept called Config Parser in Python.
OK, so basically you can create all your global properties in one file with the DOT I and I extension.
So let me show you that for that.
I will actually create one package and move all the utilities to OK, so that way it would be easy for
us slightly new and we would say on package utilities.
OK, so inside the theater, ladies, I will create new file, and I would call it as properties, these
are basically global properties.
Make sure you give an extension.
All right, so there are some plug ins available, but we don't really care about those because it's
just a simple property values adding.
So first of all, you have to give what kind of properties you are providing.
So give any random name.
In our case we are talking about apples, OK, tomorrow you might have a school related properties.
And after a few sections, I will introduce How to Connect to Linux server.
At the time, you will have other properties.
So here also you will have a post where you are hosting Eurabia in secret.
Also you will have another property called host.
OK, basically you can identify the host of Yapper with its section.
Mmm.
So this is one section.
This is one section.
And this is another section.
So each section is identified with the square brackets like this.
OK, so in our case, let's say we have an endpoint here and point any variable endpoint equals two.
And that endpoint, we have another example.
Right.
So let's copy it from here.
And that's it.
So right now, we don't have any sequel properties.
We will soon iron all these properties in coming later.
So let's remove this, OK?
So if this data and I find out some now come back to your actual post API example, so instead of writing
that code here, I will go back to you.
That's.
But I remember we have creator impeller, right?
Where are we using this?
This is not required, let me delete this, I don't know from where this came from.
Yeah, payloaders are here, so I will create another python file in the same utilities package.
I'm just trying to have multiple files that's on and inside here, I would say.
Configurations.
This one by Dunfee.
All right, so basically, I created one simple Python package, insert this, there is one file with
an extension and another file with configurations.
I will later come into this file and I use the code first.
We will understand directly how to bring that endpoint exactly to here without hard coding, OK?
I will remove it from here.
And there is one package in Python which unit to import import config parser.
So this is the package by default available in Python.
So let's import that first and then this is the package right in this packet.
So D'Arte and then you have a method called config parser like.
Now.
Let's push this into one real conflict, right?
So now this variable.
Is created and this variable can drive all your config, any files, but we don't know where exactly
the EMI files are located.
So we have to say config.
So this is the object responsible to do that?
Right.
Because from this method, you created an object and this object d'art and you have a file called Read
and you have to give the part of that file where exactly what properties file is present.
So it's present here.
So right.
Click copy related part and you can just sit here and this way you want a config file can be read by
this object.
So it has no knowledge about all the values present in this property.
Start and file.
OK, so to do that first you have to import this config pastor packet and from this package you need
to call this method.
And once you create object out of it from that, you need to call this rate method which will read the
properties file.
OK, so one set right now, you can directly write and call that end point like this.
So this is the object, right?
Object first, which section you want to access.
I told you there can be multiple sections here, right.
So right now we have only one section called API.
So config open.
How one square bracket AIPA.
And then if you give the step that will directly access the section and insert the section, you need
to access end point, right?
So can't Faye AIPA, Colin.
For Sonny.
And that's it.
So let's separate this value from your actual string with plus.
Perfect, you see that, so this is the man, 30, who have written config of AIPA of End Point.
When you say config of Apria, it will first see what file I have to go as you have already given this
property does.
And it will go inside and it will search for apperception.
Yes, it found it and then it will immediately look for endpoint.
That's what you provided here.
So this is the end point so that it will directly access this value from here and it would place in
this area earlier.
It has to be history.
DP to sixteen point.
Right.
So that will be replaced with this.
So a trying time, whatever value you provide here that will fall here and then after it will be concatenated
with your stuff.
String with Pless operator.
OK, you can separate a variable and string that plus operator.
Right.
So that's how we handle it.
And now you run the test.
It should be same and behave like whatever we have done previously, ok.
You see that everything the same book is added book is successfully deleted.
So that means we have successfully created a global properties and we are driving it from there.
Now, let's see if I change that.
Any value to 40.
Obviously, at this point, we don't have our API.
So if I tried to run this again, this will throw another.
Still running.
So you can guess that there is something wrong, right?
You'll see that it clearly told you that we are trying to reach, but there is no you are still exist.
And that server perfect.
Now, you understood how to drive the values globally, but why should I write all these code in my
actual test?
Is this not overhead?
So let me remove it here.
And then we will go to another file, which we just created configurations, so here we will try to
have that matter and just call that method directly there so that we can avoid some code.
Isn't it here?
I can write a letter, get config about Mahtani.
And then return this config variable.
Right, so you need to import.
Config Pozza.
OK, you need to get one more blank line.
And that will go away, reformatories file.
Everything looks good, so you can import this package into your.
Actually test.
From.
Configurations.
While imports stopped, but configurations package is present and utilities like.
From utilities.
OK, so this conflict right now, it's showing another because you don't have that, so you can now
create conflict equals to get conflict.
OK, gone.
All you can directly call this get configurator here to air this stuff, Basswood Patrick.
You see that now it was more simple than get config of API endpoint and then it will give the results.
OK, so let me run one more time and make sure nothing is breaking after we have done this optimization.
Awesome, so looking at it and successfully deleted, great.
So next thing is the resources.
So you have given advocate resources here and the resources here in real time, you will have a number
of apps and a number of resources for that.
So you should drive all those again from externally, from any class.
So in the next lecture, let's create one class and declare all these resources there and we will call
it from that class to our actual test.
So these are all required to make your test more optimized in framework.
Standard config parser classes and payloads should come from external file then only the court looks
a standard way.
OK, if you just have standalone court tomorrow, if you want to do any more, you will see.
And if you want to show to your project team, if you have a standalone code like this, then that won't
be good.
So if you make all these optimizations and show how all these are derived from external sources, then
that would be very impressive.
All right.
We'll see that in our next lecture.
Thank you.