Welcome, guys.
So in this lecture, we will first see how to install my second in our system because we will be using
MySQL database to interact with the data present in database tables from our Python code.
So to solve this assignment and project, we need MySQL database in our local system.
OK, so in this lecture I will quickly show how to install it in your system so that from next lecture
we can start our proceedings to implement this project.
Right.
And just click down Glaube.
My sequel In Stonham.
Just Google search with my sequel installer, and then you will have their official link where you can
go and download here.
OK, so this is not MSA extension, which you can download anything worth, I guess, but this have
324 million downloads, so probably this could be the stable one.
OK, so once you download, you will have in your machine the dart extension.
You need to run that and then it will ask some questions.
Just click on next, next, next.
That will complete the installation of my sequel in your mission.
I have a screenshots.
OK, so it might ask you to.
Select what type of account you need.
You can just go with a default account, what it's already selected.
OK, because we need all the software developer default one.
And it will check if all the installations, what needed to download this are present in your system.
If not, it will try to solve all that for you.
OK, and then after finally before that, there are some instructions.
It will then it will take whether Python is present or not, it will install it.
Just follow the instructions and click on next.
Thereafter, you will release configuration page where you will be asked to set a password, then set
any password.
And please remember it because you're going to use that in do our best to connect to our database through
Java code.
So desperate as the route so that you can remember.
OK, that's OK.
So and then after just click on your next and then you will see this, my sequel will be installed in
your mission after installation.
You can find it in program files.
Let me show you that.
S..
Program funds.
And then here you will find my sequel's.
Yeah, this one, but make sure that if you have any existing sequel instances, uninstall all of them
before you install this, my sequel.
OK.
So if there are any existing sequels in your mission and then if you try to install my sequel on top
of it, you may see that workbench folder missing in my sequel folder.
That happens if there is already some server running in your mission.
Okay, go to program files and uninstall our control panel.
You'll have an option where you can uninstall the programs from there and install all existing and then
try to install a freshly so that we will have this workbench.
If you already have my zip code in your mission with this setup, then you can skip this installation.
You can click onto this workbench further and start this or my sequel file so that it gets open.
Basically, this is an editor where you will write sequel queries either to insert the records in database
or retrieve them or to perform any sequel operations.
You have a neat editor inform of the workbench.
OK, so when you connect for the first time, it might ask you that credentials, your username is root
and password is whatever you give there, if you give them password, also will be rude and see that
this sequel is started.
Sarut started on three three zero six support in your mission.
OK, if there is any other project started, just not on the sport, no one will be using that later,
OK.
So simply select this and that will ask you the password.
Give the password and that's it.
Just click on OK, and then you will be taken to the workbench.
Ed Perfect.