Welcome back.
So in this section, let us create a framework for all the APA automation test, what we have written
and wrap over this desk on top of this reality framework.
It's very easy.
OK, so the next 90 minutes I will go over all these steps and will help you to create your own BGT
framework from scratch using Python.
All right.
So let's get started.
So what tools does.
Python support for BGT frame, but first you need to understand this, so let's go to the official website
of Cucumber.
So Cucumber is officially supportability automation tool.
OK, so cucumber, not evil.
I hope most of you know that cucumber is commonly used whenever there is a scope of BGT for legal framework.
OK, so let's go to the dogs.
And installation.
Right.
So we are now in Paten Automation, so we have to get dependencies, are dots related to python cucumber,
right?
So scroll down.
These are the third party plugins available for their respective programming language.
So for Java, you can use to combat and for JavaScript, you can convert deice.
So like this for Python.
So there is a third party tool called behav.
So that tool is giving you the support of BGT automation in Python language.
OK, so you see that it's not official product after combat, but Cucumber's supports this behav tool
for Python.
OK, you cannot directly use cucumber for Python, so we don't have dependencies.
Are jobs available to directly work Python Lutsenko combat.
So Cucumber extends its support with the help of behere.
So let's go to the official website.
So when you select this, this will take you to the official website.
Before you see that, please see the Behere website if you want to active in your framework and get
there again to explain what exactly is BGT.
OK, so you can see the definition here.
Behave is a behavior driven development.
Stabilities stands for Behavioral Drayman so you can try your best guess in terms of a normal plain
English and you can connect all your English language to the actual code.
OK, I will show you some examples of that.
You will understand what exactly it is and how that will help.
So in agile mobility is commonly used because if you describe your requirements in plain English, so
when I say plain English, you have to follow some standards to describe that so that anyone can understand
if you put that in that specific standard, so that there will not be any confusion in the way you describe
your requirements.
So that is why people choose this behavior driven development practice.
OK, so I can show you a quick example.
How does it look like so here there is something called feature test setup.
Let's go here.
And there are some examples given here.
Right.
So this is how you have to define given some condition, like in our case, if you take the example
of the project, what we have done.
So given we have all the details of headers, you all to add the book.
OK, so we have basically book details with us, so we have to send those details in the form of a bit
of ad book so that, you know, details will be submitted to the back end and you get a response back.
So you have to describe that like this.
Given how all the details when I execute an eBay method, then book is successfully added to the database.
OK, that is what our actual requirement here is.
Right.
So we have the data.
We had the advocate and we got the message.
That book is successfully added.
OK, so same thing we were describe in this standard in the given when then.
So this language is called Gerkin language.
OK, so people, some people call it Gurkin Zipkin.
It's up to you.
How do you pronounce that.
It varies based upon which country you live.
So this kind of standards are frightening given Wenden format.
We call it Gerkin language.
So basically this is like what you have, what you are going to do and what you are expecting you should
give in this fashion so that we call as a gerkin language.
And we also describe this as a feature in general.
When you have a test, I guess you would call it as a test case are sculpturing in which it is standard.
If you like something like this, we call it.
Does it feature.
OK, so one feature file can have multiple scenarios, so this is one test case and you can have another
condition, like another test, like given I have details when the action is taken, then verifying
that book is successfully deleted.
So describe what a test in this way and then write the actual cord and plug in that code to these lines.
Also, how to do that as well.
OK, so this feature file.
So basically a collection of scenarios is called one feature file.
So just like how you say a test is how a collection of tests, a feature file collection of scenarios,
and here you can write and will the book, but make sure you have to write in the standards of given
vendor.
OK, we will do a practical example and then you will understand how I am going to describe this in
Gurkin language.
Right.
So let's get started with that.
So in this section we will define we will pick up one of two scenarios of automation test, what we
have written for the EPA and we will describe them in this feature file standards and then connect this
to actual code and implement one BGT framework.
This will be very, very easy and you will get all the features, a framework.
So in general, what all one can expect in a framework design, everything can be achieved with the
help of this behav, with the plain simple English language.
So let's see how to achieve that.
So in the next lecture, let's get started with installation and take it from there.
OK, so we have decided that we are going to use the became a tool to create our behavior driven development
rest API automation framework for Python language.
Let us continue here.
Thank you.