Welcome, guys.
So in this section, we will see what is Web scrapping and how to achieve that in Python using one of
the famous packets called Beautiful Soap.
OK, so beautiful is not adjective here.
It is the package name.
We call it a beautiful soap, which is available in Python.
Right.
So first, what is Web scrapping?
Let's try to understand some basics behind it.
So it's all about extracting the data, all you can say content from any webpage.
OK, so in general, people use Web automation frameworks like selenium when they want to get the data
from the pages.
But there is a concept called web scrapping where you can do it without relying on any front end automation
frameworks.
OK, so basically the scrapping is used in researchers like if you want to get some on topic from the
Internet, so you have to resource that from the various websites.
Right.
So you can use the web scrapping concept to scan the data content from different Web applications and
get your data based upon your filters, what you apply.
Right.
So this is highly used in data science to extract the data based upon the logic, what you ask to get.
And using that data, we analyze and prepare metrics like prepare pie charts, diagrams based upon what
we analyzed the data from VEP.
OK, so you know, one of the common principles, what we have in data science projects, it's like
find the data and play with it.
So basically, when you want to analyze the data, like it could be like how frequently user is researching
something on the web or there is so much of data analyzing it.
So to analyze data first, we want to extracted from any Web application now, for example.
So let me take you to the third IMDB.
You know, this is a famous website where you can find ratings reviews of many movies internationally.
Right.
So now here you want to get all the movies list, which are part of Thriller.
So I would select TV episodes and get me all the movies with the word cult.
So all the pythons with me will be retrieved here.
So your goal is to get all the movie titles in your output.
OK, you can scrap this page and get all the titles of movies into your output.
Once you get the data, you can do some research and you can get some analytics.
So that's where, you know, the scrapping comes into picture.
So this subscribing help you to get data based upon your input so you can ask anything here and you
are scrapping, can pull the content from your webpage based upon what you provide and then you can
further use it for your research purposes.
So that is what one key principle, what we use in data science, is finding the data and playing with
it for any research.
Finding data can be done with Python scrapping, which is one of the most common technique we use.
And for that we use a utility called Beautiful Soap, which we going to discuss in this section.
Right.
And here we will not use any Front-End testing frameworks to do that.
That can be achieved on later note with the help of beautiful soap.
So let's get started and see.
And that way you can understand more about scrapping when we do some practical examples.
So, as I said, you can do a number of filters here.
So our ultimate goal from the section is that, you know, you have to go to each and every movie here.
So there are a lot of movies present on the.
So your goal is to scan each and every movie from this page and go to that specific movie and see what
is the gender of that comedy documentary or news or whatever.
So every movie have one gender, right?
So you should figure out what it is now, for example, if you see another link here, it is comedy
gener.
And here it is, crime fantasy, horror thriller.
OK, so like that, you have to get all the genders of each and every title displayed in this speech.
And the next lecture I will show you how to do that.
Using but scrapping with the help of beautiful soap.
Thank you.