Welcome back.
So in this lecture, I will show you how to generate nice history alone reports for durability test
results.
OK, that's very simple.
Guys, you have to install one plugin which can be commonly used for both generating a report and you
want to be here.
OK, so that plug in them is a lone hyphen here.
So let's install that first.
So this plug in are we can call it as a python package, which will help you to connect to your behavior
results and prepare alone reports.
OK, so a little hyphen here, hear this is the package name you need to install it you can install
globally and make sure you are pointing to that interpreter in your face.
I already have in my mission.
That's why I got a message that requirement already said is right.
Great.
So once you install the.
Next step is that you'll have to generate reports, right?
So what you can do while running your debts, you need to add another parameter.
So Behave will trigger all the features in your feature for the right.
And you are using your captor to get the locks.
And next thing what you can do here, you can go hyphen F and provide annual reports.
So this is the command.
Let me show you how different Éluard.
Underscore behave so if you want, in that format, so you can save formatter a little for.
Right, and you can give the folder where you want to store your results, you can use hyphen or subfolder
name and let's create a folder in this project level only.
Let's call this as a live report.
So this is the folder will get created.
OK, Ivan, all stand for giving the folder name.
And this is the flag you have to provide alone.
Behave, darte Ford Motor Co. formatter.
Right.
So when you run this, you are all fetus will run again once Deskins execution is done, then this will
be here format and reports will get to innovate and they will get stored in this directory.
So this directory will now get created in your project level.
OK, let's see you then enter.
And.
It started execution again.
Good.
So if you see your project, you should see the folder now called Allen Reports.
So once you open that report, you will not directly see Hestia Mitchell report.
All the reports will first be shown in days files.
Now, you have to convert this Jason files to actual history and will report so far that you have to
download another package.
Kalala.
So let me show you.
So search for a lower download and you can go to the releases available and pick up the latest release.
OK, so this is the latest release and you can go ahead and download the file and that will.
Yeah, this is how you can.
Select official Allura website.
So from here, you can download a lower command line somewhere you needed this to generate Hesterman
reports from the Jason files, what you just created.
OK, so scroll down and you have different command line options.
If you are on Macarius, you can install like this for Windows.
They are asking us to use Schoop command line, but instead let's make it simple.
We can download AGIP extension file so you can go to this Bindaree in manual installation.
Let's get the latest version available.
So let's go back to the GitHub alert framework.
So that will take to the good HelpAge.
Yeah.
So from here I think we can get the latest version.
We can just directly do it from Schoop installer.
But for that first you have to download the scope command line installer and then give this.
So let's not download any number of tools just to have a load in our mission.
So what I can help you here, you see, then grab it from binary.
So when you go to Bentley, you will get the latest.
You are also from here, you get the latest version, which is released recently.
So select this link to that 13 dot fight.
By the time you watching, it could be any other version.
Right?
Scroll down and get it in the file.
You can just directly download this.
So I just download it and you unzip this and once you unzip, it looks something like this.
OK, so here is a Benfold.
Go inside this.
You can add this part to your system variables or you can directly generate that Hesterman report by
navigating to the spot.
OK, so let me show you.
So let us directly go to that part from your command prompt through this.
Perfect.
So from here you can give that command.
So the command what you have to give here is a little subtle and that result folder.
OK, so I is a keyword is that goal.
So basically this will solve all of converting.
You want to do some files, what you just got created into his HTML report.
OK, so that's the concept.
So why I am giving this a load from here.
Because if you give it from outside then it will complain, saying that A is not recognized as internal
or external command.
So to avoid this, if you want to give it from any of it, make sure to add this part in your system
variables.
OK, so if you don't want to add then you have to come to that Benfold or what you just downloaded.
So you need to come to this fold and copy the part, go to your terminal and from here give a load.
So and you're project directory.
OK.
So here is where your project is present.
Copy, copy.
But you need absolute path.
So here with my directory is present, you don't enter and this will start a new server where you generate
a report for you, Lexi.
We see that report successfully returned and it will open up your browser and it will show that reports
like this supercool, right?
So you have four test cases, everything pass and you have a sweet Siete session management check,
plus indexation management.
You have excluding given Wenden everything.
It is perfectly showing like how much time it took and verify and book Apaid functionality.
This Rantoul two times with two different datasets, one by one 1.0.
Right.
So everything is really displayed here and it will show how many parts, how many felt, if anything
fail, the red number will be upgraded to one and it will show the failed disk is so like this, you
can manage entire history and will report.
You can share this start.
Hestia will report which shared if you want to know, the part here is the part you can go to this part
where you will find the report.
OK, so these are the four steps you have to follow.
But it's easy, right?
So a little reporting comes into very handy because you are not putting anything in court to create
reports.
OK, so you have done four simple steps.
Step one alone hyphen behav.
So you are installing this package because when you install this package, this will help you to create
adjacent files like this, which I can understand to convert, to do Hesterman report.
So that's why you installed this package first and then you give this command became a hyphen is a flag,
and you have to say that generate in a lot formatter and give you the result folder where you want to
generate reports and features.
So if you have any features, if you don't give anything, it will blindly run all flutists present
in your project.
So once those dissin files are created, then you download this command line server and from that directory
you have a son and give the results for apart part, just like we have given here, and it will give
you the browser open.
And this is how it looks like.
Awesome, right?
So that's how you can prepare a report without rewriting or without writing any new code in your framework.
So that concludes discussion about pretty desperate.
But I hope we really enjoyed this.
And as I told you guys, so we have done only 40 to 50 percent framework optimization in this section.
And last all we did already in the previous sections by showing these configurations, properties,
resources, because if you look at any code, let's say book details.
So all these configurations we did not do in this section.
This is like core optimization, which is independent of your framework design.
So all the core optimizations like endpoints are coming from configuration files and resources is coming
from there and payloads are also dynamically generating.
I have also shown how to generate paillard from databases.
Everything is properly organized.
If you see the structures like here features utilities.
So we have a nice folder's which will help you to design and build a framework where you can now extend
this and create your own aviator's cases.
But this is how you can get started.
So I hope this section will help you to understand how the frameworks work in real time.
So with this we can this section.
We have covered all the important topics, what we generally expect when you dissent within a framework,
so that's the rub.
So in the next section, we will begin phase two of learning, which is independent of this ABA testing
and really ready for.
But let's put all this aside with a fresh mind set.
I will introduce how to relax we face because that helps you to do battle automation and battered by
Dobsonville with some visiting in Linux servers.
So using Python, you will connect to those servers remotely and execute its commands.
Roundabout's commands that a lot of fun stuff you have in the coming sections.
But we are wrapping up phase one discussion here and starting fresh with phase two discussion from our
next section.
All right.
Thank you.