All right, so we have printed two lists, and now if you carefully observe in this list, they don't
index first index.
So there is a mapping, first index of them is a second index of some is rejected.
So there is a mapping here, right.
So that's how these are there.
Now, let's write one logic that we will first find out which index is present in this names list,
OK?
And on that index, let's go to stats and see if it is approved or rejected because there is one to
one mapping.
So if you see the two list and compare with your CSP name status, one, two, one mapping is there
for two.
List them abroad, some rejected.
Right.
So the name and the status will come in the same index for that particular group.
OK, so don't.
So now to understand if some case is rejected or not, first we will try to see in which your next exam
is present in this names list.
OK, how do you do that?
So if you want to know the index of any item in your list, there is a method called list, which is
names here, DOT Index.
OK, so it will give the index of your element name.
So here you want to know the index of the same.
Right, and you can store it in one variable.
Right.
So this will give you the zero one two second right and address one to one mapping.
If you can grab the second index of stats, that will be nothing but status of this loan.
So zero one two, that means the same thing, right?
Sam is right.
So we are smartly capturing that into two different lists and then using the index.
We are trying to figure out that now.
So once you understood that.
I'm coming on one index now on this list, stats, stats just give that index number because this holds
about status, loan status of the same loan status to.
Brent.
Sam Malone status is.
Give this very long status.
OK, so let's give capital letters.
Just to follow coding standards, OK, now if you run this, then it will give you a perfectly Sam Malone
status is rejected, right?
Similarly, if you want to know the status and just give that down here.
Let's keep in genetic.
Launch status is rejected for as well.
You see that Joe is rejected.
So like this, you can build a logic and you can read CSFI file and then extract the values so you can
play around like this with The Cafferty File getting into last night right into it and push them into
one more list with the index.
OK, it's up to your imagination again.
How do you want to play?
But this is how you can read the values in CSFI.
OK, in the next lecture I will show how to write the values to CSC.
All right.
Thank you.