Welcome this.
So now let's get started with our first project of automating the manual apparatus cases using Python
libraries.
OK, so we will get started with this project one.
But before you start with API automation, you first of all have to understand how to pass a requests
are decent responses.
OK, so in the next two, three lectures, I will show what are different Python packages or modules
available to pass you over to Jason files and then extract the values out of it.
So no matter how complex you are dishonest, you can still be able to pass it with very simple techniques
using Python models.
So once a good enough knowledge on this isn't passing, then I can directly jump in to show how API
automation works.
All right.
But before that, make sure you have enough knowledge on list tables and big data types.
These three data types we will use heavily in this first project.
So be aware of having that knowledge and let's get started.
So in this lecture, let's start understanding passing Jason files so far that I would create one new
Python file and let's call it as Jason passing.
OK, now, by default, there is one package available in Python to pass all over this incanting.
So that package name is nothing but a.
So first you need to import that package into your Python file so that you can perform the operations
using this as an object.
OK, now, for example, I have this dissin file with me.
Right.
So if you see this, doesn't it have to kiss your name and language?
And in Python terminology here, language just is a list because it have a square bracket, isn't it?
So key value is languages, but the value of these languages is a list.
OK, so that's how this Jason is done.
That's fine.
So our overall goal is to pass this Gissen and extract value out of it.
So first, let's try to understand how to get the first language.
Present this, Jason.
OK, so I will take this complaint, Jason, and there is a method in Python which will help you to
pass the decent string and it will convert it into a dictionary.
So before that, first I would declare one variable and inside this variable, I will paste my Jason's
string.
OK, so if you do the string you should have pursued in courts and inside this, the courts, you can
give you a decent canting.
OK, so let's write all this in one single line for now, because it's a simple one, right?
So I would.
Right back.
OK, awesome.
So this is your Jason and you have stored your and as a string variable.
OK, so this causes string variable is holding UBA days and counting.
Now, to parse this, there is a method available in Python cartloads which will help you to pass Jason's
string and it returns dictionary.
OK, so the whole Jayson's doing whatever you saw now will be returned as one big snotty object.
OK, so once you get that into a dictionary object, it's easy for us to access the content in the dictionary.
Right.
Which we have already seen in our previous sections.
So that's why I keep on stressing that couples list and dictionary.
These three are more important data types.
You need to understand how to retrieve the content from it because in real time, all formats we have,
ultimately we will convert all these farmers into dictionaries on the list and try to access them from
those lists.
It's very simple.
So using the distant object, which you just imported, Jason Dark, that is the method cartloads.
OK, so use this method and insert this method.
You need to pass this string, which is having a decent content.
Right.
So when you run this method now, it will extract the decent string content and it will convert that
into a dictionary.
OK, so let me throw this into one variable.
Right.
So right now I have this entire content in dictionary database.
So how would you confirm if it's written in dictionary are not you know, that there is one method in
Python, which is correct type, which will tell you what kind of data about the variable you pass inside
of this.
OK, so let me put this.
All right, so I can run this python file with the shark out of control shift and the.
Awesome.
You see that glass dictionary, so it clearly tells us that whatever we have is a dictionary now.
OK, nice.
So if you print again the complete variable, this time it will again return the same content, whatever
you have in your Gissen.
But this time this is a dictionary.
Now, when you have it as a dictionary, you know how to access items in dictionary, right?
So in dictionary, let's say this is the one name is the key value is the.
Our value of the name, right, similarly, there is another key totally in this study, there are to
kiss me and language and the value of these languages is not strength.
So what is the value of this name?
It's a just a string called Rovell.
Should be, but the value of these languages is a list.
You see that square brackets.
OK.
Now using this, if our goal is to extract the name present in the gissen, as you have got that in
two dictionaries, you can simply say the dictionary of the name and that's it.
So this will put into the content because it's so simple, right.
You see that so you have successfully access to your first variable from the descent to do that, you
have smartly converted this entire system into a dictionary format using this slots matter.
And then you are simply accessing the values present in this, Jason.
Now, let me give you one trigger scenario.
So my goal here is to get me the first language taught by an object.
So in our case, it's a Java.
So how would you pull this, let's say?
Again, let us stick to our basics, first of all, to access any content, you have to call it with
the key, right?
So if I call with languages.
OK, so if I print this, what happens?
It will simply print the value present in this key because you are calling the key and this is how the
value will be printed.
OK, now let's see.
Right, so it printed me up.
So by seeing this output, I understood that this is a list, right?
So this is nothing but the whatever you have extracted with this score written that list.
So I will carefully copy this into another variable now, because the output of this is a list, right.
List of languages, something like this.
OK, now what is this return to this return by now should be obviously lost because of square brackets.
Let's let's check again, babe.
I'm telling you from Root so that, you know, you can understand once you get familiar, you can basically
everything in one step.
So to understand how to pass this step by step, I'm showing you all this process and let's run.
You see that written list?
It's obvious because when you access this dictionary, the value of this dictionary is nothing but list.
OK, fine, regardless.
But what is our ultimate goal?
So we understood that it returns the list, but now we need to print first item in that list because
that's what our overall goal is.
Right.
Get me the first language.
Start by the trainer.
So if this is the list, if you want to access the first item and again, it's simple language.
How do you access the first zero when you call zero, then first item will be retrieved?
So this is how you can actually retrieve the Java.
OK, so now when you're under, your output will be Jawa, perfect, you see that?
How did we approach the logic?
First we converted into a big study and then when we call the key the study of this key, the value,
whatever it into the list.
And again, we pass through to this list and brought up the zeroth index.
And this is how you need to pass over Jason using locksmithing.
So that is one approach that a number of ways to pass this, which will be seeing in our next lecture.
Thank you.