OK, so let's get started with installation of the hip, so I will point you to the official website
so that tomorrow, if something changed, you can just follow how I am doing and repeat the same process
to get the latest changes.
OK, so once you have installed here, we did not install yet.
So let's click on this and see what's going on.
OK, so here they have clearly given instructions of how to download behave so you can take this comment
install.
Get history dubious so you can go ahead and install it.
I already have in my mission, so I don't install this.
So when you click and enter, you will get installed in your system.
So behave.
OK, that is a step one.
So once you install it, the next step is to have an ED to continue your framework, and you might wonder,
like, why would I need a ED?
Because I already have this fight on.
But one problem with Paten is that it do not support really framework.
OK, you don't support FITA fights.
When I say fights and don't support, that means fight some community work and don't support.
There are two versions of it available in their website.
One is community version, which is a free to download and another is a professional version.
OK, so these guys have the ability, framework, support only for better uses for professional edition.
But don't worry, it's touchiness free trial is that we can still downloading this course and we can
do practice.
But after that ludus, it might ask you to provide latency.
OK, so the free version is not having support to create future files because future files is what we
are going to create.
I just explained in the previous lecture.
Right.
So every test we describe in terms of Gurkin language by creating a feature file like this and when
you create a feature file, that extension, that of that file is DARD Fetim.
So till now, when we create any file here, the extension here is dart player.
Right?
So that feature extension files are not supported in that community version of Biton.
So that's why I downloaded a professional version.
So you can see about Paten professional is there.
So you can also get it.
I can picture.
How does that happen.
So I download.
So we have to do this free version so you can still practice it and thereafter, if you are working
in any company, obviously they will provide if they have really a framework developed.
So, yeah, you can see that free trial.
You can go ahead and download this for 30 days.
I think you can still extend also after 30 days for every 10 days, it will ask to extend.
So you can still continue in practice because I have this for more than a month and I'm still using
it happening somewhere it stuff.
But meanwhile, let's complete this.
OK, so once you download and then you can open your project, you have already this project created.
Right.
So fine, you can stay open and then you can choose that project which you already created and open
in your by some professional edition.
So once you open that, Ed, you are done with having a nice editor with you because only this election
is going to support plugins.
All right, guys, you have the hip installed with the installation of the camera on you and you have
additions as well.
Now, let's get started with our actual call.
So for this, I will create one folder under this package.
Right.
So right, like new I would directory and directory, let's call it as a fetus.
So that way I am creating project is very important because we expect you to follow some conventions.
So it checks for all the future files only in the fetus directory.
So you have to create a directory like this.
So make sure you create one.
And under this fetus, let's create a new feature file new and scroll down and you will see Gurkin feature
five.
As I told you, this option will not be available if you try to use quite some community edition.
OK.
And let's say does.
Book AIPA is a feature film.
Right.
You see that pretty far in our data is already there here.
So this is the syntax feature.
It's like you are best Sweetenham.
You can treat it as a test case because one feature will have multiple test cases.
So better.
Let's have let's treat future as one test to sleep, OK?
At best, a suite which actually verifies and validates the book at a library.
OK, so you can say verify your books.
Are anger and deleted
using library.
So this is our filter.
Mmm, something like this, a description now scenario is what you are actually a test case.
So let's say we have one test available here.
Right.
Let's dig this ad payload.
So here I'm not using beebee interaction.
I'm using the interaction which we have created with this.
OK, so let's assume that we need to provide data from our file, not from the database.
OK, so we can drive this data from cucumber filter files instead of driving it from the files like
this.
I'll show you.
So I will pick this.
And what does this test against us?
So this will add a book and then it will immediately delete again and it is validating if book is successfully
deleted.
Right.
So this is what this test against us are and delete it immediately.
So this way we are relating to add and delete.
So let's start with an ebook here.
So I will describe a scenario like this.
But if I add Apria functionality, so this is my desk is.
So enter steps here and you can start by giving in given when then standard, I show you right.
How given Wendon standards.
Well, OK, so you have downloaded behav with install.
So make sure the compiler what you are community and professional edition have matches with that because
you downloaded it globally.
OK, so pippins done is done globally.
So that means you have to make sure the Python compiler, which is used globally, is also pointing
to this.
Ed.
OK, let's confirm that.
So fine settings and you can come to
Project Python interpreter and make sure you select the compiler, which it's globally there, because
there is the one you have installed usability.
Right?
So this is the one guy's user owner data programs Python.
This is a global python interpreter.
So when you download it from command prompt here where it will get installed.
So select this because this package have the information about him.
OK, so after you select, make sure that packet is displayed here.
This is the one behave is displaying.
It's all set up.
OK, right.
And he didn't enter from the scenario and you can start giving given so given what do we have?
We have the details right.
Given the details which needs to be added to the library.
OK, so we have the book details with us.
So what we need to do is then.
We execute that and ad book to Mr..
When we execute, I post ABC Post API method.
Then what happens when we do that?
Then it should be caps, then book is successfully added.
So this is what our scenario.
That's OK.
Success.
Perfect.
Now, this is really the standard scenario.
OK, here, when you read it tells the behavior of your test case, like given what you have, then
what do you perform and then what is the output you get?
OK, now for this, we have to plug in with our actual code.
So this is the worst scenario, which we return in future file.
And we we know that we're exactly what actual code is there.
And here in our actual code is present.
Now, in the next lecture, I will show how to plug in this code with each and every step here.
And from the integration between the code and your are Frankton interface of scenarios.
All right.
See in the next lecture.
Thank you.