Welcome, guys.
So in this lecture, I will show you how to set up Python and write a letter to write your Python script.
OK, so let's first get started to install this Python software in our system.
Right.
So you can go to their official website by OAG to download the latest version available.
So let's quickly go to there and say by the download, and that will give you the prompt to the official
website.
Yeah, so from here, you can download it if if you are logged in using MacMillian, then you will see
something like download the version for Mac.
OK, so this website is intelligent to detect your operating system and provide your dart the file based
upon that.
All right.
So one click will help you to download this dart file into your system.
And once you have this Darbee XP value, you just need to open it and do some next, next next clicks
so that, you know, Python will get installed in your system.
See?
So this is the first window and gets open when you start the.
And this is the most important you have to remember.
So here we're Python is getting installed, user, owner and data local programs.
And here.
OK, so you can see from the annotation here for Mac users where the part will be.
So this is the part by default, it will get downloaded from Windows.
You can submit this and click on next so that, you know, this version will get installed in your system.
I already have this, so that's why I don't proceed it.
I just click on cancer.
So simple clicks will help you to set up Python in your system.
So once Python is installed, let's go to that path and see if it is successfully installed.
So I'm a user, owner, operator, local.
So in your case, owner will be replaced by your computer.
OK, so programs and Python.
So I have different versions here.
So it depends upon what version you download.
That was a no.
You will see here.
And this is the python home.
But OK, so here where it got installed, now you'll have to set this part in your system variables,
right.
So let's do that so you can copy this entire pod, because if you set in your system variables, then
from anywhere you can run your python test so that your system will recognize that Python software.
So in Mac, you need not set any part variable because by default, the user local bin will be in your
part directory.
So in Windows you have to do it so you can go to edit system, environment, variables, environment
variables, go to the part variable and edit this.
OK, so here, let's add the part from Python.
So I knew and then just add the part and this is the form part of your python directory.
Similarly, you need to add one more part.
So come back to your python.
Home they.
And here you see another folder called scripts, right?
So you need this part as well.
I will just tell you, why do you need this?
Because you will really work on this PIP installer.
So for that reason, you have to add this part as well.
So make sure you add this.
I will now explain what is.
Now, let's go to the our documentation.
So we have seen how to install Python and we have successfully set Python in our missions and we know
where exactly Python will be located.
So we have said that in our system variables.
So first, let's see if Python is installed.
So go to the command prompt and then go Python hyphen hyphenation.
You will see the version, what you just installed.
So that conforms.
You are system variables are correctly updated with Python home right now.
What is it?
I just told that we need to give the part of scripts for that as well because we have picked out Bekesi,
which needs to be detected by our windows.
So what is Pip?
So Pip is a standard package manager.
So if you want to download any Python package now, for example, in this course you will download a
package called Requests.
This will help us to do API automation.
OK.
And when we are developing a testing framework, I will download a load behaviour package.
OK, this will help us to give me a load reports for my apparatus us.
Right.
So these are the packages of what Python support to get that into your system you will use and get them
using come in so you can simply say pip install and then you can give that package name so that automatically
it gets this package into your system.
And one great thing about Python is once you download this package, as you think, Pip, what do you
get this software and inject that into your python environment?
OK, so you have your Python software sitting in this location, right?
So automatically when you download any package using PIP, this package will be injected into this environment.
So you need not separately again, import them when you are working with any testing projects.
OK, so if you take DAFWA as an example in Java, you download Java separately and then if you want
to work with any selenium dots are WIPA dots, you download them and import into your project.
OK, and then you project supports the code related to those afterwards.
Right.
Two different things in starting Java is different.
And in your project you have to import the dots, which you download it.
If it isn't Java now, you have to import this tool in your project when you are working and editor.
But in Python you need not do that.
So when you download Python and when you download these software using Bip, bip automatically injects
all this software into your python so that you can directly start working in your project without using
any input because you are Project No is Python.
And despite having knowledge of all these packages.
Troopship OK, so you need not worry about importing the packages or getting the dependencies once.
If you look between stuff that is enough.
OK, so that's the cool thing, what you have in Python, right.
So when you use Pip, so now, for example, here, when you use PIP, install this, PIP belongs to
this python environment, right?
So this bit will inject that software into this Python package.
Right now, I have two different Python softwares in my system.
I deliberately downloaded it for explanation.
So if you do pip install.
So if that pet is pointing to this project, then it will inject into the software, but not into the
software.
OK, so if you were a project users, the Python, a first folder, then that will not have any knowledge
of the packages you downloaded because that installation is done here.
So make sure the PIP installation, what you are doing and the python environment, what you are using
should be simple.
Make sure they are in sync so that you need not worry about importing anything.
Right.
So let's do one thing, guys.
So in our upcoming lectures, I will again show you what is the cost package and from where will we
get that when I am talking about AIBA automation, but for now, just for a demonstration of what is
and how to download software.
So I will now download a package called Request.
Basically, this will help us to do API automation.
Right.
So I already have in my mission.
So that's why I got this message.
That equipment already satisfied.
But from your site you will see some logs and it will get installed.
Right.
So once it is getting installed carefully observe in which Python software it is installed, Python
37 that so it is automatically injected.
OK, great, because this is what we have given in our system variables.
But when you say Pip, it is pointing to your system variable given part ASM.
So we have successfully downloaded one package and now you understood what is PIP and how to download
softwares.
So you might be wondered at this time, like how would I know that this is the packet?
So that information again, we will go deep dive.
When we talk about API automation, I'm just giving you a brief idea now that we will get back to that
again.
OK, so this is a syntax which I just showed you, pip install in the package name, if you want to
know if it is successfully installed in your system, then you can show request.
So this will tell you if the package is present or not.
Yes.
Package is that and it clearly tell you the location and everything else on base.
So that's how we'll install packages.
And the next important thing is to download Ed.
So where do we write our Python code?
We need one editor to write all our automation related code.
Right.
So Python will be our prime choice to do that.
So let's download this editor, Arsalan.
Buy some download.
And if you go to their official website, Gelperin Starcom, so you have two different versions of by
chance.
One is community, which you can download for free and one is professional.
Some in some point in the course, you may need this professional for explaining one section so you
can still download free trade.
But now let's go with community version free or open source only.
I tell you when you need this professional version just for practicing free trade.
So now let's get started with community opensource.
Obviously, there will be a difference rate for prevention and opensource.
You get some extra filters when you go with a paid professional.
Right.
So you download this and that's all.
One more data file will be installed in your system.
OK, so that looks something like this.
OK, so I'm passing it because I already have in my system, so once you download and this is how it
looks.
So bite the bullet that looks like this.
So just open it and that's it, you will be in an editor to start writing your code.
So initially, when you open for quite some first time, this is how a window opens for you, asking
to create a new project so you can give the new project name.
So in my case, I would call it as a back and automation.
OK, and this is my project, and you have to set a project interpretor that's important.
So what Python software you want to choose so by default, so when you create a new project in your
Python supply, Pritam also creates one python environment for you.
OK, so you have to be very careful because when you download PIP, install all software into one python
environment, and if you choose another Python environment here, this python will not have the knowledge
on the software where you download it.
So when selecting new environment, make sure you choose the path of your python where you have installed
locally and where you are Pip is pointing to.
So that way you can download any software using PIP install from your terminal and that will reflect
in your pajamas on Mesfin.
So this is the part where exactly we have our install software.
So if you don't see here for the first time, then you can click on these three darts and then just
go and.
Select the part of the python what you want.
You have to go to that home homeport and in that form part, that will be fine.
OK, so basically I'm talking about this one.
So if this is your software, this is the python.
So this part you have to give here and then say create.
So this way, you are quite certain, is now pointing to the python environment, which you install
locally and all your installs will reflect that.
OK.
For the first time, it takes some time to create a virtual environment, so please be patient and once
you are done drastic, if your project is pointing to the right Python interpreter, so we call it as
an interpreter or environment.
So file.
Settings go to the settings.
And come to the project, the project, what you selected.
Select Project Interpreter and then.
OK, you'll see that again, it has changed the default of the plates on Project Interpretor, so the
project where this is using is not the python.
What we installed in local.
I told you right.
Plates are also will create one project, Python software.
So this is pointing to that back and automation script slash Python.
So that's why in this python environment, there is no request packet.
You see that there are only two packages.
Get big and set up.
This is not a great interpreter.
So you can actually show all.
You will definitely see us here because you just created a new environment by creating the project.
So you should see something like this.
This is the local software where you are doing all installations, right?
If you don't see here, then simply select plus icon and select the part of that project.
OK, so select Plesac on there and then give the best interpreter.
We already did this before we land up on that page.
So definitely you will see it here.
So once you see that, select that interpreter and click on OK, and then you will see the different
packages because I have a lot of packages in my local software.
That's why, you see, once I change interpreters, so many software start coming and here you will
see a request.
This is the one we just downloaded.
Right.
And the package is reflecting here.
This is what we need.
And now when you click on apply and.
OK, so what I'll call you right here.
All this code is pointing to that python and that python, how all those requests are libraries so it
can support automation of your APIs.
So that's the concept.
So make sure you select the right project interpreter before you start anything so pointed to your local
and then happily download all software from either terminal from your Windows command prompt are from
here.
So we will again see how to download our requests and go to their official website later.
All right, guys, so that's pretty much.
So this is a big election, but in this election year, we have seen all the little things which are
setup.
We have how to set up Python software, and we understood the importance of people to download customized
packages.
And we have also downloaded by Ed and we are pointing out Python, local interpreter to our Bryton project.
Awesome.
With this, we can get started in the next section.
Let's go through the basics of Python before we actually jump into API automation.
So if you think you're already aware of Python basics, then you can skip next to section and then directly
jump to Section three to get started with API automation.
It's up to you guys.
All right.
Thank you.