Welcome back.
So one last step of removing this resources information here, so I am calling this resources because
in an end point, the actual resources like libraries and book for adding the book and EPA and for deleting
the book.
This is the resource library book.
So this is the key word which will help you to reroute to the correct API resource.
So this will reader to delete the book.
And if you add an ebook and that will return to our book API in the end server.
Now is this required to drive from separate files then?
It depends.
So for example, tomorrow, if somebody changes the resource name instead of a small letter, if they
updated to capital letter, then all you got to start feeling.
So if you are using this resource in 10 places, then you should come and update all dentist cases.
So instant.
If you have any central location where you access all these resources, then you can just updated one
single place and all these deaths will be accessed, that resource in that center location.
Right.
So you need not change in all 10 places.
That's the overall point.
OK, let's quickly do that.
It should be very quick.
And with that, we can wrap this discussion and go forward with another new concept in API.
Now, utilities, and I would call it as resources.
And this time I will create one class, OK, one simple class API resources.
OK, that sounds good.
Yeah.
Here you can start creating variables of that class.
I book and delete all the variables, whatever you have as a resource since you can declare all.
So basically in real time you will have around 10 or 12 resources to do everything you can declare here.
Now in our example, we were using Adblock and this is the string, right?
So let's go back to our resources file and have the stream declared here.
And for delete also, we have an example.
Right.
So you just created one class and that will take care of creating all variables and you can simply call
this variable with class name, not variable, because these are class variables.
OK, class variables can be simply accessed with NBA resources, Dot Adbul.
So like that, if you have another resource, I think we have also walkden resource like get book with
Ortolani.
OK, so you can go ahead and declare that resource name as well here.
So it's up to you as an assignment.
So let's actually change this ad book.
Right.
So now come back to you.
But actually just post.
API example, and you need to import that glass from.
And what is that finding sources like these sources import stuff so that it will import all resources
and functions, metals to whatever you have in that fight.
Yeah, so it's in utilities.
So let's give you the latest name.
OK, now you can remove this, so this is the complete Yodle, right, instead of writing this completely
out of here, I will create one variable.
I would say you are an equal to Albiston in one variable, and I will simply call that you are all here
instead of having a long list of characters in this post that you see that now it's more readable.
Right, because let's have everything here.
OK, so I will remove this.
And now if you want to access the results, as I told you, that you can access it with what is the
class name here?
Yeah, this one.
Right.
AIPA resources.
You can now access it here because you imported that package.
AIPA Resources, DOT and book and perfect.
That's all you need to do, reformat and that will go away and you'll see that this variable now holds
that end point and it can down with results and that complete value we are placing in one variable and
that you all you just placed here.
And now it looks very simple, right?
Similarly, that's also what I will do.
I will create one variable here and I will push that into that variable.
So here is the value which is holding everything.
So copy this.
And instead of having all the dictionary here, you can give that variable value here.
OK, so that's where I think you can break all of this in one single line without having multiple,
let's see how we optimize the code three, four letters back.
It was like messy code with so much of information, but now everything is properly organized so that
one can understand that we are doing one.
Has DDP post a request to the CRM that you are is coming from here.
This is an endpoint coming from one configuration file and that are the book resources coming from the
resources file.
So all those came from externally and we concatenated and created one end point.
So the complete calling Amapa is done in one single line with driving the data from external resources.
So now you run the test one more time and you'll see that nothing is breaking, everything is fast.
And that's how we optimized and cleaned our code.
So I would give you as an assignment to do the same for delete book as well, so you can download the
code of this project from the very next lecture and repeat and place all this on the book API stuff.
It's very simple.
I don't think you really need much time to do this.
Create one more Yoran and Doodle do for the book aspect.
All right.
So that's pretty much how about this lecture, guys, in the next lecture, let's talk about authentication
in APIs.
If you have a scope to authenticate yourself to hit that request, how would you do that?
Let's see that in our next lecture.
Thank you.