Welcome back.
So once you are done with your work, make sure you close the connection with as Head Start, because
if not, multiple connections will be opened up and you will remember it will be filled, right.
OK, next, we will try to see how to upload file from your local system to the server because we thought
of one project initially.
Let's solve this project.
I have one batch file.
So this is the best file.
Basically, this batch file will expect a copy file, which is also here.
So this takes the CSP file and then update status of all the accounts displayed there, either approved
or rejected.
So let me show you here first.
So I'll save this.
So this is the fight now.
You can run this fine.
In your server, and that time when it runs, it expects this file also right as a CSP so that it updates.
So basically these two files now should be in your Linux server.
The reason why we need that in daylight in that server is when it tries to scan the profile details
of the account number and implement the logic.
All those should be accessed from database, but that database is not in your system.
So far, this batch file to work correctly, this should be in the server database.
So as we are assuming that our databases are present in this Linux server.
So let's actually move these two files from our local system to that.
So just assume that you are a developer, gave you the banks file and asked you to run that broad database.
So now your goal is to write a Python script that will take this batch file and deployed it along with
The Cafferty File and then run your batch file there to update us.
Yes, OK, we'll see that.
It's a fun.
So overall, you have to know how to upload files from your local system to Linux, so I copy these
two files.
I'll come back to my editor.
But I will create a new package.
Or you can say directress, well, let's see how that actually comes back to face.
So instead of this batch files, I copy those two files.
So.
Copy.
And you can download the code by end of the section Greenberry.
All right, so there are two files here.
One is a CSFI and there are no status yet because bad job elaborated.
Now, I will go back to my associate misconnect.
And here, where I have to right now go to applaud these two files in the server, it's very easy,
I guess, for that.
There is another protocol which you have to use for uploading that is SFP.
OK, so that is another protocol available to upload or download the files, just like how SFH is used
to connect and that protocol will help you to upload or download.
OK, so first you need to import that.
However, with paramedical you will get it by default.
So you have to open that SFP connection through your Secich.
I'll show you.
Upload files so we can accidentally open another connection, which will help you to transfer files,
vice versa.
OK, that can be done with this safety protocol.
And once you open that protocol, store it in one variable so that this object is now responsible to
transfer the files.
Now, where is the path you have to install it?
So let's say two parts.
One is the destination, but
the destination.
But as I told you, that by default, Python will have access to that home path of easy to happen user.
So an explicit here only.
Right.
And what is the final?
So how would you need to pass it?
So this is our final script.
Not be a script.
Not.
So basically, this fine will get stored in their destination, but as they are not giving any delay
little, but it will take place in the home.
But and from there you have to place that down.
So you need to give that the local pub.
I didn't get this sort of spot and it is present here.
So, again, the relative part copied and pasted here.
Great.
OK, so there is a simple matter now to send files, because this object is aware of such a connection
and also it open panel to send files, right, so that this object.
Dart put what is a matter which will help you to take the file from your local pot and it will place
it in the destination pot.
So basically this method expects to arguments one.
The first one is a local pot to pick the fight and the destination pot in places like.
So now, right now and a seven year, there is no final later with script be right now after running
this court, there should be a filed Lexi.
Perfect execution is done.
Now let's come back here and do a little funnier, and you'll see that script to be very fine.
So that means we have successfully more of our file from our local system to our line, except now you
need to just run this file.
But for this file needs to be filed as an input.
Right.
So that is also present in our local system.
So you need to push that as well.
Let me write another.
Three folders, you can create a method to wrap all this and simply pass a local bar, the destination
part as an input so that you can reuse that matter.
OK, because we already discussed a number of examples of how to drive the usable components from configuration
files.
You see that in utilities.
We have already discussed so many files like this.
OK, so use similar way because there is no point in me showing storing that in separate glass because
we already discussed such kind of mechanism.
OK.
Is the search going to Daymo?
Is that fight here?
OK, I would now give one more part.
And destination file is the.
Take this as an assignment, OK, write this in separate utility file, upload file should be a method
and that should accept local port and destination port and it should do the work for you, OK, instead
of doing it here every day.
Loan Assir.
CSP.
Now we are pushing this file as well, so we destination is the same file and we are giving it from
our veterans.
OK, so now with this one, it will also push this file as well.
Let's see.
Great comeback back and you see that, yes, we find ourselves already.
So what is the next step?
So you have to preserve this batch file, as does a python file.
You can trigger with a command core python space copy.
Right.
OK, so all these files can be triggered with Python space filing.
So as we are using this python monitor, we are clicking as Ranaudo using controls.
But ultimately, if you want to execute all these files from command prompt the syntax is python space
and the file.
OK, and now we should execute this file so that this loan records will get the new status.
Now, if I see the cat, I will give Katamon to see what our contents are having CSFI.
Right now, status is blank.
OK, there is no status if the loan account is approved or rejected for this account.
Now, when you've got a bad job, that bad job will update this CSFI with all the values.
OK, and that by double standards to go from this file only, let's not do it from anything from terminal.
We'll see that in our next letter, OK.
Meanwhile, try to write a reusable matter which will pick this upload file from configuration file.
OK, and you should also drive all this connection also from another configuration file.
So this way your car looks more clean, which we already did for database.
Just replicate.
Same for this section as well.
All right.
Thank you.