Welcome back.
So in the last lecture, I have shown you how to spin up a rebellious Linux server and you need to do
a few more configurations to make this available for you to connect from your Python code.
And let's see what all those.
Not this one.
Yeah.
So firstly, it is by default, will not enable password authentication.
Now, for example, we decided that we will soon connect from overpacked on to this server, which we
just created.
In general, we will make hits collection from Python to your server so far.
This is a search connection we need to give host.
That means IP address of your server so that it will understand and username password.
These are the details you have to send.
But by default, NWS will not allow anyone to login with password authentication.
OK, that's default set to off.
So as we are going to connect to that server with password, so we should make sure that we have to
enable it.
So how to enable it?
So there are some set of comments which we need to run to enable the password in the server.
Let's do that now.
Right, so right now you are logged in as the easy to hyphen user because this is the user.
Now, there are two users in any other.
One is the road user, just like in your Windows machine, you will have seen users and a bunch of names.
Right.
If you have two different accounts.
Similarly, Mirabilis, also by default, you will get one as a road user and another one is easy to
hyphen user.
So by default, all configuration software installations you have to do as a rule user only, not as
easy to have one user.
OK, so when you log in, you will be by default, easy to hyphen user now to log back as a road user.
This is the command.
You have to give pseudo your hyphen.
OK, I have given the documentation so you need to blindly follow this documentation to make things
work.
But again, please do not expect again my new details about all of this, because that's a whole different
story and it will be like another complete course.
That is already one, though, of course, where I have explained all this clearly.
So this lecture is just for setting up again.
I repeat that in real time you will do all this work as automation engineer.
You will be given the server ready with all its assets, connections open.
You just need to write a code to connect, which will be seen from later.
Just that you will practice with me, Baddeley.
I'm doing all this so that you can also have one set up and get some confidence.
OK, right, so you see that when you do like this, you will be now logged in as a road user.
So there is one file, as I suggested, configuration file.
You need to open that file and make a change to enable password authentication.
It will open like this and select a button, which means insert right after, insert more when you select
and then only it will be able to edit this file.
So scroll down and you should see password authentication.
Yeah.
Here, easy to use as keys for remote access.
So by default, password authentication is set to know.
OK, so let's think it through.
Yes.
Right, so the password is said to us and now you can make a connection with username and password.
So once Americans click on Escape Button, then give column WQ.
So this is the command to step escape Collen WQ so that it file will be saved no good.
And next thing, what you have to do, you need to reload the service.
So you have made configuration changes, right.
You have to refresh your server with these changes.
So in Linux don't have to reload.
So service SAHD reload.
So this will reload and changes will be applied successfully.
OK.
And next, you have to create a password for easy to hide from user.
I just told you that you need to connect to your Linux Servatius to make, as I said, the connection.
It needs username and password.
So you enable the password authentication.
But what is the password?
We don't know that.
OK, so by default, user name is created for you.
Easy to hyphen user when you create an instance, but for this user we should give password also.
But we should not try to login for the root username and password.
OK, we're not allowed to securely connect with the credentials user to create another user and then
connected to that server.
So by default, easy to hyphen user is the name which will be created.
So you just need to set a password for this game.
OK, and to get a password.
This is the command versus WD.
You can simply write this.
Password, easy to have use user, and it will ask you to set new password.
Here I'm sitting easy to use only as password again one more time.
I made it round, I guess.
Yeah, plus did not match because I clicked on another button.
Perfect.
So when you give two times, then it will say ID tokens updated successfully.
So we are all set.
So basically these two are the details we need.
One is to create a password and then enable that from alias, which we did.
OK, so with this configuration, we are done.
So in the next lecture, let's start with Python court tools connect securely to the server and play
around with documents.
OK, thank you.