Welcome back.
So in this lecture, let us see how to send cookies through your API requests for that, I will create
one more new.
Biton Fionn.
And say miscellaneous.
So let's start with import the question.
So you all on my website, there is one on my website with his GDP.
Well, who's your Economy.com, right?
So my website has one cookie, so basically when people land, we will see what is the visit month that
they visited last year.
OK, so if their visit is let's say this is August and if they have listed this in June, so if there
are no site changes after June, we will lower the website from the cash, what they already have.
So that response time will be fast.
OK?
And if you have updated our website after June and if the visit month is June, so then we will bring
this website from the real summer without caching.
So that's where we use cash in our website and.
To track what is the visit month?
We use cookies, so whenever people land on the page, we use a cookie called Visit the Month.
So this is a common like every website have a number of cookies to give the best experience to the users.
So whenever they land, they use a cookie called visit month.
So we will read this cookie, and based upon that, as I told you, we will launch our webpage.
Now, you want to send a call to this.
You are all this is an end point and you can make one request part to this end point.
OK, so while making if you don't pass any cookie, it will load up the bits from the actual server.
OK, so if you want to load the website from the cache, then to this you will expect a cookie from
you from your browser.
It expects a cookie called Visit Munt.
So based upon that, it might learn that Olegas, you are all for you.
OK, all cache web page.
So let's try to send first.
Let's try to fill this.
Oh, you are telling us this is a.
Bows to God, you can make that call also, that does not matter.
Because we are just hitting the seawall without any logic behind that.
OK, so you make the call here and there is one cookie which you have to send, if you don't send,
it would be just like normal.
Slinked.
So if you want to send any cookies from your pipeline automation testing, then you have to send those
cookies in a big study format.
Now, you know, this is enough syntax and dictionary and I have my cookie like this visit.
Munt.
Right, and this is a cookie collar and let's say I have written for brevity.
On second spelling mistake.
Philip.
OK, so I will start this dictionary in one variable, let's call this cookie.
OK, and just like have you have sent headers in your get that similarly, you can send cookies also
so you can say cookies equal to and send your cookie.
That's OK.
That's all you need to do if you want to send any FBI request all along with the cookies.
OK, so earlier, if you want to send headers, you have used headers equals two and then you sent headers
as a dictionary.
Similarly for cookies, you have to use cookies equals to give any name here.
It's up to you that we're able to send here and make sure this we're able to have the extended format
with key value pairs of cookie, cookie and cookie value.
Right.
And that's it, guys.
So I want to make this request call.
You can see the status print.
You will get the status and the response variable after you make this call and you can say, but in
response status score, it should be 200.
OK, so in this, like, my goal is to just show you how to send cookies.
If you are, you all are important demands to have them as part of their request.
You see that status is 200, so now you understand how to send cookies, so let's do now.
Another example that is has traditionally been cookies.
So there is one.
Let's take a call.
So here you are, not sure if it really sent cookies to Starbright.
We just got status 200.
But you don't know if it is actually accepted by the server so far that that is another way for you
to practice.
So basically, you see that this is a get called with the cookies.
So if you hit this end point, this will give you the response back with the cookies, what you sent
through your input.
Let me show you.
Right.
So you see here responsibility, so right now you did not send any cookies with this to request you
all.
So this is one Rustaveli I got.
So you did not send them cookies.
So responsively, how blind?
Basically this independent.
What does it do?
It will see what cookies I received that cookies.
It will wrap in the responsible party and send it back.
So if you try to automate this API call and if you check if you get response back as Cookie, then you
will understand that my cookies are successfully submitted because only successfully submitted cookies
are returned back in response.
So what do you send us in for the request you should see in the response.
OK, so let's do this example so that you can be better practice with these cookies.
So this is the end point we need to track.
And this is a get request, right?
So let me go back.
So it was dark.
Get and this is the end point, so either you can store your cookies in variable in dictionary and pass
that variable here or you can directly give that extended itself.
Sorry, let's it visit month for then you can send any of your cookies you can to visit them.
So this cookie is valid.
Not that you need not worry because of this end point is saying whatever new cookies you send, I will
give you back again in response so that when we know that these cookies are accepted by this end point.
Right.
So one way of storing these cookies in one variable and then giving that variable.
OK, you can say 2022 to visit here.
All you can basically give that big story here.
Response.
OK, so now let's try to bring the response response dot text, so this will give you the days and back.
So if you have this cookie in you this and so, that means you can conclude that you have successfully
submitted this end point with the cookie.
Let's run this again.
Perfect, you see that this is the response, what you got, and it clearly told that I had this cookie
with my input.
So this is how you can know that if you are cookies accepted, so does anyone have the capability of
giving the cookies back?
Now, you can also use session manager here.
Let's say visit is one of the common cookie used for this has been OK.
So visit here is something which may change for every call you make.
So you are passing it as a parameter explicitly.
But if you think that resentment is the common cookie, OK, just imagine.
So in that case, let's make a session, the dart session.
We had one very lengthy session, and for this session, let's add the common cookies so that automatically
that cookie will be applied to every call to make.
So right now, you can now call this request.
Don't get started.
OK, perfect.
You can still make it because voters see him and now you can give some additional capabilities for this.
In the last lecture, we give the capabilities related to authentication.
Right.
So here what I will little session dot the odds we have given you.
Can you come and help us also?
Similarly, there is cookies here, OK, cookies dard update.
So basically you have to say update cookies with this information so you can send this dictionary inside
this update argument.
Perfect, so now this session is loaded with this cookie.
Now, when you hear this request session, doGet, basically you hit this wall and you have this cookie
and this cookie will be automatically added by default because you are using session and this session
is already loaded with this cookie.
OK, now, when you're on this program, what is the response you expect in this disembody?
So you should see two cookies not visit a 2022 and visit months, but also because you are in session
and session have already cookie loaded Lizzi.
Perfect, you see, that was it, Monday, February 20, 2010.
So if you have something like this common cookie, common head, a common authentication which will
be used frequently across all your end points, you can create session manager and update that.
So if you write requests back.
So this have no idea of a month.
And now when you run this, it will not return this month.
It will just return what you have written for a it.
Did you see that?
So I hope now you understand how the U.S. manages and how to also send cookies with your input request.
OK, so that's pretty much about dealing with cookies.
So one thing you want to you have to remember here is you can just send cookies as a second argument
and it expects all cookie value in this format.
That's.
All right.
Thank you.