Welcome back.
Right, so in the last lecture, we have set up my sequel server and we have successfully opened Workbench.
So in this lecture, I will first add a few tables in my sequel server so that we can then use Python
Automation to query into that tables and get the results.
OK, so I already have one complete sequel query, which you can directly copy into your workbench.
You can download this query from this lecture and directly submit this so that it will create a new
database.
It's very simple.
So as we are not going in depth into understanding how to create a database or how to write a query
to create a table, because that is out of scope.
The overall point of this section is to explain how can we call the queries from Python language into
our database and how we read the output data tables using Python.
OK, so that's fine.
So you can use this second query from this lecture so that it creates a new database called Python Automation
in your SQL Server.
And we are creating two tables, customer info table, and we are adding fuel records into that customer
info.
OK, and then I'm creating another table called books and I'm adding fuel records into that books table.
That's all.
It's very simple.
OK, right.
So I will execute this so that it will run Step-By-Step.
It creates a database and it does all the operations.
Great.
So you can see that now when you run this entire query, you can download this from this lecture.
OK, and after you can see that one table is created with books.
So when you do select start from books, then you will get output like this.
So these are the books present in our table.
So table name is a box, which is present in Python Automation database, right?
So similarly, we created the table called customer info.
So let me.
Can I maximize this?
I would put it right.
Yeah, similarly, there is one more called select star.
Another table.
What we created is customary in full.
OK, so when you try to go through this, then that will give you the records presenting this customer
in people.
OK, now first, let's start with this table, OK, so we know that these are the different rules present
in this table.
So now our goal is to connect to this database through our Python Automation Corp. And from our code,
we will give this query so that these results should be retrieved.
Right.
And our goal is to read this results from our Python code.
OK, so if we are able to do that, then tomorrow, if there is any requirement of reading the values
from database and or any operations with your Python code, you can easily do it.
So key point here is to understand how can we connect to database and how can we hit queries?
Right now I am giving this query from Markwayne today.
I should be able to give this from Python and I should be able to read all the results from the python.
Let's try to understand everything and then we will go back to our previous APA project and say, how
can we build the payload dynamically from this bookstaber?
OK, so when you do select start from books, you have book name, ISBN Island Ottery.
So from these details, let's construct a design for an API.
OK, so before going that, let's now understand a basics about Python, my sequel.
So first thing, what you need to do is to download a package which supports Python, my sequel Connection.
OK, so you can just go to the Google and search for Python, my connector, and we will have yeah,
this is the right if you go to their official website.
This is the command you have to provide to install.
Packets of Misick will connect, select Scoppetta, this clipboard.
I already have in my mission.
So you can go to terminal.
And then give this guy.
So that will install.
The plug in for you, if not even you can start typing in your file, so automatically this pipe tapping
will suggest to you to install that package, you can do that.
OK, so we have successfully installed my signal connector python.
Now it's time to see one test so far.
Now for this lecture, until we understand everything, I will build one standalone test.
Thereafter, we will make changes and do all configurations in framework standards.
OK, so if I directly start from framework's standards, we will get a little confused.
So I don't want to do that.
So Python fame and.
The name we can give as DB demo.
Right, so first of all, you need to import a package called my sequel, Dot Connector.
So this is the package you need to import.
Mixed, so there is a method in this package, my second dot connector dot.
OK, so this method will help you to connect to the database.
But this method expects, I think, four parameters.
One is a host.
So that means where you are database server is present, OK?
It is a equal number.
Basically that is the first parameter.
And next parameter is you have to provide a database name.
We'll get one MySQL server can have multiple databases.
OK, it can host a number of databases so you can simply create database by giving this commensal.
Create a database, and that's all one baby will be created.
So that's the second parameter.
You have to go, which is you want to conduct.
The third one is authentication username and password.
So these two details we have to provide to connect to you.
One of my sequel server database.
OK, so while installing this MySQL server, we have provided one username and password.
Right?
So those details you have to send in this matter so that don't automatically create one connection string
based upon all these details and it will return you the connection object with which you can talk to
your database.
Right.
So let's start giving those values.
So as I said, the first one is the host most equals two as it is hosted in our local seven, you can
simply give a local host because that's when I was is there.
Right.
It's now a local mission.
Mixed database details database equals two.
We just created one database.
The name of that is applied on automation.
So by dawn automation.
Good.
And next user.
Yuzu is the road.
And password, the password, what I have given to establish connection is that I should be economy.com.
So this password is nothing but the one which you give to install.
OK.
OK, so now this method returns a connection object.
OK, and now you can simply see if connection is successful or not, you can run and return with this
object object that is connected.
So this method will return true if connection is successfully established.
If not, it will return false.
Lizzi Alperin.
So make sure you have these details, so you should be doing that because you just installed in the
previous lecture.
So let me run this past.
Perfect, Drew.
So that means we have successfully connected to the database called Python Automation.
So in this database we created two tables, great customer info and books, so you can happily access
it by calling what is on this database.
So let's do that.
Now our next picture.
All right, thank you.