Welcome back.
So if there is any authentication required in sending the request to an AP, then how can we handle
it through by automation?
So far that if you check out their official documentation, so they have clearly given that that is
a basic authentication with username and password.
So this is how you can send just like how you have sent jesson equals two headers.
Similarly, there is another parameter, which I always say miscellaneous.
Right.
And I will leave it blank after the last argument.
So the argument you can pass out and you can provide your username and password.
So that way it will hit this API with these credentials so that you will be securely logged in.
Right.
So not all APIs will be given access to directly get the response.
So you should authenticate yourself if there is any such kind of mechanism for your API, you can do
that by providing these details.
So now to do an example, let's switch to the GitHub.
So to access any API in the GitHub, you can directly use this.
You want to land on this?
Get now, now.
So there are a lot of apps exposed by these case.
But still, if you want to access any API, you need to authenticate yourself.
OK, so without authentication, you cannot access any hub repository you can access like water repositories
available in complete GitHub.
But finally, you are a specific user.
Let's say you want to know repositories of your account.
Then obviously you should login, right, without providing your login details.
GitHub will not give you the details of your account.
So that's what you have the example Artosis.
So if you want to log into your account, then provide the details so that you will be securely authenticated
through your request.
OK, now, so make sure you create one GitHub account, right.
And then we will try to login securely using an API.
OK, so this is the example they have given.
So this is an end point.
To access any user GitHub account, so if it returns 200 documents, you securely access that account.
So it depends upon what credentials you provide, username and password.
OK, if you provide wrong credentials, then it will give 404 to this status based upon the value provided.
So let's do that.
Let's try to understand this by writing the code here so that, you know, you will get some idea on
how to work on this.
Right.
So we have direct example here.
Let me go back to.
So they create one more file.
So this is just two lines of code, right?
So I will try to write that he had itself in that post example itself.
Let me put a comment.
Authentication.
Right, so it was dark, you get.
So there you are and you can identify it in that conflict, Parcell file.
It's up to you.
You can declare the property, start in and give it there.
But you understand that concept, right?
Let's not again do that.
All so simply, I will create one variable again, you Aurel and GitHub user.
This is the user.
So you can now use any GitHub API, you can read the documentation and using it have AIPA by giving
these credentials.
Right.
So that I can simply provide you all here.
Mixed art is where you have to provide your username and password, right?
So if you log in to GitHub dot com.
So sign and take your username and password, so once you sign up, you get these details right.
So I will just pass these details into my test that's on.
So first you have to produce a name.
Here it is, Rahul's at the Academy.
OK, next is the password.
So basically, I don't want to showcase my password by writing here so that I will write a letter like
this get past.
I can still get a password.
So this is the matter which will get the password for me, so I will clear this password somewhere in
another file so that I can take it from there.
OK.
So we have different files important here, right?
So let me go to resources is for classes configurations.
Yeah, I can have it here.
Get password.
So right, and I can enter some password here, OK, but actual password, I will enter offline.
So basically that password will be now directly accessible here in your post API example, you see that
at Alesco.
Now, so when you hear this request, you have securely authenticated, right, so you take the response
back.
Good response.
Similarly, in your company as well, you may be asked to provide these credentials, obviously basic
authentication will be there so you can simply use this parameter and get a response to see the status
quo.
You know, right.
Darte status.
So this will give you the status.
Good.
So I'll print this and see what kind of output I get for this.
Control shift of tempo, this will run out of oil and gas, and that's fine, you see that 200 status.
So if I change any user name this time, I have given wrong a name and went out on this again.
It should throw in a little bit of state, a score of four zero one.
That is that means you have not successfully authorized.
Right.
So this is how you can play around with authorization and sometimes you might get some SSL connection
error.
OK, so by default, when you are accessing any history BP related websites, they may have imposed
some SSL certifications.
So when you are talking to those servers which have SSL certification enabled, then when you try to
access this, then you might run into error.
So to fix that issue, whenever you encounter any SSL certification, you can add one more attribute
here.
Verify, verify equals to false.
So if you give this barometer, though, they are sarvodaya expecting as a barometer, you are compressing
that condition and you are submitting your request.
OK, so make sure you add this barometer if you run into any errors on a certification on SSN and read.
So that's all.
That's how you can authenticate.
And based upon the apps you can have, you can try it.
And there is one more API handling of file uploading.
So let's see that.
István, right now.
I don't have examples for that, but we can discuss here.
So basically there are some apps available where you can upload file by calling the request.
OK, so here there is an Excel sheet report, Dot Exelis.
So you have to upload that file to upload that file.
You see that there is already one example here, his GDP bindert, OAG.
So this is also one of the good AIPA where you can do some practice.
So take this example in practice.
OK, so basically this is the file and we need to upload this to anyone.
So they have created one file object.
You see that it's a dictionary, key values a file, and then we are opening the file in rewritable.
OK, so we have taken that into an object and we are passing that into file sequels to that object.
OK, so this is the key value here, just like how you have header cookies and what we have used in
our as a parameter.
Right.
And Paramount is one of the key word we have used for.
Get request made, similarly, that is one more call filed, so that will take argumentum files object,
which comes as a dictionary like this Arezzo you can upload file assman.
So these are the commonly used APIs.
So we have discussed pretty much about get forced and if it is a delayed then you can just change it
to delete.
Right.
And we have also seen how to pass this with the logic, how to see the state escort's, how to validate
the headers and how to drive the values externally and all.
And we have also seen authorization.
So these are the common scenarios first across our API testing in Python.
So if you come across any new issue on API, which you think that can be automated through Python,
so this documentation will be a friend for you.
So search for that specific request and you will get a response.
And if you want to practice a few more, then I would recommend you to go to his TDP.
But already there you have are different APIs available for practice.
OK, but I have shown you one real time library API which I have designed so delayed get.
But a lot of things here for you to practice.
And these guys are also provided examples like what request and data.
And you can use this and here how to parse parameters.
Obviously we discussed all this.
So you really need not go anything here.
But if there is something which is missed, this is always different for you.
All right.
So that's pretty much about this letter.
In the next lecture, I will introduce database.
So we will delicately discuss about database for sometime.
Once you get familiar about how to access data from database using Python code, then we will come back
to this API examples again and then build Jassam, whatever we are sending as an input here from the
database queries.
OK, but before that, first we need to understand how to query from Python.
Right, which we will be seeing in our next section.
Thank you.