Welcome back.
In this letter, I will show you how to connect your scenarios with actual implementation of the code.
So now for this.
Get in line, given the details, which needs to add library, so that means all the book details should
be here.
So let's see how to do that.
In the futures file folder you have right under this folder, you have to create another directory.
So make sure you create your new directory under feature directory only don't create outside because
we have cannot understand if it is somewhere outside.
OK, so inside the steps, let's go and create one file.
That could be your Python file only because the code is in Python, right?
So obviously you have to end up writing Python file only by don't file.
You can suspend implementation, something like this, so we are implementing for each and every step
of scenario.
So let's call it as a step implementation.
So Behave treats that each and every line here as a step and implementation, real code implementation
of that steps comes here.
OK, so we are in the python file now.
So what should we do?
So let's create one method.
Define, let's call it again, step implementation like this.
Now, so you can take up your step, which is here.
So right now this is your step, right?
And this step is tied up to the given tag here.
OK, so given that you have this length, so in your step implementation, you can say Abdulle given
and inside this box, that and tideline.
OK, so you have this line here, right?
Given the details, copy this line and come to your step definition as it is tied up with the given
back, give the giving back and give like this and that's OK.
So automatically now when you run your code first, it will try to execute the scenario.
OK, so once it encounters this first line, OK, this we have things that ask, OK, there is one given
back and this is the step for that.
Now let me check what I want to execute for this first step.
Then it will find out first steps for that.
Is it one step further?
It will go inside and now it will filter with all given tags as it found given back.
Let's say there are five different acts here.
It will first filters given back from when and then because the first step is given here.
One second giving back.
Next, it looks for the string, right?
So once the string matches, then it will blindly execute this method.
So whatever you write inside will get executed.
It's very simple.
OK, so here where we will write actual code, which is tying up with this length.
So this way it will come and execute the method which is tied up to this given and it's all right.
And this method expects a variable called context.
This is very, very important.
I will soon explain how this context variable helps us to try variables across each and every step.
So now first let's import.
We have not given.
I think let's talk from behaving Footstar, so this way our tax will get imported.
Now, so similarly, you can do it for then and then also now, if you don't want to do on your own
and if you want some readymade methods available to copy paste, you can still do that.
You can run.
You were caught with a jab here.
Sorry, let me go to terminal.
OK, I can still run this feature file right now.
We don't have any data, right?
If I tried to execute this test case, nothing will happen, but it will complain that there is no implementation
for these two.
So we have written a method for this.
If I give just pass, that means it just skips this method.
OK, but at least you have integration back.
So this court also will skip it.
But when it tries to execute these two lines, it will quickly go and search for when and then text
and this text.
We still did not write this right.
Then it will complain in the output logs that go and implement those methods, like let's see how it
does.
So to execute your best guess, you can simply pass him.
When you give this behave come, it will come and sat for all future files which have to feature the
extension.
So right now we have only one feature file.
Right.
So if you see the output, it clearly given that syntax for us, so you need not manually like this
Staggs and create method with doorless that you can implement these definitions for undefined steps.
So it's complaining that I am trying to execute, but I did not find the connection to its code to execute.
OK, for the first step, it did not complain.
The book details which needs to be added to library because to be redundant, but it complained for
another two minutes.
So instead of you writing it, you can just blindly copy this and pasted here.
So this way you can save some time and this is how that happens.
So for the next one, it is a Wintek.
So we are finding it when.
So reformat and this is the DenTek, you see that every line, what you have written is successful argument
here.
You can ignore this.
You it's not required.
I don't know why that's Kim.
OK, so right now we did not implement anything.
So that's why it's complaining that not implemented.
Edit we can remove all this.
So in the next letter, let's bring out our actual code inside these three details and get started.
OK, so I will just stop this lecture by writing Boscawen.
Now we will bring real court from our post API example and then push it into our step, definitions
will continue.
Thank you.