All right, so we have completed upload files and now let's run the comments again, and this is the
command which will help you to trigger, right.
So I will again copy the same comment once you uploaded files, triggered the batch of the batch.
Come on.
And the what you have to learn is Python, and it's going to be very.
I think by default, when you're working with a mission, Python will be in start in general if you
don't have Python installed in your server.
This command will not make any sense because ultimately we are executing this command in terminal only.
Right.
If there is no python here that will not work, it will drain.
So by default, I guess anybody else will give the python to see that there is a version already.
So that means Python is installed.
So if I run this command now, let's see what happens and then we will investigate our CSP file one
more time and see if the status is updated.
OK, in real time, we will have some command to execute that batch that could be controlling jobs basically.
And back in you will have jobs like controller jobs.
You can execute those jobs with some long commands.
So you just ask a developer, what is that command and that command, that batsmen's and read some files.
So you have to open that files and validate that file.
Can be Jason, that file can be CSFI, that file can be text file.
So using your python, you should be able to pass them and do a lot of things.
Look at all these are like salvarsan and back in automation.
OK, so I'm giving you some scenarios, example, because you know how to parse this and also you know
how to handle a request.
You know how to handle text files which were discussed in Python basic section.
And now we also nosiest these are like common files.
So don't think that Excel will be there.
OK, Excel isn't like Microsoft application in 99 percent gives us all the bad shit back and jobs will
generate 60 files or DNS symbols but not accept.
Right, I will run this one more time.
So this will replace as it's already present, right?
These files are already present, but when you run again, this will replace with music.
OK.
So come on has run and you see that we executed this comment as well earlier, when you don't get to
see the contenders discovered displayed right, I will run this comment one more time and you'll see
that uproar rejected and this bad up have communicated with the proper database and then give you the
results.
But in our case, there is no proper database.
I return some logic that will randomly select a.
OK, so I just returned one python file, which will randomly fill the files in real time.
Just assume this is how you get OK.
Now, there is no point of using the results here.
You want this CSP file back to your system now because you need to validate and see now, for example.
Three, two, three, two, one, go.
OK, you definitely know this guy alone should reject because these guys have no minimum balance maintained
from two years.
So when you send this file to your batch, you will expect the output, the redacted.
So then you can say that, hey, this batch job is working as expected.
One test case suddenly, if you see approved by any way, then you can fail the test and say something
is wrong with this bad job.
Because when we give this account in GSV, we made sure that this is rejected because we verify that
there are no account balances or no credit card payments.
So that way you can validate and show your your results.
OK, so your file is ready.
Now, the next step is to download uploading is done now download the file to your local to local system.
It's also very simple, yes.
Right, there is a method, again, to download also.
But it just the reverse.
So this time we are getting the file right.
Earlier we were putting the file in the cell, but now we are getting back.
So as we are getting back the file, we should use get better, that's all.
And from there, you are getting you have to give the part where exactly you have to file is located
in the server.
So in the sidebar, it's on the home only and the home.
But the CSFI file.
This is our destination, Patrick.
From here, we were getting back to our local system and to where do you want that, you have to give
that part.
So let's right here in the backfills only.
Batch files or should we create one package called output folder?
So I'll create one more directory and call US output files.
OK, and you can access those output files, output files, so you are giving the part where exactly
you will see as we file should get stored in the box first to have input file and output file.
You should get back from your server.
That's all guys get is a method to get back from destination to your source.
All right.
So this is an end to end, which will connect to your system and make a connection, send you a batch
file, then send you a loan files, CSFI, and then run this batch file once it ran.
And it will pick the CSP file from there and it gets into your local system.
So I would run this test.
OK, execution is finished, and when you open this, you'll see that there is an output file.
OK, double click on that and here you go.
You got back all your status, so you sent an input file with the blank details.
You see input and output.
You got back with all the filling the details.
So bad job has to fill all this.
This is what we call back end.
Right.
And this is how all salvarsan automation happens.
Great.
Now, you got back your file successfully.
What next?
So once you got back everything, now you have to validate whether this user what is that user three
to three to write.
Three, two, three, two, one is rejected or not, but this is Random Day, so sometimes you'll see
director or sometimes you'll see abroad.
I have written the script in such a way that it randomly places one value for everyone.
But anyway, now you know how to read to be fine.
So once you get your CSP file, let me open this in Excel so that you will have some clear vision.
So that is why in the last section, I have explained to you how to relax before it's OK, everything
is properly streamlined.
I'm just writing everything in one single file so that you can have a good reference.
But I would file CSB.
OK, you know, you asked need to open the file.
Where does that file is present?
That file is present in this location.
And you are opening as I read more, so give any reference, our particular skills.
Yes, we've.
File.
OK, so you need to import one package called import CSFI, because that have a method called reader
with which you will be able to read the three dot reader.
So you have to read this file, so you have to give the reference of that and the delimiter what we
have used this summer.
Right.
So I hope you have gone through all my previous B.S. So assuming that I'm writing the things very faster,
if not, I would refer you to go back and see how we have passed and learned about reading and writing
to see us to be fine.
OK, so we sent file object and this is our delimiter, everything looks good, and now this will read
the entire content and we will get in one real object, right?
So, yes, we read it.
Yes.
It's not in the real object.
So this is nothing but a list now to iterate through each and every arrow in that list you can write
for looked for in a spirit.
OK, so basically in every iteration, one rule will be picked.
So in the first iteration, this is the second iteration, this third iteration, for reason, like
each and every rule is, that is how we did it.
OK, so we have to do for Loop also to understand how this happens.
I would recommend you to refresh if you don't remember that now, once we got the list, this is how
it really is, right?
Our goal is to see if this account number status is rejected or not.
So, once again, the rule, this is how the list will be there.
Ralf's zero will with this guy and no one will win this game.
OK, so I will write a condition like if all of zero.
Equals to.
Three, two, three, two, one.
If the rheumatiz, we need to extractable off one.
No one should be equal, still rejected.
And I am giving a speech in front of that.
OK, I hope you understand here sort of zero.
In addition, there will be this one, this will be a big one, two, three, two, as one, two, three
do is not equal to this.
It will skip asserting it and it will run again next time for three to four three zero zero NO-MATCH
And third time there is a match because this respect rule of zero three two, three, two, one, when
that matches with this immediately in the same list of Varnum accessing OK, when the match happens,
then only I am going inside the condition.
So obviously this calls that particular only when I'm going in said only when it matches.
So in that row first index.
And you are marching with if it is rejected or not, so same kind of example we did in case we demo,
but we did in different fashion, we actually captured all these items in one list and all these items
in one list and we got index number.
And with that index number we verified in this list.
OK, that is one way of doing and the same logic I did in another way with simple optimist.
OK, so my whole intention is to show multiple ways of passing it instead of going blindly with one
logic every time.
So make sure you close your CSFI Excel sheet and you can delete all these output files even if it is
there.
Don't worry, it will replace with the new set file.
OK, even the old results are there.
That's OK because that word replaces.
But anyhow, I will delete this.
To factor everything.
All right.
It will do an end to end its.
Rejected.
But that is an assertion, and I think this time that bad job gave you approval.
Yes.
You got a buck in your back job, isn't it?
So you clearly know that this user, this account number should always be rejected.
If there is something wrong that is bad job is not working as expected.
So you have to your back in the batch job.
It is sitting somewhere in the Linux server using your Python.
OK, that's what we call automation.
Instead of saying, OK, why?
What's the issue?
Let's open the file output file and you'll see that for this guy, this came back as a broad.
OK, well, then again, this time you might see the correct one, because, as I told you, that I
have written logic in such a way that it will go trajector that approved.
I will go back.
Finally, one more time.
And then let's change to approve.
I will run one more time.
But this time it passed because that doesn't give you a back as approved.
OK, so this is how you can automate.
So I'll go back to the document and let's see if we covered all the stuff or not.
And also before that, now, you were ready to prepare your resume with all the skills you learned from
this course so you can showcase your resume with Pythonesque skills.
But the utilities, what you have learned until this lecture, because we have tested various points
of all back automation related things, so you can proudly showcase all these skills in your résumé.
And that will really help you to short list an interview, because these are unique skills not many
of people have in the market.
So I request you to add this, because then only you will get real value for what you did if you need
any assistance for your resume.
Update regarding Python backend automation points they taught me here and I will send you points and
you can plainly add into your resume.
OK, now let's just recap what we did in this section.
We ran the comments from our local python bulimics via, as I said, what is the command and execute
command.
Right.
This is the command method which help you to execute commands.
And we also know how to read the output from the next mission using a study out one commands and you
read the output with the red matter and you can read all the output given by that command.
And how to transfer files from local server to Unix on Linux, whatever of it, and for that also upload
files, we have understood that there isn't a safety protocol which you can open with openness of people
matter and then destination.
But local park and put metal will help you to put your files in destination.
But.
And running Python bats files and Linux server.
Yes, we did that batch file we ran.
Next, download the files from limits to your local mission via SFD.
We did that, too.
We have successfully downloaded with getting better CSP.
We find this present in the server.
You brought it to your local output files and finally validated batch files output through passing.
You want to see Ussery files?
Yes, we passed our output files and we are telling you to fill that post.
So that's pretty much about how you can make such connections to server from your Python code using
the paramedical library.
I hope you really enjoyed the section.
And as I told the assignment for you to use to write reusable components for upload, download and connection,
just like how I have written for the database and then make this framework more optimized.
So that's all I have thus far.
The section.
Thank you.