Welcome back.
So now let's start step by step process, so we will first try to print all the titles displayed in
this page.
OK, let's try to scrap this Web page and get the all titles.
So for that, let's go back to our editor.
And you are clear that now the soap object is now holding all the rest of that page.
Right?
So there is a method called.
Fined.
So basically, this method will help you to extract the data based upon the attributes, what you provide.
So this method will take two arguments.
So if you were, our goal is to, first of all, find.
This entire table, so let's start scrapping, I would spy on this trailer.
Like, so the entire content is actually starting in one table, it seems.
You see that?
You can see finalist table glass equals two, so this is a table.
So now let's dig and get access to this table now.
So now about a soap object is having access to international right?
So let's limit and shrink our solution by narrowing our search results, by first accessing only the
stable content, because this table content have all the data right.
Everything is wrapped under this table and in there are rules.
Each room have one title.
So now to narrow down our results so you can see.
So this object is having the access to entire content from entire history and content find, so it accepts
two arguments.
First argument you can give that Tagami.
OK, so table is a tag, name and second argument to access this.
They will uniquely you can pass some attributes, like there is a actable called class finalist, so
this attribute class will help you to identify this table uniquely now.
For example, let's say there are two tables on this Web page, one table here and one, they will decide
to get all the titles.
Now, when you say so, not fine with the table, then it will blindly find out.
That tag name timetable, so if you find multiple, then we don't know which one to use.
So that's why to give it more filters, to tell it with more information, you can pass attributes so
that it can uniquely identify your table.
So and it works out nothing but what you see here, there is one attribute called class, so you can
pass attributes in a dictionary like this class column.
So what is your name?
Finalist.
So this way, you are properly starting with the attribute and they will show that you are SoPE object
and I will identify this table and it will reach here so you can store it into one variable, you can
say.
Movies, they will.
That's fine, you can put the caps are just asking naming conventions, right?
So what is the difference between these two variables and mobility?
Will this have the access to entire statement on the page?
Now, this movie star will have access to this table content.
OK, because our goal is starting off scrapping this present in this table.
So we narrow down our results and we are starting here.
Now, I will print a game and see if we have successfully narrowed down our results.
Will this table not prettify this time?
It should not give me the entire Hesterman content on the page.
It should give me the Hesterman content related to that table.
Only Lizzi.
OK, so you got the results and you'll see that it's ending with a table back, his statement, which
started with a table tag and it ended with a table.
So that means we have successfully narrowed down and we are now holding of history and content of this
table only with the help of this variable movies table.
Right.
And now what I can do so because we are doing all this because our ultimate goal is to first get the
title of this Web pages.
So this is one Titan.
And you'll see that I can see if you find that there is a class called the text and at the same time
in this table there are those.
So basically, every movie have one protea.
Right, so let's narrow it down further.
Now, I will use this movie stable.
And I would say dard find all that is another matter, can't find all, so when you find it will return
only one result.
But when you just find out, it will return all the matching results.
You know that.
Find out.
Find out will take first argument, which is a mandatory diagne.
And second argument is optional if you want to get an identify uniquely.
So in our case, when I do movies, they will not find all the searches will happen.
Now inside this table.
Only when you do not find out, then such will happen an entire history and will continue.
But we still don't.
Our results and we placed on this movie stable.
Right.
And now we are quiting.
Find out on that narrowed down results.
So now search will happen on this table part.
So we are simply asking, get me all the data with the tag name pick.
OK, so all these rules now will be retrieved.
So when you say find, then it will retrieve only the faster trailer you are seeing here.
Right.
That will be retrieved.
But when you just mentioned final, then it will return all the rules.
So if you have knowledge on selenium, it will be easy for you to grab all these.
OK, when I say easy, it will be quick.
You can quickly correlate things.
So get out.
I can say those.
Nice.
So all the rules are present in this.
Rules are variable.
OK, now you can I trade over this rules and pull out each and every rule.
OK, so all the rules are successfully retrieved right now.
I will write one simple for fun rule in the rules.
So in Python, if you want to have a follow up from all the rules because it returns a list of rules
in every iteration, one rule will be picked and that can be acted inside this for condition.
OK, so in the first iteration it will be the first row and that will get stored in this rule.
OK, now what you should do when you got this first rule here.
So you have to, again, apply one more condition here.
So you are so that results are still not all down here until this step you got a table, but from table,
your first results are matter to all the rules.
And now you're iterating through each and every rule using follow.
So in the first iteration, your search results will be on exactly this row.
Right.
And now inside, if you want to get the title of this movie, this is presenting Teletech.
So that means there are two digit tags inside Israel.
And so its results are now pointing to this one block only with this row.
So let's do one thing, because in this row, there are two theories, right?
I would say Rawda find all.
Diddies.
OK, and I would say.
Columns are rawData.
Right.
So this rawData variable is now storing these two values.
You see that how smartly we are drilling from our main hits.
Demel so content to finally to foster these two data.
OK.
It starts to be revealed right now.
Your goal is that you are actual title is present in second degree.
Right.
So first data can be accessed with zero index and second data will be accessed is using first index.
So once you start there, you can see the raw data if you want to get second so fast it in zero, you
can rotate out of one because the raw data will get stored in the list.
So when you say raw data often, so this you will have control on this second data.
Alsammarae, you finally leads to here.
From here, you have to do one more step to reach this point because here ventrilo title is present
for you to extract or scrap your data.
So from here to here, how would you go?
You can again say on this find off air so that it will reach this point or one shortcut you have.
If you think there is only one or two tags present inside your parent tag, you can simply access that
with a dot the tag, name it so that automatically this will start from here.
Raw Data one is here, right?
When you say data, it will try to find out the tag with the air inside this.
Right.
It will reach here.
This is a shortcut.
Apply this only when you have one or more bags.
But if you have so much of a statement that instead of dot the use dot, find out for you so that on
this road, that one it will search now with the dot, be it you are at this point rate success.
Ultimately you reach to this.
But what is your goal?
Your goal is to extract text which is present here, OK, to extract text, you can apply a method called
dart the text.
So this method will help you to get the text present on that anchor where you currently stored.
And here is where you are and when you extract will be output.
So now this loop repeats for each and every rule.
For the first iteration, it will do all these operations and give you a thriller and then the loop
right next time, because it have all that straight, it will be second data and it will again open
this graph to dot yet dot content and this will be printed.
So like that for each and every row it will loop and it will give you that title of.
The movie, so this where we are scrapping the entire page to get paid bills of all the TV shows displayed
on this Euron, and we are doing this using beautiful soap, right?
So let me run this full control shift, often on your page, out of my way to run any python fight and
let's see what happens.
You'll see that as we are printing get it printed all the titles on the beat.
Great.
So you also learned Hesterman because we are printing that also.
Let me come it and Branigin.
And this time you should only see titles, so all these are patents, so you have successfully written
a crafting Python script to retrieve all the titles of a bit, and you have not used any front test
automation frameworks like selenium to achieve this.
OK.
There's still a lot more scenarios out there, which we'll see in the next lecture.