All right, so this video is for Mac users to give a quick update that you need not set any by on part
or part in your system variables.
If you are working in Mac OS, when you install Python in your system, automatically, Mac will set
that in your part variable.
OK, so after you install Python successfully, just click on whatever it prompts, then it will tell
that Python is successfully installed there after you just need to type which python to let me maximize.
Right, you can see that it got in stark slash user slash been slashed.
So you already have by in your path without doing anything.
But do remember that you should have only one version of Python that is three plus anything after three.
If you have older version, which is less than three, then you need to be a little cautious because
if you have multiple versions of Python, you'll never know which was enough Python, your system is
being pointed to.
OK, so in that case, if you still have any older version, then which Python three, because the version
what you have downloaded is a greater than three, however.
So in my system, I just want to show you that I do also have previous version to that seven.
So that's the reason to know which version I have in my system.
I have added a word three so that Python triggered in start here, use the local bin.
So if you have only one version of Python, you really need not worry about that.
Number three, just like how we have seen in our previous video on Windows.
But if you think that if you have any older versions, then to know which version you have, just add
to this or that, it will show where exactly that is located.
But if you are still interested to know where exactly this python guard stored in your system.
This is the part, OK, go to library frameworks and here where you will see open the terminal.
Let's open the tunnel very quick.
And so to go to that part, I can simply say open.
Slash celebrity, let's go to that patency, and that will take you to this spot from here, library
frameworks, frameworks by standard framework versions and here where you will see the version, what
you got downloaded.
So this is exact part where exactly your python gets stored.
But you might be wondered that if this is the part why I am seeing here local been.
So basically we need executable files to set it in our system variables.
So automatically come all this bin folder is copied into this user user local folder.
We'll get this complete folder of executable files which are required to run Python are automatically
copied to the spot and your Mac mission will listen to this part by default.
OK, so that's the reason you need not write anything.
So if you still see any issues that Python is not being recognized, please let me know.
Post a question in the discussion board related to my configuration and I will help you.
Overall, I just want to tell you that you need not do anything.
And if you really need to know Python is stored, this is the location.
All right.
That's all I have.
Thank you.