All right, guys, let's get started.
So we have successfully completed the first of two steps launching in an instant and update configurations
to accept, as I said, the connection.
And now third one is bellbottom because, as I said, connection.
So what is this about is one Python library which will help you to connect remotely to another server.
OK, so let's install this level.
So using this library, we will be able to communicate with our Linux server.
So we will go back to our browser and then say, but let me go install Python.
So this is their official website.
Or you can go to the Python Library and just provide the install paramedical from here, I will go back
to our ED.
And from terminal.
But installed by Michael.
Right.
So you can go to their official website and understand about it.
So this is a library for making such connections.
That's what I tell you, right.
All right.
So let's see what happens.
It is installing.
We are almost there.
OK, successfully installed, Greg, so I will now create a new five.
And so it's connect demo.
It's very simple, yes.
So here onwards, it's very easy to understand.
OK, now you need to import paramedical, this is the library.
So from here, you can import that as one variable by calling paramedical, right?
So this is the more lamebrained.
DARD, you see that you got all the matters here, SSX claimed so fast, you have to tell to your library
that I have to make a sausage connection.
So there are different protocol connections are there?
In our case, we just need such a line.
So let's select that.
New capital as Glenn, this one.
So it will create one stream of connection so that you can store that in one variable.
OK, next, you can directly start connection because you have enabled this glass metal, right, with
this object.
So as I said, Dart and there is a method called connect, that's all.
So this expects for parameters, IP address, board member, user name, password, and that's all you
will be connected to your bottleneck server.
It's very easy.
You can all do this with one single method called Connect.
OK, and here you can start giving your all details, but I would prefer you to in properties that I
and I find and you can say you are Lennix or just so.
And host equals to IP address of that host.
So where do you get that?
There are multiple ways to figure out that you can go to your console and for that selected instance
here where you will find it.
Come back and.
Will, it's not required if united in an effort both so by default, all this stuff will start in 2022.
Wendy, to put no user name, we have created one user named ADC to hyphen user that comes by default.
And the password we have set in the last lecture to the same you see to and it as a password.
Awesome.
So these are the details needed because our server is this IP address.
It is not my idea to run for one night free and we have given username password to login and all configurations
we already done in our previous list.
So now let's come back.
Suppost equals two and we should drive it from our config properties.
Right.
I think there is a way we did already the shortcut.
So I will simply import these configurations, because the way to get config method is present.
So that way we can use that so from configurations, imports start so that all methods will be imported.
So this is present in utilities, right?
Utilities start.
Now, host equals two, you can basically call this matter just like how we have given get config user
password.
I think I can use this.
All right, so it's a just a variable, so you need not give in courts, so this is a use name and get
config this time we were getting it from Sarovar S..
Server and user name here.
So this is how you have to drive it.
And next is a bus for.
And will the courts, at least we have given in court because we are storing that into the dictionary.
So I think that's the right word here.
Yeah, next port, no coast to more details.
So we have already closed here.
See, now there are multiple properties are post in the in this page here.
We have Woolston here also.
We have but based upon the sections we are differentiating.
OK, so.
Host, where did we go, did we delay that?
OK.
So one last one we have is a support, No.
I will call this.
All right, good.
So username, password, all the four already.
Now let's send it in to the Connect method.
OK, so this method first accepts Hosta parameter and next board number and next username and password.
So all the details will be used now to connect to the line server.
But one more step you have to add here.
Basically, it will try to authenticate with public and private keys so we don't have public key of
that server.
So you can suppress that check by writing one step.
Let me read it here.
So this is presenting their official documentation.
It clearly says that set the missing key policy AHTO.
And so by default at runtime, Python will generate one public key and it will added, OK, you need
not do anything from your code, so make sure you add the step.
If not, you might run into some keys related a.
Great.
So if you're not aware of how we have to go parameters, you can just, as I said, start Ganek and
here you see you have a description how you can connect.