All right, so if you don't want to write this in multiple lines, you can all just write it in one
single line.
So once you know this is dictionary and study, once you know this is a list and why do we need to store
it in separate variable and call zero index?
You can call it directly zero zero and that's it.
You can get rid of all these steps.
Isn't it also the same output?
OK, so let me write it in the bottom and show you you can skip all these lengths.
I'm commenting it out.
So.
If I simply call this, this will return the list and in the list I want zero index.
So once you get familiarized with all the data types, then you can directly use like this.
But if you are confused, then step by step, how I have done in my previous lecture, take into one
variable and finally decoded.
You see that it's still OK now this is one design, but in most of times you will not have this design
like this.
You will have this in the file.
OK, so now what I am doing, I have my design file here.
I copied the content in my design firm and stored it as a string in one variable rate.
This is one approach of passing.
What if you have this in file with you externally in your system and Python should automatically open
you file, extract the content out of it and then pass it?
OK, so that would be also one of the scenario, right?
Most of them will have a face and it might not be ideal to copy here every day.
It's it's referred, but it's the government that when you have a smaller design with this static.
So now to extract files and pass it, there is another method in Python so far that I would go back
to one of my days and file.
Yeah, so this is the DNA file and this is a little complex.
And I learned first of all, copy this into the DNA, a for clear visibility.
All right, so this is the distance and you see that key Mustafah, let's see, what are the keys?
Oh, there are only two keys.
Technically, when you convert that's in the dictionary because that's where we can do it.
Right, using method.
And ideally, you have only two keys and the value of our stickies, again, dignity by seeing this
Kalume.
This, as you can understand that there is one more dictionary, but value of this courses squared bracket,
that means the list.
OK, so like this step by step, you can be good, you can minimize it and understand what's happening
inside it.
OK, all right.
So I have this in external file location, Goldstar Jason and this is my Pottsy users on our document.
So I click I can copy the part from here.
Full file to clipboard.
Good.
So I will go back to my editor.
And this time our goal is to open the file and then pass it.
We don't want to deliberately mention everything here.
Bus content present in decent flight to remember the difference in the previously with part of the content
present in decent strength and now five.
First of all, you have to open that file, right?
So basically Baynton has to open the file and read the content.
So as we discussed in our previous sections, so that's what I say.
I always refer to watch my python basics, because if you skip those section videos, then you may not
be understanding what I am talking now because I already took some good amount of time to understand
those.
So there is one lecture I explained how to read and write files using Python.
OK, we are going to use the same concept here.
So our first goal is to open the file and read so far that there is a very important you can open the
file with this method open and you have to give the part of your file.
Right, soccer star, Jason, so you can give the courts.
So this is the part where my desk and files do it and I want to open this so I have an open method as
let's give any object if.
Five.
Now, so this F object have the ability to read your and file because you have opened it and read more.
So if you don't mention any parameter by default, this will open and read more.
If you want to write it, you have to give it another parameter called WQ, which we will see in our
next letters.
OK, so next step, Jason Dot, you see that there are two methods available here.
Lourdes is what we have seen in our previous letter.
Lourdes will take a string as an argument.
But in our case this time, we don't have this string.
We have file object.
OK, so our final object then is another method in Python to use, which is the Lord Lord.
And you have to simply pass your file object because this object have permission to open you up a decent
file.
OK, so then it will open and Lord Method will read all the content accessed by this object.
So you will again get all over this file content now in the dictionary.
So I'm just storing that into another variable.
OK, so this data available is nothing but dictionary again, just like how you have started into one
variable here.
Also we are studying in data.
Right now, once you get that into the dictionary, let's bring this just to make sure you get a dictionary
back or not, and I would also print tape so that you will know the written type.
What you have is a dictionary.
So control shift, if then you can just right click and sarandos this and passing anything is fine.
You see that last two lines.
This is dictionary and everything you have here.
In this study for the same reason, but now you can access with your dictionary methods.
OK, now let's go back to our ED.
As I told you, I'll treat it as a dictionary.
So now your goal is to print.
The second course course.
OK, so this is the real question.
I have given you the system and I have asked you to bring a second class of at the academy.
What is the second class?
So basically, if you scroll down, these are the courses in the design file.
And this is the first class, right?
Yeah, this is the first class and this is a second class.
So you have to print Cyprus in your output.
And the next requirement is that you have to print a website now, which is set up, which would be
a miracle.
OK, so these two you have to do now, let's pass them carefully.
Now, first, we have to get second class status, right?
So minimize them to understand the hierarchy.
So basically when you minimize them.
First of all, this is a dictionary, however, and there are two items.
So my actual title is present in this crate, so I will start from basic first at data to access the
value of key.
I can use courses because this is the key which will help you to access like.
So now if I print this, it will print all the.
Three.
Complete list.
Basically, this is the list.
OK, so this dictionary is holding the list.
Right now, let's spread this.
OK, so this is how it retained me.
So basically it retains the value of this courses, which is nothing but list.
So once you understand this is the list and in the list there are three items or square bracket.
And this is the first item and this is the second item of the list and this is the third item of the
list.
But interesting thing here is first item in the list is what is that string?
No, if you see on my previous example, this is also a list like this is on the list, but items in
the list are simple strings here.
So you will just access the width of the zero index otherwise written.
But here in my zeroth index, it's not string.
There is one more dictionary present in the list.
Well, this is complicated, but that's fine.
Right?
So in the zeroth item, one dictionary is present in the first item and other dictionaries present.
So our goal is to print the second item.
So that means the next in the first index, because index I start from zero.
OK, so that means in this dictionary we have to as a list, we have to access first item so that we
can will come here so it successfully access to this.
OK, now when you print this, it will just return the second item, which is a dictionary.
So dictionary will be one output now because you are accessing the second element.
Let's see.
You see that perfectly dictionary is written.
OK, now let's create this other dictionary and this dictionary.
If you want to get title, how would you access it?
So initially, this is dictionary like data.
And if you want to access the key data, of course, a civil right now, in our case, this whole is
a dictionary.
And if you want to access a lot of it, you can simply say them and that's it.
And we understand this will return.
OK, so that's how step by step you have to proceed.
So once you see the Decem, you have to scan in your mind about what all these like what is the last
what is a dictionary and then start passing from the base.
And it would be easy for you to pass any Jason right now.
This is very complex.
Some days you'll see that there are mysteries inside it, but they have simply passed it and extracted
the whatever item you want with the concept of list and andexanet is OK.
And next, our next goal is to access this website.
OK, so how do you access the academic outcome again?
Now minimize everything.
Let's start from the basics again and our website details are present inside of this Plastiki item of
big study.
Right.
So this is the parent, the extended data support data.
This time you have to go inside dashboard.
So dashboard awesome.
And here where you can access the item.
So when you do this, then you will get the output.
What do you get the output, so output also here is the dictionary, OK, so key is that dashboard and
value this time is returning one more extended.
This is not list.
You see that calibrations are there.
Right?
So output is also on because they can form print dictionary and you can also print the type of this.
So.
You will now understand that our put.
OK, so you see that in the dictionary and this is what you present.
So in my dictionary, if I want to access website key value, it's simple, you know.
Right.
You just need to access the key website.
So given column.
Svetlana Binsted.
Right, so inside this loops what happened.
Oh, that's right.
So let me complete website.
So now when you bring this, bring our Web site me.
So that Travelocity Economy.com.
So this is how you can access any and it meant you knew about this.
And so the difference between the previous example and this is in previous example, we have used a
string and here we have a file and we have successfully done that.
And that's how you can pick any complex and whatever you have and use the concepts.
What I have told in these two lectures, and you can just do it on the fly.
All right.
So that's pretty much a worthless lecture.
Guys, thank you.