Welcome back.
Now let us see how can we write back to see as we file and you need to open that file again, but this
time as Whitemoor more so you have already have the syntax to open the file.
Right.
So by default, if you don't provide any argument, it opens in, read more.
But if you want to write it, you have to open and write more.
But problem here is when you put the value that will scrap and erase all the existing content and write
freshly.
OK, so that is one scenario.
But in our case, let's have it use case that it should add another rule.
Basically, it should happen to the existing data.
It should not scrap the already data we just presented so far that you have to have a flat quality which
stands for APPEND.
OK, so the file you can see right file, this is an object reference, so then it will be available
to.
Right.
OK, so there is a system, a package between important.
Right in that there is one more method called write the simple dice, that's all.
So there is nothing science here.
So Python again, I stress Python is very, very easy.
If I take a mouse to explain in Java or C shop, a JavaScript, I can take only two hours to explain
that python.
OK, so that's the proof.
Take out my other courses in Java and to show how to read from CSC files are.
Except that is a lot of things are involved, but in Python it's very easy.
So right now is a matter and why do you want to write so basically.
You have to write into this file, right?
OK, so.
Then you can throw it into one object or variable rate of variable, so this variable is now having
permission to write because we have gained permission by clearly saying that.
Right, right.
There is a method which will help to tell on which file we have to write.
Yes, we have a reference to the right object and right dot.
Right wrote.
Michelle.
Our position is not coming, but this is the matter which will help you to add neutral, OK, you can
either directly write it here, right or wrong, but I'm just taking that into one variable by breaking
into two legs.
OK, so that's what you need to do, right?
You have to add neutral.
But if you remember how the roll is being added or how the law is being read using this iest reader
object.
OK, so we are we have written as a list of Ahmat.
Right.
If you remember, we got all this wrong in the list of Arment.
So even to write the new rule, you should make sure you send that Murong in the list of Ahmat only
now if I want to give new list, another rule.
So let me add that.
Bob and his status is also projected that road I'm sending as a list, that's how this writer accepts
and reading also that gives us back in list only.
So everyone now should be treated as the list in CFB standards.
That's all I know when you run this, you will see new law added into your CSP file.
OK.
There is nothing logic behind that.
It's all about having writers matter.
And on that object, you will have another matter called Lytro and send all the list.
Now, run this program and we will see what happens of it failed because permission or permission denied
to access.
Interesting.
Where did I place this file to get this?
Oh, it's because this file isn't already open more so when you want to write it back, make sure you
close all the CSP files where you want to write it back.
So close this Excel document, because that is stopping us to write into that.
So we got into.
So as I closed now, we should not run into any permanent denial errors.
So let me run this file again.
OK, so this time I don't see any error, so let's see if that new rule is added or not, so you can
simply go it alone and NSV and here you go, Bob rejected.
You see, that new rule is added because we are adding it from here and you can start writing a number
of rules by simply giving this matter again and again.
Like write one more rule with one more debate.
All right.
So that's how you can read and write in to see us.
So with this knowledge, let's switch back to the associates connection.
So this is one of the important topic in backend automation.
So from our Python code, we should be able to connect to another Linux server and execute the commands
in that Linux server from our local mission, Python code.
OK, so we will see how to do all this and then we will bring this concept again, because there is
one batch file which generates CSFI file and we should be able to run that batch file in Linux from
our Python code and the parts that say, yes, we fight.
OK, it will be very interesting and of course, easy as it should.
So we'll start that from our next section.
Thank you.