OK, so in this short lecture, let us try to understand what is redirection and payment and how to
use that concept in your API testing.
So here, when you actually hit this city Economy.com so fast, it will hit.
It will go to one wall from that you are in it will redirect to this of a bit.
OK, it's not directly hitting Rovelstad at the academy dot com.
So before that, there is one redirection happening.
So then there is the redirection happens from one quarter to another.
You are in your response fast will show three, not two.
And then so because it is frustrating when you are in and then it is redirecting to this Web page.
So after learning this Web page only, you will get a response back.
Right.
So then you will see 200 or so.
But before that I am making one redirection with the NewLink.
So if there is any redirection for your API calls, then you will not directly see 200.
You will first see three, not two straight EZCORP because of redirection.
And then after loading actually what you will see 200.
But in the output when you set up on Star Status Code, you will see the latest and the final status
code, what it reported, but it will not show all the history.
So you can still get the history.
And if you in the response, if you a response star, that is a third call history.
So if you use history, then it will tell you if there are any redirections for forever.
And point what you have called.
OK, let's see this.
So redirection is very common in the waters, if they want to have some security implementation or anything,
they'll just go on this redirections.
Yeah, in this case, redirections three.
Not so any state ascorbic starts with 300 will be used as a redirection.
So here it's a three, not one, which is initially happening.
OK, this is the History Channel for us.
And then it is loading the actual euro and Gambir 200.
So as I told explicitly, it will not show you.
But if you see the history, it will show that there is a redirection here.
So if you don't want to redirect, so let's say this is the how you are functionality is currently working
and then our developer bought a new project and they was told that you should not redirect from another
water to this page going directly to should be Economy.com and delete all redirections because they
have implemented all security directly in this Web page only.
So they would ask you to delete all redirections.
So how would you take that?
Because when your response starts to scored, even when there is a redirection, you are getting 200.
So after they fix this issue, still you get 200.
So one way of seeing the history, OK, and by saying the history, you will verify whether three,
not one, is present or not.
Based upon that, you decide.
Another way is that there is one attribute you can pass and you've got to get call, which is a low
redirects if you set it to false.
OK, so if you said this, attribute a redirect to funds, so it will just stop after it receives Fuster
status.
So in our case it will just stop at three zero one.
It will not do any redirection, because we are saying that while you think this request, if there
is redirections stopping.
OK, so by default, it is redirecting from 300 to 200, but in our case, our response will stop here
because we are not allowed to redirect.
So if the developer fixed it, when you give this attribute, it should directly show 200 because we
are doing this.
So now let's see what is the output we get?
OK.
Let me comment this response, our history.
I'm just giving this data earlier when I tried this without redirection, false.
We got 200.
Right.
Let me try this again.
And you see now you got this little one only there is not one right here because we are stopping the
election to force.
So after developing to fix the bulk of redirection, we are expecting now 200 directly.
If you still see that in action, you can feel it by riding a dinosaur equals two three zero one, which
we already seen having assertions in my previous lectures.
So this way you can test the direction for your other apes using a low redirects attribute next.
So once you hit the request.
Let's say it takes one or two seconds to get a response back, but ideally your response variable will
not wait once this hit and let's say it takes two seconds to get a response.
So you will get a blank object in the response because you never told do your request get going to wait
for two seconds for response and this will not have any idea of waiting.
Right.
So they know what they have done.
So we got an instant response.
So we did not feel the heat of waiting synchronization.
But if you hit an end points which have heavy load in realtime e-commerce, so the response might be
delayed two or three seconds.
So you have to give some mechanism, do your best to wait until three seconds and then get a response.
OK, so to give that weight.
Or you can write back here.
So there isn't another attribute called timeout.
OK, payment equals two can give seconds.
Let's let me get one second.
So basically this will wait one second and then it will take the response back, OK?
This is very important, guys.
If you're working as I don't have a lot of real time projects, you might get a response back within
three or four seconds and you respond very well picking before that and you won't see proper history
or proper response back that's there.
You no waiting issues comes over so that you can provide payment.
So this is a tribute and give the number of seconds you want to wait and then it will wait and then
grab the correct response.
OK, this will come very handy while testing.
OK, so it will not have any impact, you can run a game.
You see that just waited one second and grabbed the response.
OK, so this is how we can work with time up and redirects in your method.
We'll continue with another topic in the next lecture.
Thank you.