Welcome back.
So now you can also check the status of your response, so in the last lecture, we have seen how to
retrieve the decent response and pass it right.
Similarly, if you want to see the status, call what your surveys have written, then it's very simple.
You can still use this response.
Object response, star status code.
Right.
So this will give you your response status quo.
So this will help you to actually check if it has gotten successfully or not.
Basically, people will have a solution for this in testing.
So first, let's try to see what is the status quo.
We are getting the output.
You see, it's 200.
So what you can do is set response status score equals to 200.
So this way, if something goes wrong, you will get another status called apart from two hundred and
you can report failure.
OK, and you can also monitor headers of your response like Wartell.
And as you receive with your response, let's see.
It's again same object response.
Dart Pelops.
And all this we singing Postman Man, will you see that status, 200 similar thing we have seen with
this star status today and the head of the line of heroes present here.
Right.
So all these heroes now we can access.
That's does matter with this object, subtrend response, Darksiders.
You see that all these are headers, so one interesting thing here is that these headers are written
as a dictionary.
So my goal is to verify that the header of what is that content type is application jassam or not.
So that is my goal of verification.
So this is the content type header, right?
So in postwoman also, you have that.
So most of the times you might be asked to verify if content type what you have received is just an
opinion, right?
So this is the content type.
Now, let's for the check point and A to validate.
So when you do respond to start headers, it received the complete dictionary.
Right.
So in that if you want to access only content type, you know how easy it is.
So basically the respon start headers is a dictionary in that dictionary.
Key value is content type.
OK, content so equal, you can have this.
Right, and then give an assessment.
So basically it will extract that value and come past with this, what matters then?
Our test will pass.
Let's.
But that is an item if you're trying to ride a camel here and then from here, you will definitely see
another, because that is a deviation.
You see that that is an assertion at all.
So this is how you can validate not only response distance, but also that heads and state escorts.
OK.
Similarly, you can do for as assessment, but as one start, you will get cookies, OK, you can retrieve
the cookies and that will also bring the dictionary and use this key value pair to retrieve any response
cookie you need.
Great.
So this is one kind of validations next.
So let's do one logical validation here.
Now, I would try to get results.
Get out there, and I would just said.
Let's see how many results we get.
OK, so I have a bunch of results here.
So my goal here is to retrieve the ISBN with the value of Djihad Cissie.
So I would write the.
Comments here, so retrieve the book details
with ISBN.
So how do you get that?
So once you get that response, you will obviously see a lot of books with that order when you buy property.
So now your goal is to pass this response either through each and every book and see if the ISBN name
is matching with or whatever you want.
Or if there is a match, then you have to return that whole book list.
OK, for that, first of all, we will take this complete response and we would put in our Jessan Ed.
So this way we will Vitalogy two percent.
OK, so first of all, this isn't list, right?
So, however, we can get the complete list details here.
So when you do response to our Jason, you have the complete list here.
OK, so now basically you have to either read through each and every element in this list, OK, in
this square bracket list.
This is one element.
This is another element, and this is another element.
So it looks like simple for loop to isolate each and every element of the list.
And when we access that iteration for that specific list, we will grab the ISBN name and see if that
matches with our requirement.
It's very simple.
Yes, let's do that.
So how do I direct and.
You already know that we saw in our previous lecture, so syntax that is for a new variable name.
Let's take a look in listing it.
What is your list?
This is the list right here where you will get your complete response list.
Right.
So now when you print book, it will print each and every item in that list for every iteration of the
book.
How in the first iteration, this book, how access to this first item and when you run for second,
third loop, your book have access to the second Bigum.
Right.
So when we are accessing that each and every item in the list, our goal here is to see if book.
That means that particular item in that item, this is each item is no dictionary.
Right.
So then list access to each item in every iteration.
What is the data type of that item?
Let's first see that type of book.
And that's printed.
Every item in that list is nothing but a dictionary, you'll see that every item.
Well, it says there's a dictionary, right?
Then of course the dictionary and you want to do is to be a it should be simple, right?
Biosphere.
OK, so it'll just keep if condition if ISBN equals two or hit hits, right.
So if this matches, then our goal is to read the complete book details, OK, you can then say for
the book.
OK, so basically, you don't want to see all the details, your goal here is to get only the book details,
OK, and let's say there is one test case where you want to compare that whatever book you got on the
head, CISPA, that should be equal to your expected book.
OK, so this is the actual received from the response for Arjay Head, S.C..
I am speaking now.
Let's build our expected book.
Come out of this look because if you write here, this will be part of your condition.
Right?
And if you write, it will be part of for loop.
So come to the first point so that you will be out of this complete block and define your expected book.
Let's have another dictionary so that the actual whatever you really all should be equal to the expected
book, what you are expecting.
So there is that already had secret.
Yeah, here, so let me copy this dictionary.
This is what we are expecting.
OK, simple, and this is what you get.
Let's write a actual book.
You see that the book, whatever it is based upon condition of that, is, that's what we need, right?
OK, so how you can compare an actual book is one dictionary you have expected.
Book is one dictionary you have.
So basically you can compare two dictionaries.
I told you it's very simple and you need to simply use the actual book equals two expected book.
And that said, have an assertion and if something goes wrong, your test will fail.
OK, let's run this program.
Awesome, there's something gone.
Let's try to understand this, OK, line 27, it clearly says Assertion do not match.
Let's try to read this dictionary and see where it went wrong.
So like this, you should be OK.
OK, so you printed the actual book, right?
Actual book is printed with book name, Lenape Automation, ISBN, IAL.
Everything looks good, but when you try to compare it shows an assertion.
What would be the error?
Any guesses?
So I want you to guess this so carefully, observe this logic and you will figure out what is the error
here.
So if not, I can show you in the next lecture.
But again, I'm I'm just giving you a hint that is something wrong.
And the if condition here, that's fine.
We are getting a failure.
OK, so before you print.
I try to bring to this actual book an expected book before this assassination and see what will be different.
So try to on a and then we will see this in the next lecture.
Thank you.