All right, so now to hit our execute any comedy so fast, you have to create Calzada object.
So using we already have a connection object.
So connection dot that is another matter called Castle.
So basically this method will help you to form a streamlined connection to talk to the database tables.
So here you establish the connection.
OK, so draw that connection.
You have to send queries and get the results back.
Right.
So the castle object will help you to form a stream between your python and your sequel database draw
connection object.
So you have to mandatorily first create that streamline between your python and the database using this
custom method.
And you can get that into another variable, the object, what you get from here.
All right.
So as you have fun, extremely streamlined with that database now using this segment, then you can
execute your queries.
Now, for example, I want to run this query and I want to know how the results are displayed.
OK, so select this and consult dart execute.
You see that this is the method which will help you to execute any queries on the database which you
got connected.
OK, so instead of this just passed the query, no need of giving semicolon and that's it.
So that will execute query.
Right.
And the results will be read to the right.
So once you run this, you will get the results.
All the results will present in that streamlined Kazar object to fit results from this streamlined Calzada
object.
You have a method called Casser Dart Fetch.
You see that it's all self explanatory when you say it fits all, it will fit all the rules written
by that table.
And when you say Freda's one, this will return the first row written by the team.
OK, now let's start with the first.
So when you run this query, total phytoestrogen.
So when you say Fêtes one, this will simply give the first record return.
So let's throw it into one variable and this is the rule.
Now we have in our hands, so let's bring this through and see what it is showing up.
OK.
Let me run this control plosive this after.
Perfect, you'll see that it has in selenium and the date, so because it's the date objects, all you
have got like this and 120 and Africa, the first Vegard is successfully retrieved.
Right.
So if you observe carefully.
Death row is nothing but Apple.
OK, it's not a square brackets here.
So when you have like this and you have brackets like this, that's the list.
Right.
But this time you have something like this.
So that means it's Apple.
It's an audition for Apple.
OK, it's still the same.
If you want to access any elements from the list, that double the mechanism is still the same.
Now in you at Apple, if you are interested to know what is the location of the first of the card reader.
OK, so how do you do that?
As you understand, this is the table so you can simply throw off.
Zero, one, two, three, starting next week, you can settle off three, OK, and print it and this
will print you the.
Third index, which is nothing but Africa.
We see that, so basically, once you get that record, you can access the each and every element of
that role with the help of index.
So you just need to understand what is the return type.
OK, so once you understand it and so you should figure out how you should pass it.
If it is a dictionary, that is the one way to handle it.
If the list are double, you can just give the index for the dictionary will go value.
OK, so one thing you should understand here is that sequel database results are written in form of
apples now.
So now you understood how to read The Faster the car and you also understood from the fossil record,
if you want to retrieve this particular column value, that also you can do with that Semtex.
What next?
So let's try to fix all the records system, concertante fetch all.
And I would say all.
And let's bring all these.
You see that it has printed all the rules, but all the rules are present in the list.
Because the notation is different here in the list, there are apples.
So that means it written a list of apples.
OK.
When you ask for a single roll, it just gave you a single example.
But when you ask for it all, so all the staples are wrapped up in one list.
So now if you want to access the second drawer, OK, so in the list added to the list, you can set
all of one.
So that second row will be.
This is nothing but second table, so this is how you can play with the results.
OK, you want overall goal is to access any data, right?
So now with this steps, you are able to access all the records, not only accessing all the records
from all the records, you should be able to travel and pass each individual value by giving index this
nice.
But one thing, if you absol selenium is the fitter faster.
Right?
And when you ask for it on, it started from Secondo, not from the festival.
You see that it started from protractive ytterbium and web services.
Daym totally for results are written.
But he had to fight.
So why.
So when you say Sadaat fits one forecaster, control is here first, right, and now when you subfertile,
it will fit all the remaining records.
So it starts from where your control is presently there from there, if you will recall this now when
you go on the third one and from here, if you're safe at all, it will just return next to do OK.
So you have got to run the single roll, right?
And when you repeat this step one more time, the control will immediately go to the next door whenever
you call Fitzsimon, every time it moves to the next stop.
Right.
So from right now, you are here step number 11.
And from that step, you call the feds.
All right.
So it will fix the remaining three, but not again all.
So now run this again so you will not see protractive this time.
Let's see.
You see that it started from Avium.
OK, so do remember that.
So if you want to simplify it, all of them don't use this one method, OK?
Right.
So let's do one program here.
So your goal is to fit all the records of the customer and some of that amount of using Python.
You should be able to hit the query, get all the results and some one point forty five and give that
total.
So that's remarkable.
So you can do this with your query database query as well.
You can use aggregate functions of select some of amount which will simply give you the thumb.
But for practice and to get you some handson, let's do it from above the python code.
OK, we'll see that in our next lecture.
Thank you.