OK, so now let's bring Daccord from.
Our previous example.
So right now we are trying to add the book, so I guess this is the data related to adding book.
So let's carefully copy that and bring back to our definition files.
So now let's partition that code into different methods here.
OK, so the callback we wrote accomplishes all these three methods, right?
Because we have book details we executed and we also verified selectively pasted here once.
So let's quickly rearrange this properly.
So when we execute and a post-paid method executes this one.
Right.
So we are executing Polster method to get that response right.
So this step should go to that this folder.
And next, once you execute, you want to check whether the book is successfully added and you want
to book idea.
So let's assume that you want to get a book idea.
So once again, the response, everything else should be validated after you hit that request.
So let's not let's print here.
That's fine.
And let's not have this for now.
So how would you take a look is successfully added so you can verify a message that is an assertion
right to check book is successfully added because in response you get that message.
So let's have that assertion here.
So assert.
The response is what we got in that, let's verify what message.
So they should actually tell book is successfully added, so let success.
So this is the message it will take in response.
Now, if you have carefully observed that a lot of us here, let's try to fix all of them.
So now what we did is we have partition and divided code based upon the what we need here.
OK, so book verification code is here, execution codes here and all the inputs, the book details
we are storing in a variable rate header, Siwa and everything that is not required because we are not
going to be called here.
OK, so firstly, we can import this request so that Aregawi, why No one and next get config.
So if you remember this, get config, all these we are getting from these files.
OK, so let's also import these files into our definition.
So one thing you have to observe 70 percent of frame work related things we have already done under
previous section.
OK, so if you carefully observe we have utility's files and we store resources, we stored configurations.
And, you know, the data is not hardcoded here.
It is coming from D'Arte and they file like which endpoint you need.
And for resources you are getting from class payloaders constructing from pillar glasses, everything
is almost 70 percent of framework best practices.
We have already implemented in the previous sections the only one new thing, what we brought here is
fronton interface just like this.
OK, so we have added reedited flavor in this section so that our frontrunning in the first time sort
a behavior driven style, but back in the utilities, configurations, properties, resources, everything
we already made.
So that's why this section looks so simple for us, because the real core code is already ready.
We just need to partition that by creating one feature file and mapping the two step definitions are
step implementations, that's all.
OK, so now we'll see here the get config, everything else that's gone because we imported those packages.
So we are nicely bringing this end point from a centralized global file and add resources from there.
Great.
You all that is good.
What next?
So there is another here which you have to fix now you are.
So earlier we did not get that error because we have written everything as a single file.
So if you stored it in you are available, you can access here.
But in your step definition file the scope of this, you are the method variable will be inside this
matter only because if you close this, you see that variables are getting closed.
So that means the scope of this variable is inside this method only.
So that's why this method is not able to understand.
What is this you wanted?
Similarly, you got a response you stored in the response variable.
And now when you try to extract Jason from that response in the metro, new context isn't because scope
of that response variable lyson Duckmanton only.
Right.
So how do you fix that?
So he had a bit of context comes into the picture.
So context is one variable which will be activated in the future level or in the scenario level.
So when you run this entire future five on a single scenario, any time when you start planning one
variable context will be assigned to your total execution.
OK, so that variable will be sent to all your methods.
So in this variable context variable, in this context, you will actually have this as a property.
You will store this.
You are own property in this variable.
OK, let's do like this context that you are.
So if you do like this, we are sending a property of you all to this context object.
OK, so you can call it as a variable or object.
So basically we are sending a new property to this object right now as this context is global.
And I told you.
Right it will be.
Activated when you start running this entire future scenario and it will be ended only when you are
going to do a session, so this session context object will be available to all Democrats until your
program of execution is done.
So here it is available now.
But how to retrieve that?
You want to you can simply retrieve it by calling on to dark.
You are perfect.
You see that error is gone.
So here as our current, what we are doing to share the variables between a different astep implementation
methods, we are relying on context because context is global.
So you are assigning a new property of your order to this object and using that property anywhere,
because context looks every bit OK, that that's how we manage variables, objects, anything, and
shared across different methods.
In reality, we have a framework.
OK, that's an important point.
OK, so we have a role here Aspell.
Because in this matter, the book details which needs to be added, so we got you all we got ahead of
us also let's place like this context to not hate us.
OK, now you can use this context started us.
In your execution at the.
Also, this looks super clean now and response, one last thing and for this context object, let's
also assign and response property so you can reuse it wherever you want.
Cool, I guess all the errors are resolved.
Everything looks good now, OK, so if you go back to Earth a fine, this is exactly what it is doing.
So given the details, let's see.
Let's go to here.
Yeah, these are the details.
You have everything here.
Nice and.
Let's do one thing, this ad hoc payroll also, so this isn't over in detail, right?
Let's have all the details here.
So let's confine this executable post matter only for execution.
So I don't think I'll copy this iron book payload and write it here context and create a new property
payload.
It will stop and you will.
Let's get some random variables so that it will be unique.
And it creates for us the context at payload.
And you can reuse it here instead of having it here.
You can see there's an equal stuff on the stock.
Baylor right now.
This way you have segregated that in a very nice way so that all the details, Baylor headers, everything,
what all you need for your API Hick's, everything will be executed in the step.
OK, so if someone wants to know what exactly this step is doing, they can simply control press control
and select this so that they get here and see what's happening and next when we execute Adbul.
Right.
So, yeah, this is what it's happening.
We are executing post matter and the last one is verified.
Then book is successfully added and we have validation assumption to see if book is successfully added.
All right.
So let's run this test again and see if that's really adding a book or not.
OK, again, so if you want to run this entire future of this folder, you can simply say here, but
if you are interested only to run one single feature file instead of running all, so then you can give
the future filename.
So right now there is only one feature file here.
So by default, even if you give this only one builder, but you can say like this also future slash
the folder because you are already in project level, right.
In that project level field of slash.
Give you a feature name.
It's a book.
A dark future, OK, and this is how you can run the one single feature file.
What you need here by default, human last, see the logs in the output if you want to see the logs
in the output when you want to be here.
When I say logs.
So here you are printing mcadie all these, right.
So those will be suppressed by default.
You can make them not suppressed by giving this flag no capture so that we behave will not capture and
storage in any file.
It will simply show for you in the console output.
Right.
So syntax here, right here is a file you want to run and lock up the flag to see output.
If you want to run, all of these files simply won't be here.
Don't give anything.
All right, let's run this.
OK, so you see that one filter passed, that means one filter, the interest rate is color feature
in that there is only one scenario.
So it's this one scenario is passed and then there are three steps given when then three steps past.
When we say three steps past, that means the cord, which is tied up to these three steps past without
any issues.
OK, so if you scroll up, you can see the logs message successfully added.
And this is the book we are printing in the output.
Awesome.
So we have successfully converted our python test to be dedi behav framework.
OK, so same test.
We are now able to write with nice user interface by connecting with the star definition.
One great thing here is that our work became easy because in the last election itself we have done a
lot of framework optimizations.
OK, so if you say utilities, we have resources to collect all the resources, class files, properties
where it takes the detailed configurations, everything we have done.
So that's why our code is easily migrated now to build a cucumber style.
OK, let's continue our discussion in the next election.
Thank you.