Welcome, guys.
Let us try to solve one more tricky scenario here.
Let's say I want to get the price of Arpit, OK, so there is a course called RPI and I want to get
that title.
I just want to get the price of that goes.
But the problem here is this goes Makumbe in the third place or second place or first place again.
Right now I have to go to three courses here and it's on the third place.
So tomorrow if I do another course and alphabetic order may change and it might come on any place.
So I'm not sure where exactly this title comes in, this causus list.
So basically I want to get the price of this title.
So that's my overall goal.
And you should not go buy indexes because in the previous session we went through indexing of one.
But let's assume that order is not guaranteed and you may get any order based upon new courses addition
after that.
So now how would you write a logic which will give you the price?
Of course.
OK, right.
Let's all this.
Again, it's very simple.
Let's throw the question looks complex.
And that's what beauty pythonesque whatever.
B the challenge question you have, the answer would be is in Python.
That's why I really love this language.
OK.
Again, let's stick to our basics.
That's all I can tell you every time.
So first of all, our goal is to extract this causus right.
Let's do that.
And you know how to get that, because you already took that into a dictionary.
And dictionary, of course, will give you that list, isn't it?
Because the output of this is a list.
So you can write one simple step data coarsest, which will give you the list.
That's fine.
No issues with that.
OK, so there is one called indentation as.
Please do remember, you are opening the file and reading it, right.
So the next line, whatever you write, should come exactly with a tap space here.
If you started from the beginning, then this matter will be independent of this file.
Object, OK?
So you will run into a so-called indentation matters, so do one tap and you will be exactly looting
their.
As we are working on this fire as a fire object, the scope of this object will light only when you
are inside of this.
So if you are inside, you should be exactly with this step.
If you come and write it on the first line, then it will read that you are outside and the object will
not be applicable to this.
If it's not applicable, then you can't work.
But in this case, I don't think we really require, isn't it?
We are not working with any object because we already have a data file here.
OK, so we are just reusing.
So it's up to you.
You can right from the start of the beginning.
That doesn't matter, at least for this case.
OK, so this returns what again, I want to see what it returns.
Because I just access to my dictionary.
OK, I saw the list, so what can we do once we understand this is list?
I basically want to iterate over each and every element of my list and to see if title is Arpit or not.
That's my goal.
So basically in the list, there are totally three items, right?
So how would I know what list?
I have already discussed this in my previous lectures.
So if you want to either you can use follow Foud, take any variable.
In this case, let's take a course in.
The list what is the list data causes?
So this is the list, so when you read this, they're basically.
False starts and it iterate over each and every element in the list and for every iteration, every
list item will be stored in this course variable.
Now, if I try to bring to what happens here, let's see, Brent goes.
So now when I run this particular file, every time, one item in this list will be retrieved.
So in our case, we know that list to have three items.
So that means it in the first iteration, a dictionary will be printed in second division.
Second dictionary will be printer let's controls after 10.
And you'll see that so far every iteration it has been internal one item of that list because data,
of course, this is what we are iterating now and we have successfully printed these three items.
Right.
So now in every iteration, this course variable holds a dictionary, isn't it?
Because the item of that list is nothing but a dictionary.
So our goal is to print if title is our right.
So once we get the dictionary, you can write this print course.
So after you print your course, we will carefully check because this variable is now dictionary is
isn't it goes off.
Right.
So if I'm reading one step, which will tell us if course title equals to R B, so when you run this,
make sure to have an indentation.
So this is important.
So you start off a here.
So as these steps belong to the outlook, make sure you know exactly.
Starts from this C not from the beginning.
So called in addition to having this must in paper.
Right.
Because you don't have any calibrates like in Java.
OK, so what is the step now so far the nation once it printed then it will quickly say Kosoff title.
So this dict study of title, it will retrieve selenium python if equals to Arpey.
No, then you can skip it when there is a match like this then.
Now let's say it will come back for the first list.
And secondly, there is no match.
But when it lópez-istúriz in third time then goes matches with RPI right at that time when there is
match.
OK then come inside the safe condition because at the match time this course variable is calling the
third dictionary right.
So then only it matches.
So when it title matches without fear, that means discourse is now holding the third dictionary.
So now your goal is to get price so you can simply course get me the price so that you, if condition
will go into the step only when there is a match.
So then it will reach refortify in your output.
Right.
So this is how you can simply write a logic to tell your python to extract based upon your requirement
supplies.
Of course, Arpit.
OK, so let me run this loop.
Sorry, I gave a wrong step.
Control shift after.
You see that finally it printed 45 five, so let's come in the spring because it's no more required
for us and perfect.
So the RBA title is 45.
Let's compare it with this character, not it finally got in second index 30 index.
You see that title RBA is forty five.
So basically this is it's reading from which Philco to start descent rate.
I will make one modification here.
So instead of having this title at the end, I will write it in the beginning.
So we will see if this costs, if this score is still valid, because our overall goal is to get rid
of that index and use the concept of decent rate.
So this is dynamic basically.
So it varies every day.
Let me make sure everything is correct.
All right.
So I have saved this file.
Now, RBA will come in the beginning, but still Cordwell smartly identify when the title matches and
it will print your output so the value should not change.
So that means good, our test is now not depending upon any kind of indexes, so you can start having
some sessions to see if it is the actual price, because in real time, when you start reading test
cases, because if you want to validate the coastal regions fortified, then you would assert and cause
price.
Whatever you have matters with whatever you can say equals two forty five.
All right.
So let me run this and you'll see that test is pass.
You don't see any failures.
But if you try to write any for 50 or some other value and try to run it again, then it will definitely
fail, saying that is an assertion error.
So this is how you can put validations.
But if you want to do and string.
OK, so I have shown you the logic of accessing the elements, right?
So once you access the content, you can start using the assumptions to test your ideas and find out
if it is returning as expected with this asset statements.
So that's how you can actually use the logic and validate without depending upon indexes in your words
and fight.
OK, so the days and whatever we have used as a tool of the complex and if you are able to pass this,
you can pass any kind of dissent.
OK, so in the next election I will show you how to compare two different files and confirm if they
are same or not.
It should be very simple.
We'll see that in the next lecture.
Thank you.