So one last and important topic before we wrap up a testing discussion is how to send attachments,
throw a cold sweat by Python Request Library.
So some of your apps are required to send attachments to the server and to get the response back accordingly.
So how you can send this file attachments?
Let's see.
It's very simple.
So if you see this documentation of a request, then search for files.
You see that post multiple might be and Gordon files.
And this is topic.
So here these guys are sending an attachment, you can see that they were using a dictionary again in
dictionary.
The key value is find what they want to send and value.
It is the attachment.
What do you want to send?
They were sending in the open mode, OK?
They were giving the access to read because that is important, right?
If you are sending the file, you have to give the permission of how this file can be used by Python.
OK, and this is how you need to send your file.
Once you have this entire dictionary in one file object, then just like how you have used in the previous
letter, like cookies equals to that variable here file sequel's to send that file.
So this is how you will send it in attachment.
Let's do one practical example for you to understand this.
So.
There is one area called Pet Store DARD Swiger, not able you can just Google this and Google this in
your browser and you will be landed on this webpage.
So here there is an API which will help you to upload an image.
OK, so this is an end point.
OK, you have to take us back to this pet store, Durchslag and I will slash Baggaley slash upload image.
So this is completely foreign and this is a post request, OK?
These are the parameters, but it is something you have to pass.
You can give any random idea.
And you have to send fine, which we just saw how to do that.
Here you have to send file information.
So in response, you get back to an interstate escort and it will give you information whether your
attachment is successfully uploaded or not.
So let's see this case.
It's very simple again.
Let me start with attachments.
So there you are.
Here is.
Pet store, this is the best you ought to have to start with.
And after that, see, I'm just using whatever the information I'm having here.
OK, so this is not something which I'm doing with experience.
So basically, once I land here, this is the baseball and this is the resource.
So to get an end point, you have to concatenate these to which I did here, OK?
And these guys are telling me this is a post request.
So simply requests dark.
I would use post metal and I will send this to you all.
OK, and next, they were saying to upload an image.
So one is a bad idea.
So here you have to give the real elite.
So this is like a placeholder to provide, but it.
So let me provide one idea, which is a valid for this so you can use this nine, eight, four, three,
two, one seven.
So I have seen this in one of the examples that Despedida is working so you can use this, but this
is existing territory for this database.
So far this pettily we are uploading an image, right.
So this parameter we have sent, it is still metadata.
This is optional.
You can ignore it.
And the fight.
So file you have to send as an attachment.
So files equals to and send that complete.
File variable, so let's create files variable here, just like how it was given for us in documentation.
So I am copying this, the sample given for us in documentation.
Right.
So this is a dictionary.
And key value is vital must and here you have to provide the file.
What you want to send as an attachment.
So I have one file in my system, just a PDF file.
And he made it so that I will give the part here.
OK, so basically I'm telling that go and upload this file as an attachment to this app.
Right.
So I'm using open because whenever you are sending any files, you have to tell on permission basis,
you are actually sending it in Python.
OK, so you are aware that we are opening this file and read more if you have any questions to understand
this.
Well, I taught my Python basic section there.
I have explained different permissions and how to open the file.
So assuming that you have watched this that video, I'm giving you this.
So basically you are sending file input, right.
So this is a variable.
So files equals to face that time.
Now, this call is made.
Now, when you submit this, you are going to submit the supposed to call with an attachment.
That is the magic.
OK, so you get your response back in any variable, let's say, are.
So spaces here, it's not quite.
So if it is successfully sent an attachment, then you should see this data score 200 nice, right?
And we will also see the response just to see if it is successfully uploaded or not.
OK, so if it is successfully uploaded, then you should get a response back as 200 successful operation.
Awesome.
That's all right.
So that's how you attach any files, whatever you want to your API.
OK, let me run this can BroadSoft often and this will give us the response back.
OK, so it complaint's not found, so we made some mistake, so it is saying that you all itself not
found.
OK, let's try to investigate.
I think I got the issue already.
So if you carefully see here, they were saying baseball is a pet store.
That's why I got to that.
I was like, OK, so you can read here.
So in our case, we missed.
We do.
So on top of all this, basically what you have to give this Rizzo's name, right.
So we took from you all, but not here.
They have clearly given that this is the place you just because you have given wrong baseball, it could
not find this address in that sample and it given you the four, not four not found at it, OK.
So let me run on this one more time.
I hope this time we have given correct in point.
But fact you see that it gave us 200 status discord and it's me today that we did not send anything.
So here they were asking to send additional metadata.
Also a description about this document.
I did not pass this because I saw it original, but you can see that file uploaded audio being so the
file is around eighty one thousand eighty five bytes.
OK, so this message concludes that you were fine.
Not being with these many bytes is successfully uploaded to their server for a better idea of nine eight
four three two one seven for this very your image is now successfully uploaded.
OK, so this is how you can send any files as an attachment to your API request calls.
So just follow that official documentation and then you will understand how to use this efficiently
already.
So that's pretty much about this section.
And here I'm wrapping up this API discussion.
We are still not done.
In the next section.
I will talk about databases and how to retrieve the values from database tables and thereafter once
you get that concept.
So now we have given the API payloads everything in our test files.
Right.
So instead of having that payload information for an book, everything from testifies, we will dig
those values from database tables.
OK, so our payload, Jason, payload for our API input request will be dynamically generated from database
so that we will start from next section.
So meanwhile, if you are looking for practice to get any interview questions, assistance in this on
state we are testing, you can message me because we are done with all the concepts of API automation
that's just retrieving from databases is the only thing left now.
So reach out to me here and I can help you with Python Rest API interview questions which will help
you to clear any interview regarding Python API testing.
OK, thank you.