OK, so I will go back to the webpage, and our next goal now is to open each and every TV episode here
and then see what type of ginner it is.
So that is our next goal.
So right now we just scrambling and give the guidance only let's move further.
So you have to go to the next debate and find out the gender, but how to go to the next debate, that's
tricky, right?
So how to do that?
Let's see.
These are all different tools available here.
Right.
So in the last lecture, we just understood that we can grab the content with the help of text method.
We also understood that you can apply find a method on your soap object to find and narrow down your
Hesterman results.
And when you apply, find all that will give all the matching results back.
These are the three methods we learned now.
So.
Your next goal is to reach the spit, go into this space, but we don't know how to navigate to that
page, right, because the link is not displayed anywhere here.
So how to get that link?
If you're smartly absol on the Antaria, you apply DOT text so that it gives the title.
But there is another attribute called Hedstrom.
So this attribute is nothing but a link to that child page.
Now you are on this page.
So to navigate to another page, you see that whatever you have here titled three seven one three three,
everything is here.
So that's a basic right.
So how to navigate to this specific title?
Suffit that link is displayed here.
So we should write some logic.
That we have to extract this order and then concatenated with I am the dot com, slash this head through
that logic here is like you copy this completely Babycham the dot com slash and pasted here so that
you will go to that child a bit of this movie.
So this way we can get you on it because you are is most important for us that you are alonely.
We will do this request also that we get the hestia content.
And from that historical content we have played beautiful stock to access Hesterman.
So that way we will scan again this entire page and then reach the genders to figure out what is present
here.
So to scan this child web pages for each and every title, first we need to know you are and then only
you can do.
And we have a clue here how to get a you are on a headset in fact.
Right.
So now let's try to construct a child a you with the help of this.
It's simple, guys.
Now, you are on this anchor, right?
So this frontal lobe actually lands, and every time when it runs, you will land on this anchor.
You earlier you used to get vital, but now you need this attribute value.
So to get attribute value so you can use the square bracket and give that attribute value that's up.
So when you apply this automatically, you will control.
Well, first of all, rich there.
OK, and then it will see what is written in square brackets.
If you say it's ref and the total value.
Will be extracted, so let's store it in the one variable again, Saburo.
So now this new order will help us to navigate to the next debate, right.
OK, once you get a subdural, let's do one thing.
Again, I will use this request to get.
Plus.
Start a game, so you have to start with I am David Dotcom, this is the bed and you are right on this
parent you are in.
Not required because that slashes is already coming from here tided.
We will concatenate with this sub.
All right, so that this all will be hit and the quest will make a call to that and we will create the
end of the object like this sub data.
So this is this now holds a title page of your title.
OK, so this title Childbed is now stored here.
Once you start here, you know that you can apply a beautiful silk method to convert that into SoPE
object.
You can again use a same beautiful soap method instead of data.
This time we are grabbing some data, not content investment.
And you can say any child soap.
Awesome, looks interesting, right, and now you have the content of this page, Aspen, so your goal
is to get this generate.
So let's try to inspect the system and object.
Comedy, OK, so basically this general value is here.
So this is the class C more in line can rap.
And from this glass, we will actually drill down to this and create that one thing, the same strategy,
guys, what we have done earlier, you have child support right now.
Let's find child support find.
And first, let's give the tag name Cardell because find my daughter will accept Tognum.
But if you use only this, there are so many depths, so you can't find this uniquely.
So that's why we will use a called classic wants to see more in Canberra because that is where this
general is wrapped.
So to give any attribute, you have to use mapping here.
So.
Glass.
Colin, and what is that copy be the name.
So this is where you are getting the general value.
OK, what next?
But this will not help you, you are not exactly on that committee, right?
So you are just on the main title.
So now to drill down your reasons to anchor.
So let's say you just need faster, General.
Let's not pull up.
Everything will become the first one.
So your next goal.
Jenner on this drill results.
OK, now we drill results and now you're soap control is only under this package.
When you use Jenner now it will start only inside because we narrowed down our results in that Jenner
dart find.
So it will search only inside that.
So what should be fine now?
A anchalee, so there are only two tanks here, right?
So instead of trying to drill down your results, Father, I can use Dorottya directly and this will
help you to go to that DIAGNE just like how we have gone here.
Once you found your results from that result, you are drilling down your results to Anchorage.
So don't give that tag name, so you will reach.
OK, if one or two tanks are present.
You can do that.
And once you reach here, what you should do, you should extract the content, how to extract the content,
not the text that we already did that text.
OK, and to see that output in the output can print.
All right, so what happens now?
What this court is actually doing, let's try to understand.
So here all the rules are grabbed of this in this variable, and we are using one furlough so that every
time one rule will be picked.
On that road, you are actually going and getting that title and you are printing it, and next you
are also taking that separates you are from that place and you are constructing a new are to navigate
to that page as well from Main Page and some you are and you are making a request also that you will
get soap object again.
Right.
So this is how you create a soap object for this child.
Guess once a great soap object and then you are dealing down your results to exactly.
Come to this, Jennifer.
So once you reach here, your actual value is present in Anchorage.
So you are moving there with a dart and once you are there, you are calling text method to extract
the content.
So this will repeat for you each and every story here.
So here also it will go to the next page.
And for all that TV episode titles, it will go to each and every page now.
And it will give you the.
That specific Jenette, or whatever you have, you see that how easy it is to scrap it.
If someone asked you that, I'm sorry, there could be some positive results on this base right now
showing two hundred only.
You've done a thousand movies displaying here.
And if you want to know what is the gender of each and every movie, that you can only get that by going
to that base and figuring it out.
But now, with the simple script, you need not go to thousand pages.
Even if you use any selenium frontin framework's to get that title, you have to go to that page and
again grab it and then come back.
So here no more browser browser itself will not invoke and not transferral pages.
Simple code.
This code will help you to scan some pages also of all these pages and will give you the content.
So it's cool, right.
That's where web scrapping comes into picture.
So if your goal is only to extract content from various pages, I would recommend using this web scrapping
instead of any fronton frameworks.
So let me run this.
And see, what are the results of a millgate control shift aften.
OK, so OK, first of all, this thriller, it's a comedy and next movie, also thriller drama, and
you'll see that crime framed music so fast it is showing the title because we are first printing printed
title and we are printing generalities.
So it is successfully going to the also and grabbing it.
So this way you can grab the data.
So in data science projects, people use all these concepts to get the data from multiple pages and
they prepared our data analytics.
OK, so it failed here.
There is a reason which I talk in the next lecture.
So we actually started working and we are seeing some results out here.
So let's continue and see what's going wrong here.
There is one technique you have to use, which I say next lecture.
Thank you.