Welcome back.
I hope you have figured out that issue, so basically let's try to see this for a loop.
If it matches with ESPN, it prints the actual book.
OK, but for Loop is not stopping here.
OK, so it's still continuing, right, though?
It matters.
We were not insisting any way to exit, so it just found and it went into a condition and printed the
actual book thereafter.
It continued to iterate through every list and finally it either rated this Java withdrawal should be
like the last item of this response.
It either deleted.
And now I tell bookstore's this last response, OK, but we thought we are looking at this response.
So basically, once you find your actual book, you need to give the statement break and then it comes
out of this loop.
If not, it will still continue iterating through other items present in the list.
And finally, it got stopped somewhere at the step.
And that item list is stored in your actual book, and if you are comparing that with your idea, it's
been obviously that will be a failure.
OK, so that's the simple trick we have missed, right.
So now let's try to run this program again.
And you see that there is no error.
Now everything looks smooth, so this is how you can retrieve the specific values from response by writing
the logic and compare that items with your expected response lists.
OK, and we have also seen headers.
You can do cookies as well, state escorts and passengers and crew.
So that's about get ready for request and let's do it under his stewardship request, which is a post.
Right by Tom.
First AP example.
All right, so let's go back to the documentation or we can use our postman also at the book.
Now, two things let's do here.
We will at the book and we will delete the book.
OK, we will go back to back these two operations and post is the history method supported for these
two operations.
OK, so let's get started.
It's also very easy.
Yes.
So.
So the same documentation, what you'll see in the academy outcome is what I have written in this post
manual, so you can either refer this or that doesn't matter.
So if you want to refer this story to our test, let's do that.
So can't I open with Google Docs?
OK, so this is our best you all so far.
Now I'm writing it here, but in later letters based on what else could come from any global properties.
OK, we'll see that soon.
So first, you need to import the question again, the first step.
And remember, because we have used to because that has to do with metal.
And this time or GDP method is forced.
OK, so it goes dark, forced.
And please observe here.
First one is that you are basically water and the resource and next the data.
So basically enforced, you will send the data in the form of decent payload.
OK, and get in this location.
We got parameters right.
We have used balance query parameters in get tested equipment.
That data is sent in parameters.
So that's why we use up bottom here.
But importantly, we make that data is sent as a decent.
So that's why you are seeing another parameter called data here.
All right, and next.
You can pass the head all this stuff, just like I have done here, so see post and first one is to
provide.
The basic moral value service services hosted.
Slash.
And then library slash, what is that?
You can simply copy this resource.
This is a resource which you are trying to access, right?
So I will soon change this with you are to who should be Economy.com next second parameter should be
the Jason.
So there are multiple ways you can send this, you can see that data is one parameter, but you can
ignore that and you can use.
Evalu value colleges and also you can see that you can simply pass this, Jason, equal to automatically,
it will detect the input request.
Whatever you are sending as a Jason.
So use this decision equals two.
And here you have to give the payload.
So as I told you, for any forced request, you will have a decent payloaders input.
In our case, we need to add a book.
Right.
So all the details like what is the name of that book, ISBN?
I'll remember that after everything is present in your work, Jason.
So this data you have to send with your ad so that Saravanan will store these details in their database.
So that's the overall point of this resource.
So our book is the API, which will add book into the database.
Which book you need to add is what you have to send from your payload.
Right.
And this is the decision you have to send for post coast.
We will come like this.
OK, so let's go back to editor and you'll need to simply based this Jason here.
You can pass it here.
And this is Jason.
Right.
And this is the second argument.
So what we need now.
We have given the payload and the base you order, but in our earlier lecture we have given parameters
but had to be given as a destination.
And do remember that when you pass through our Jason here, so you will get some errors in this fashion.
So if you think that it's accurate, then you can say, ah, enter and then say ignore errors like this
so that, you know, this will go away.
OK, but make sure you exactly paste however you get from your word document.
So if you go any spaces here and there, then Jason's structure will change and you may not get expected
results.
So whenever you based any Jason, get this copy from that word document and exactly.
Start from here, Jason equals two and then based it control of so that it will come in this fashion.
Do not disturb or give any spaces here.
If you see any errors like this underlain just type of error, you just cannot enter and you can ignore
them.
OK, but you can keep it.
That's fine.
Those are not real.
It's just like a Bible stuff loaded with it.
All right.
And the next one is ahead.
So if you see your postman.
Are the documentation so here is not mandatory to pass, first of all, but just let's pass the as well.
So it's good to pass a header with content type applications like Jason, because here you are sending
content and Jason format.
Right.
So you have to clearly tell in your request header that the content, whatever we are sending, is a
decent and as a tool.
If you need to give any hurdles, you can simply say, hey, this equals two and all that you need to
pass in a dictionary format, just like how we have passed all parameters in a dictionary.
Similarly, Hidatsa.
So you have to send in a dictionary format.
OK, so one here.
What we have is a content type.
And in addition to that, you have to give a column and then password and other key value of that dictionary.
So if you wondered, like, how would I know that Heather should be passed in the dictionary, all this
stuff, then you can go through the official documentation request, start read the dogs, start over.
So this is the library we are using to automate EPA testing and Python.
So they have given clear documentation on how to automate using this reckless celebrity.
OK, so I'm showing you some examples, but later you can leverage your process and based upon your
project requirements, you can go through this document if you think that you could not find anything
over there.
See now, for example, headers, right?
So you can come to customers and you see that these guys have passed in the dictionary.
They created one variable and sent these head of some dictionary.
And finally they sent this variable inside of this.
OK, same thing we have done.
So we directly copied this and we pasted here.
OK, so there is a concept of optimization yet.
So right now I'm copying it everything in this argument.
But in the next lecture I will neatly bring all this you all headers from different places by building
a framework.
All right.
So if you want to like how would I know all this, then this is not official documentation where you
can go, but based upon your customized requirements on some days and the last parameter is now optional
if you want to give any arguments so you can just leave blank by giving come on and close this record.
So it's here that exploded on the same step.
And that's say you have successfully provided that you are and where you are, the cost is present and
you are treating that request with this spillar and you are also adding headers to your request.
If you have any excuse to add, you can just go ahead and add cookies as well.
OK, but in our case, we don't have any cookies to send as part of our input request.
So when you hit this and run your program, this will submit our book and the book will be created.
So the response was carefully captured and book response into one variable.
Let's convert that response into this.
And you know that there is a method which will help you to get a response.
And Jason, because when you add a book, this is how you should get a response, successfully added
an idea of that book.
This is what we need.
OK, so first, let's bring this response up and make sure this book is unique and it's not already
present in database, as I have given this format.
Obviously, there are many people who maybe already submitted this book details.
So ESPN and this combination should be unique for you to create a book.
If not, it will give you an interesting book.
Already exist.
Now, for example, if I try to run this again.
This is the new book, right?
Submit this book again and you'll see that ad book, Operation Fail, looks like a book already exist.
So let's make some changes so that it's the unique.
And others book, we should be small, little, OK, so that's all.
So let's run this program now.
And they should and the book perfect, you say that you got a message saying book is successfully added
and this is the book idea.
OK, now you see you can clearly see that this time the response of the decent print that has a dictionary
in the previous lecture, it printed as a list, isn't it?
So if you see where did we use that?
Yeah.
So when we try to retrieve all the books then it retrieval in the list format with square bracket.
But when you add a new book this time that came as a dictionary, OK, you need not worry about all
this automatically.
This matter will take it based upon the response of our readers.
So now what type of this and response are decent is the dictionary.
OK, let's compare.
I would take this into one variable response, Jason, and if you try to print the type of this, let's
see what it returns.
It should be dictionary now.
So based upon the nature of your Jason format, it will decide what kind of data it can give you.
They see that it's dictionary now your goal is to extract irony of that book, it should be simple,
right?
You'll know how to do that.
So in response to our Jason, you can simply idea and that's it.
And you can stop that and Sivak book.
ID equals to.
This one, right?
So this way you will get into this variable now you are going next is to delete this book.
So now you have successfully written a code to test advocate.
OK.
When I say testing, you can add validations.
So I'm not going in depth again and having all validations.
It's up to your imagination, like how many validations you can add.
So I'm showing the process.
You can then have a session on status score like Ad Respon starts data score, Darksiders Dargis and
you can do whatever validations and put a session and you call it asset testing.
Right.
But I'm showing you the process and concept of automation here.
So my next goal, after writing a book.
Yes, we have successfully added we need to delete the book.
OK, and for delete it will alienate.
So if you want to delete the book, it will simply ask, give me the irony of the book, which I want
to delete.
So I have added this book and I have grabbed the itinerate.
So basically I want to, again, immediately delete the book with the same idea, whatever I added here,
so that it should add and it should get delete immediately.
So not next picture.
Let's like the code to delete the book so that it will be like an end to an automation script for EPA
testing.
All right.
Thank you.