Welcome back.
So in this lecture, I will quickly show you how to compare to Gessen's, because that is also one of
the requirement you frequently get when you are trying to pass Gissen files.
OK, so it should be very simple.
Right now I have two different files with me.
Soccer star Jason and I have created another file called Courts One Dardis, and both are in the same
pot as just different files, right.
So I would write for 50 here.
However, I think we have updated the index right now comes on the 1st.
So obviously these two are different points.
So you want to compare these two files and tell if they are correct?
Right.
So for that, you have to open second file also.
Basically, you have open court dates and file as read more and you have read it and you read all that
and you have stored in one dictionary.
Our overall goal is that like there we will open another file and that file also we will read the content
and we will store in another dictionary.
And finally, we will compare this to dictionary objects that say it's simple.
OK, so first, let's create two dictionary objects.
One dictionary will hold the content, of course, Dodgson, and let's create another dictionary, which
will hold it up.
Content, of course, one Dargis.
So we already have one dictionary data with Goldstar Decem.
So just like the previous example, start from the beginning because you are no more in the in this
F object loop.
So same step, no change.
I would it here because one dot, this is the new film and you can give me another object called a fight
and you should simply now convert this file content into this study.
You know how to do that.
So there is a method, Courreges and Dark Lord, which will dig that a file object and we can simply
store in another study.
I can say this too.
Right?
So I have now two dictionaries or you can say Datatel because we have declared one dictionary as data.
Right.
So this object stores this content and this object stores this content correspondent adjacent.
So what you do now, you need to compare these to dictionaries.
OK, it's very, very simple.
Yes.
So data equals to the title.
That's it.
So here you are comparing two different dictionary objects, so this will return true if the competition
is equal.
Obviously, this will not be equal because we have changed the content.
And correspondent Jason.
So let me run this file and see.
You'll see that it returned false, so that means these descents are not the same.
OK, so if you want to achieve the same in Java language, you have to end up writing a lot of code
to compare to different files.
But in Python, it's very simple.
You have a superb method called law, which will simply convert all your content into a dictionary.
And then you can just compare dictionaries, isn't it?
But to make your test pass or fail for you are back on the automation, you have to use a statement
asset, right, so that, you know, if you are asked to compare distance and return the output test.
So this will return.
True.
And if it returns false, what test will fail because you are using assumption of false is false.
Right.
So let me run one more time and you will see failure.
You see that assertion error.
So now I will go back and update the content.
So whatever I have in this file, I would just replace it here.
Is it replaced?
Looks good, and now I should not receive any error if I had done this one more time to see that everything
is bust, so that how you can compare to Jason.
I think we covered pretty much about how to partizan.
We also understood the logic of passing it without relying on indexes.
And we have also seen how to retrieve how complex the decision is.
It could be a list dictionary or a string.
And we have also seen the difference between Lord and the Lord's methods.
OK, so with this knowledge we will jump into AIPA testing and then also we will use some Jassam responses
as validation.
OK, there we will try to implement this knowledge as well.
So this way you can learn both API testing as well as complex tests, decent passing.
OK, and once after this, we would introduce database step by step.
We will build on our automation suite and how powerful utility is ready by end of this class.
OK, thank you.