Welcome back.
So there is an Arab price to do for most of the cases, but for some cases it failed.
So that means you really want to carefully it's online?
No.
So it says that money type object has no attribute it.
So that means for each and every title here, it's going to take place right on the page.
We were trying to find Genom.
So in one of that time, the page basically this is not displaying we don't know which pages.
There are so many records.
Right.
So this is not displaying.
So this object is returning money.
So when you are trying to go to the anchor from none, it thrown another thing man type object.
So whenever it fails to find any element on your webpage, then you will generally see this error.
So how can you and why did this set up?
So when you are retrieving thousands of moveit is somewhere, one or two may not have that.
So you are scripter should not stop because of it.
Right.
So one simple trick, what you can do here.
If let's have one if condition, if this condition is true.
So basically, if there are results, then this will give us a clue.
If there are no results, then it will give us a number.
So if of this condition so if no results are written, then these two steps will get skipped.
So that's how you can simply avoid that issue.
OK, here's polling convention matters.
So when you write this condition, this should go inside of that.
So tomorrow, whenever you run this game, when it will see if it's written on paper or not written
sometime, it won't go inside this.
So you want to run is actually this land, right?
So it will all go inside because we have given this condition.
If it is true, if you find element, then only execute all this.
OK, this way you can apply to the up.
Right.
And let's put some condition so we know how to read through all the cards.
You are retrieving now.
Generally scrapping is something that you want your desired results.
So you are getting all the generals here.
Let's say you want a documented results.
So there are thousands of movies, but you are a guy who is most interested in watching documentary
category TV episodes.
So what you can do, you can write a script and say that gave me the movie titles.
If that movie title Agenor is documentary.
So you are scrapping script should automatically scan all these titles, go to the pages, find out
the gender and give you the output.
Right.
So here we are printing blindly all the Jenners.
So let me put some condition.
If gender, whatever it got for you with dot dot text right here is where you get you it out.
But if it is equal to.
Documentary.
I think one space is required here because you'll see that it's coming with one space in the beginning.
So that's how our developers have written this.
Right.
So when it is documentary, then we are asking you to print it.
So basically this will not help us.
So I will comment out of title, which is the title we are waiting for in print.
Here, so let me cover this.
And I like it here.
So this time it will not blindly print each and every TV episode, and it's it, so it will only print
TV episode title if that Agenor is a documentary.
This is how I designed with this condition.
OK, so this is now having some real shape.
Our web scrapping script is intelligent to find, but TV episodes of are documentaries.
That's where we build our script now.
OK, you can actually print it out real time.
You will.
People generally take it into list.
OK, so if you are aware of Python, you can actually create one list with any variable like OK, so
I would give a small little L I equals two.
This is a blank list.
So I'll print it at the same time, I will take all the title names into one list.
So that by end of this fallopian list will be ready, which have all the titles of movies with the Jenner
documentary.
And finally, I'll print this list, OK?
Right.
So let me run this again.
And if you are researching further in your data science projects, you will take this list because now
this list holds all the data of your documentary generally and you can use it.
OK, so what's happening here?
So let me comment on all the remaining prints, so this time it should only print out four different
documentary matches, I'm sure that I commented about everything.
All right, let me run.
So it will take some time because earlier every second you used to say output, because we are blindly
printing our TV episodes, but this time you see that it's coming only if that channel is documentary.
So it takes them around three to four minutes because there are some hundreds of results here.
It has to make service calls to your main page and also submit and retrieve the results.
Right.
So it will take around three to five minutes based upon how much data you have to scrap and it will
give you the results.
You see that only document related TV episodes are coming into your output.
So that's the coolest future of scrapping.
So as a tool in data science projects, people will do all this clapping and take the results into one
list or tuple or any other Python data types, and then they play with it.
So it's the key principle.
Find the data and play with it.
They get the data using web scrapping and then use it for the algorithms and they will start writing
real data science related algorithms on the data.
What you found and they built all research report on that.
Right.
And that's why people heavily use web scrapping.
So if your goal is to extract only content, I would recommend you to use this instead of using any
affronting test automation frameworks.
So this will take some time to then I'll put on a bus and I'll bring back again once you see the complete
output.
All right, execution is completed, and you'll see that one list is prepared with all the movie titles,
with documentaries in it.
So this is how you can play around using web scrapping.
So I will give you one example as an assignment in the next lecture.
And that is one more topic left that also we will discuss and wrap up this discussion.
So by the end of this lecture, now you'll understand how to control the classes.
Also using that you are in construction and you also now know how to get attribute of any e-mail with
the help of words that we have had today.
Yeah, this is the method you have to use and square bracket to get the attribute like this are the
two takeaways you have to take from the last two letters.