Welcome back and let's quickly right up for the book as well, and if you check out that book documentation,
it should be very simple.
I think that's the last AIPA we have here is.
Like, so the same baseball, 216, whatever you have, and you have to add this resource and that will
be the post, and this time, as in December alone, you have to send 80 of the book.
OK, earlier you have sent the details of the book, which needs to add it.
And for the book, it is expecting this.
So basically, this is how you get a contract.
As I told in my previous lectures, if somebody tells you to do Abia testing, they have to give all
these details for you, then only you can test and write automation for it.
So you yourself do not have any knowledge about what should be your input payload and what should be
the result and what kind of history department that it is.
It is the duty of a developer to share all of this so that you can properly test and write a script
for it.
OK, so this documentation is a must and you can just demand from you.
There have been.
So requests start forced and you're not the best you are.
So this is the best you all.
And slash and library, the lead book, this is a resource.
OK, and next you have to pass to Jason, right?
Jason Carroll still so you can.
Give does Jason, but the key point here is that according to Station Fastforward, the fatal error
is gone and the idea here is not death.
So basically, your goal is to delete the book, which you just added.
So you order this book and idea of this book.
We have smartly grabbed into this variable rate.
So let's bring that variable here so that at runtime first it will add the book, it will store that
book in this variable, and then when it tries to delete the book, the boogity, what you stored there
will be placed here so that it gets this will get deleted.
OK, so this is the data driven mechanism, right?
So this data we are getting from our previous just variable.
Awesome.
And you can pass again.
That's just like how you have done in your case.
And that's it, and this is how you can send another post request, because this is also a post request,
if you have any other operation like food or delayed, then you can choose that aspect of and request
or you will get the latest GDP matter.
And if you have put history department, you can simply request.
So right now, in our case, we have to actually we might have to get and post the concept the same
guys.
You just need to change the history department, their name based upon the EPA matter.
Whatever you are, you have if it's a post and you post here.
All right, so I will take the response of the book into one variable, and my next goal is to see if
this operation is a success.
So I would say not a status called.
And then it should be 200, right?
Let's see are the work is a 200 status like having a session?
Right, next, once the book is deleted, you will get response, something like this.
Output responsable book is successfully deleted.
So let's have a session which will try to get the value of this message to be equal to book is successfully
deleted.
OK.
So for that, first of all, you have to convert that into Jason formatter, Jason, and then take that
let's.
Jess, Jason, some variable name.
OK, now this Holstead Jason response, and you can see that the response, what you got is in big study
format because it's not in square brackets list.
So obviously this is not header.
Right.
And this is the response.
Yeah, it's still in the dictionary.
So if you want to access this message.
So you have your extended I with you, with you and Jason, and you can simply pass the message key.
So that valuable military.
So let's bring this first and then I will write one assertion that Assir whatever the message I retrieved.
Should be equal stole, our book is successfully deleted.
OK, so when you run this, I think this time it should fail because it's trying to add the book again
with the same details, you already ran the score and you have added the book with the same details.
Right.
Whenever you try to add again, then it will complain that our book already exist, then you won't get
it.
So it will fail here, then you won't get it.
You can't understand it.
So to create a unique book, you have to give the unique combination of ISBN.
And I'll also make some changes here so that it will return as a unit.
And also we have seen running the test by having the body of the design inside the file.
But in real time, it's not good practice to have this entire descent in your testified.
So they should drive it from externally.
OK, so right now I would try to create one more class and I will drive this different data from there.
OK, so let me show you.
It should be a simple fix, but this way we will have some cleaner code here.
Paillard So basically all the ballots for our test will come from this file.
OK, let's create a simple function here.
So I would say our book.
Payload.
OK, so inside this function, I will first create one string equals two, and then you have your bell.
All right, so let's call it from our word document so you can access this document from Rovell.
Should be Economy.com slash practice projects.
Awesome, and then finally, we will return this.
Return 40.
So currently, file is not formatted, so we are concerned it will ask you to reformat file.
So this way it will be exactly in the correct format.
OK, so make sure this court indentation is properly aligned.
You need not do anything.
So it will steal, just like I did here.
OK, so there is a function which will accept you payload and return it.
OK, so you are storing the entire payload in one variable and you're returning it so you can quickly
call this method directly in your API example.
So remove all this.
Yeah.
And this and the payload.
So right now we don't have available of this function reading here because.
So this isn't another file.
How would you tell your Python file to imported from that special file.
OK, so far that from payload is seven and under the filing right from payload you can simply say import
stuff.
So that means it will import all the functions or methods present in this payload file.
So you need to write the syntax like from payload import start.
OK, reformat the file and everything looks good.
And so if you want to send the unique values every time instead of going here, let's parametrized this.
So we need some Espin and I'll combination unique.
Right?
So far I would directly call here I SBM and this is when I would drive it from my test.
OK, so this is coming as a barometer.
So from my actual test, I would send that SVM value.
So let me send some random value so that at runtime this value will come and fall here and from here
it will be placed in this area.
So that very unique book details will be created every time so that you won't get and Branning to duplicate
things.
So make sure you update this parameter.
That's it.
So that will take it.
So, all right, so that's all we have.
So let's run this test, because we made a little optimization of having this payload from another funnel.
Make sure you have only a single slash here.
So I still believe we have given one.
What's left apart from that?
Everything looks good.
So let's run this test.
Perfect, you see that book is added and it is also successfully deleted.
You did not fail because it ran and got data scored as 200 and we are accepting into it.
OK, so you added the book and you deleted.
So you need not worry about changing this ISBN every time because that book did not exist.
So when you ran again, it will firstly add and delete it immediately.
So this way you can validate both ad and delete book apps.
Right.
But right now you have driven this entire payload from this file.
But in coming sections, I will introduce database and we will dynamically build this from the values
present in database.
That will be very interesting topic.
OK, so in real time, when someone are you to ask to add any books every time a stock will be there.
Right.
All those details may be present in database.
So basically you should add them from database and push it to some other service.
OK, so you need to dynamically drive all this from your baby tables and construct this design out of
it, which will be seeing incoming sections.
So for now, this is how you can achieve this concept.
And then we'll leverage this with more optimization by removing this endpoint and obsessing over the
next lecture.
Thank you.