OK, so our goal is to sum the all the records amount so far that we have to fit all.
So let me do one thing.
Should I comment on this?
Yes, let's come in.
Right, and then I will execute Curser, not fit all.
So this will get me the all the rules, so let me have it one variable.
OK, so we know that when you run this virtual rossville written a list, so if you are not sure.
So first try printing it print type of loss because it returns a list of tuples.
Lexi.
I can see that it's the last.
Next, we have to read through that list now, OK?
Our goal is to either read that list.
So let's also bring Rose to see how that list displays so that we can try it better.
So one thing, one, you started that connection at the end.
Let's close it, because if not, it will open many connections and that will slow down your sexual
integrity.
So, OK, let me close the connection at the end.
Let's give it the last step.
OK.
Right.
So this is the list we need to pass.
So let me iterate through this list.
So once we understand this is the list to iterate, I would use one for loop for a row in a row.
So basically now this for loop I direct and for every iteration, one row will be picked for the first
time.
Facebook will be picked and that will be stored in this role.
OK, right.
So here what you have to do.
So once it's stored in the row, basically row is a couple.
OK, so let's say I iteration starting first time.
This complete roll is picked from this list.
Now what you should do, you have to pick a moment.
Right, because you need to sum up so amount is zero.
First, second.
OK, so this is a couple now.
So basically it is nothing but this one.
That middle aged here.
So every iteration, you will get something like this.
Right now from this, you want to get em out again, this is a couple, so I would simply say a rule
of two.
So this will give me the amount, OK, and.
Let's print this and see if it is correctly giving amounts.
So now if I underscored it should simply display the amounts of every arrow, OK?
Awesome, you see that one twenty forty five, ninety nine, all right, now our goal is to sum this
up.
OK, so try to understand I'm just making you hands on free to understand how to retrieve the results
from database by having the queries.
OK.
All right, so I will initialised one variable called sum equals to zero.
And simple logic, what I would like is some equals to some place.
Rule of two, this is not a.
Yeah, so now first iteration 120 will be picked.
So some zero zero plus 120, some will become 120 in next iteration of those forty five previous summits,
120.
So 120 plus 45 will be stored here.
And next iteration 99 will come here is ninety nine ninety nine plus previously some of 120 plus forty
four.
So like this for every iteration, this number will be summed up with the previous sum and once you
complete the full up, finally you will have some value of all the elements.
Like I think we have done this example already in Python basics.
So let's come out of our loop.
So this will basically be an incremental or some value.
And finally, once you come out, bring that some value.
I know when you run this, this will give you the final sum of 361, great, so that's how you can play
with the data of database, right?
Using a python without depending upon any l'état like this, without relying on this, you can simply
form the connection and get all the good results by giving the commands.
Now we just saw only select right now let's say update that are a few more current operations like insert
update, delete.
So let's also see that now, for example, I want to update our customer info table.
So this is our customer info table, right?
So I want to set location.
To us.
To what so we're basically for Dimitar, I want to set location to us, so they, of course, mean I
assume that you have basic knowledge on Cequent.
OK, so we I'm not going in depth to explain, like, what of the Kuwaitis and how good I did the basic
assumption of, you know, this Kuwaiti.
Right.
So basically, this is a table.
I'm updating location to use their codes name equals to Daym so far, the middle class name.
We are changing the location from Asia to U.S. So when you under Squaddie, then that will update it
to the U.S..
Yeah, that is an error here.
What happened, you are using safe mode, updating or trying to update the table.
OK, let's change that.
So give this guy a reset sequel, save up next to zero so that he will be given permission to update
values and tables.
OK, let me run this again.
Perfect.
So it got changed.
Now I call this the results again, now this time for Dimitar, you'll see that it updated to us.
OK, so that's that's how you can update the value in tables using the query.
Now, our goal is to update this from Python.
OK, it should be simple.
Yes, very, very simple.
Same mechanism.
What you have done.
Cinder blocks liquidated here.
So I will write that query in one variable, so let me write it in here, so put it in strings, so
write your code and have it in strings like this, like mixed.
So basically you can go hard core values.
In your string, or you can drive it externally now, for example, here, location equals two percentile.
Yes.
So that means one spring should come here.
So we have not hard according the values.
This is the core QUERREY work, which is not having values, values that we will pass in another percentiles.
Again, when you use our percentile as it stands for one string will come and replace it.
Right.
And this is your body.
So write your query and store it in one variable so that queries should be generic without hard coding.
Any values now create one tuple.
So you know how to create double right.
Double syntax of creating something like this.
OK, if it is the list, as I told it this way, now you need two values here for this.
One is the location and one is the code name.
Right.
So location.
Now, U.S. is the one it's already there.
Let me turn into UK.
Gunma and of course, name and let's use the same Jimm, right, and store this stuff all in one variable.
So basically you have two variables here.
One is a string of generic query and the another is a data which holds the actual values of what you
have to provide here.
You can connect these two smartly with your cousin, right.
You know how to execute query that we have already done concertante execute.
So same thing.
You can provide a game Cassard Dart execute, but this time you'll first send this query so either you
can directly align this inside our store it in one variable and you can call like this also.
But if you think this query needs some values to input and make sure you have a variable as a table
and send that tuple as you get to that argument, that's it.
So then at one time automatically Findon have intelligence of taking this tuple and it will place in
this query in this percentiles in the order place.
So you can sit here and then we will sit here so that my data and query should be separated.
That's the best practice.
You should not hardcourt so that tomorrow, if anyone want to use for another location and of course
name, they can still use this query variable.
And since the second argument.
Right.
So once you do that, you have to commit Eurocorps.
So basically we're updating it right after update.
You have to come in to commit that so that it should be done on connection.
So connection is gone.
Right.
So as I told, Casser will help you to streamline between your baby to your python.
It can send a query and it can return results.
But if you want to connect, commit database level, you have to again choose connection, your main
object.
Not coming.
And that's all.
And now when you run this query, this will now update the table and right now it is showing as us,
right?
So let me run this.
Program and bold shift after.
Perfect, so it's updated to know that you call this stable a game and watch out for this location.
It's U.K., it's no more U.S. So that's how you can also update your other database tables from your
Painton with a query and making a smart data driving externally front table and you can delete also.
Now, that is it's all the same, guys.
So I gave you syntax.
You can use any Quirino.
OK, so no matter what you do, you have a pretty direct one.
You can go like this if it expects any values to be part of quality, you can use this way.
So as an assignment I will give you a delete.
Right.
So if you want to delete this web services rule, this is the command, right.
Delete Web services.
And give the condition where God's name equals to live services.
OK, so this query will help you to.
And so this is a table in, right, sorry, so delayed from this table where Qassemi services will now
you're right, you are a python executed method, just like how I have done here.
Is that.
Yeah, right.
One more method which can delete regard from your database, so this way you can play around with your
database table results using Python.
OK, in the next lecture, let's see how can we optimize by doing this connection externally in another
fight.
Right.
Thank you.