All right, so these are the global properties, host, database, user and password, so those should
be driven from this property is not identified.
OK, so those should not be hardcoded in want test on any python face because these are global and should
come from here.
So let me create another section.
OK.
This stands for sequel.
So here you can start writing the user password and the database, which you want to connect and the
four students, so everything we can derive it from here.
So let me quickly copy all of this.
Localhost.
And databases fighting automation.
And for.
Like, so, however, all these configurations should come from here.
Nice and connection related stuff also ideally should not be in you were actually testified, so they
should come from another utilities file.
So to make that happen, we will write one utility method which will start connection to your database
so that any tests can simply call that method to have connection into the test.
Right.
So to do that, I will copy this.
I think we have properties.
Configurations, right.
Right.
Sort of get Conexion.
And you can buy something like this, but here.
It has to import my sequel.
Make sure you import my sequel, Dark Connectors, like and these details, it's a very long string,
right?
One good thing about this kind of metal is that it accepts a dictionary.
Right.
So let's do one thing.
Let's create one big snoddy variable and assign all these values in that dictionary.
And you can simply write the dictionary variable limb here.
So instead of writing all these details here.
OK, let me show you.
It should be very simple and that is the very clean way of writing and establishing Thinkwell connection
in Python.
And so we would quickly create one big study variable.
I'll do it on the top.
So let's connect config so you know how to create a dictionary.
So this is a simple syntax.
This is an empty dictionary.
Right now, inservice, let's start writing Yuzu is the first one, I guess.
User column and give the value and what is the user value?
So basically the value is broad, but that value we thought of driving it from our properties start
and.
File.
Right.
So get config will give you the.
Actual config access, so.
Get config.
S. is a sequel in sequel S. Earlier, we have given absolution and then.
User user is the guy you need, they so user is the guy and siecle is a section.
So create function, it's already dead, right?
Oh, it should be on the top, so basically it should be before that so that it can detect you see that
at Krischan.
OK, so this is how you got to use it, and next is a password.
Password?
And the same.
So basically, you are creating one big snotty object that said all the details you can pass as a dictionary
object and you can simply passed this dictionary very and said this instead of giving all this.
Password.
And next is the host host.
Is a database state database.
It's up to you if you want to drive database from externally or if you can hardcoded it directly here.
Anything is fine.
It depends upon your project related process.
OK, if you are project have multiple databases, then you can't use it in global property here.
Right, because some test may use another database.
And if you globally like it, everyone are forced to use this database only.
So it depends.
If you think there is a specific database for every test, then don't like it here.
You can drive it from your test.
So let's assume here we have only one database.
OK, so you created one simple dictionary variable or you can safely study object.
So in that key value based on that user password Holston database, basically these four values we are
giving here.
Right.
Instead you can create a dictionary like this and you can simply provide the dictionary variable here
and that's it.
So you need to give to stats.
So that will clearly tell that whatever argument I have is nothing but a dictionary.
OK, so that is a representation which will help you to identify.
You see that how clean your code is.
So earlier you have everything here and you have a dictionary and in that big study, so you don't have
actual values.
Those are smartly driven from you were not.
I am a global fight.
Right.
So this is how we have segregated everywhere.
So that you have written in modules.
Now, so you have the right, I guess, mechanism here, because if something fails, you should know
what is that?
So for that, let's say.
Right.
So basically, this is the meter perimeter will run this.
According indentation.
And here we can see if connection is there or not is connected.
Then print.
Connection, successful, something like this, we are writing some logs to understand.
Successful.
What if it fails?
So let's also return this connection so that any file can call this method so they will have access
to this connection variable which you created here so you can simply return gone so that, you know,
they can access this connection.
So that is the one.
And next, whenever you write right, then you should write gatch mechanism as well.
So in Python, Katz will be written as except OK.
And this mystique will throws it up.
Right.
If it connection is not there, it will try not to understand that error.
You need to import one package because using that package only you can retrieve that error.
So once you import this package from this package.
My sequel, Dart Connector.
There is one method we can say import al.
So this mother will help you to give the details of what exactly went wrong, so that will not present
by default.
You have to import it and that will be available for you.
So except Aaron, AC.
And you can print that.
So basically now if something goes wrong here and this adult object can read and understand what is
the reason for connection, failure because, look, if it fails, then only it will go to Gatesville,
right?
So this will get the error.
And you are printing that error as reference so you can see it in the output.
What exactly it went wrong?
All right, guys, so that's it.
So you have successfully implemented prickish mechanism and remember, you are returning your connection
object so that anyone can use it.
So that's the overall point here.
So what is the matter here?
Remove trailing Blackland, OK.
So you have successfully created one good connection method.
OK, so now let's go back to our file and here I will come on this.
So basically, you have this connection object from that method as well, right?
What does that mean that any resources is?
Good connection.
Get connection and you have to import.
So from utilities.
We want to import all so that this connection will also come into picture that your utilities start
configurations is our final name, right?
OK, so you can store that connection because we are returning the connection object, isn't it?
So when you go to get connection method, so here we are redoing the connection.
So that will be cast directly here.
And you need not worry about all these details.
All the details have been already taken care and get connection.
And they are coming from that extended here and from this study we are bringing from my friend.
So this is how you can segregate.
And now when you run this file again, that will not have any errors.
So just to make sure this is a real test, you're going to have a solution.
So some is 361, right?
You can simply assert some if you have anywhere that you are.
If you're not already the total is 361, then you can compare like this so that if something is wrong,
your test will fit.
All right, so there is another human type object use connector line number eight.
Oops.
So user is rude here, not local post host is a local host, user is a rude password is place at the
academy.
So now I come back to my python file and now I will run this.
That so that it has to be same, just like how they have run previously, but with configuration changes
as we are driving it from external face.
Let's see, you see that 361 same result, nothing fell and then also passed and we have smartly driving
all these connections externally.
So this is how you need to optimize it without using all the details here.
So with this knowledge, let's go back to our API test and there we are to hardcoded our payload.
So if you go back to your payload file, this is how we have given.
Right.
And now there is a table for us which gives us the book's details.
So let's take one draw from this table and then we will build it this, this and dynamically and push
it to our API request so that we can conclude this database plus API integration.
OK, we'll start that from our next letter.
Thank you.