Welcome back.
So let's go to our agenda and see what we have accomplished a lot so we know what our future definition
files and behave.
We also created we really structured in our project so we can return existing EPA test also in military
style.
We also understood the importance of context available.
Right.
And the next one is to see how to achieve data driven and how to do parameterization of your test with
multiple datasets.
This is interesting.
Now, so if you see this step, you are actually hard coating the data here.
OK, every time we are coming and changing the data, you need not change because you are cleaning the
data at the end.
So that should be fine.
But what if you want to run any EPA test with multiple data sets?
OK, so that it could be a scenario that you want to repeat during a test with different data sets every
time.
Let's see that.
How to do.
OK, so in our case, let's assume that we want to run over a big test with different Aspendale combinations
every time.
OK, so let's do one thing.
We will add I'll also and put it here so that this method now will accept two parameters.
I spin and I'll let slide one which find from that file we will make sure this feature file ran with
a different data sets each time it has to pick one ISBN and I'll combination.
OK, let's see how to do that.
Before that, let me give some numbers here because we just changed that method signature so that it
also will be now sent as part of your method.
Great.
So if you want to add to parameterization, then here you have to.
Give me a second.
Yeah, so you have to use another key word here instead of scenario use scenario outlined.
So this is the key word you want to use if you want to parametrized who are testing multiple datasets.
OK, so select this.
And it will show an error, so if you more about cancer, then it will create examples s. what is this?
So let's see that before that, let me do one thing.
I'll copy paste the same scenario.
I'm done.
Make sure you go back one step, because when you got a scenario, it should be here.
This should not mix with this.
Right.
But I want to repeat this test with multiple data sets.
So I will add a scenario outlined.
And when you add this, it will complain to an example section.
So let's create that.
So what is this so here where you can send your combinations, so I just thought that let's run this
just with ESPN and I'll combination so you can send those values here instead of hard coding in your
test methods.
So now we are sending these values by hard calling it from here.
Right.
Let's change that.
Let's bring these values from our feet.
And finally, because this is the best practice the values data should be in your scenario so that,
you know, you want to be a business analyst, product developer.
Anyone can come and give the data here because they don't want to really care about what exactly is
doing.
Let's say you are a business analyst, knows the data, so you can just share this copy and she can
read it because it's plain English so she can read it at ESPN and Elle values for you.
But if you read somewhere like this here, she can understand where exactly she has to act because this
is a technical write.
OK, so let's add those values here.
It's very simple, guys are just like smart people have you create Excel.
So under this ISBN value will go.
Let me give some random spin and as a gift pipe symbol so that it separates from ESPN.
Give any I lember.
And that's say this is one combination.
Now, if you want to run this dust scenario with the another combination, then add another.
OK, so another data sets and this is a new data set and you can give new and perfect the see.
So you have two data sets now.
So this test will run two different times each time.
It will run with one row.
OK, so with the first row, it will run the list and again, it will end with this test.
But no actual problem here is how these values will now come into this method.
OK, so let's not hardcourt now.
Let's load this in this way.
Our values should come and fall here, which is a tricky.
OK, let's see.
I will go back to feature file again, so the changes, what you have to do here instead of giving this
plane line.
Let's modify this line like this, given the details with ISBN.
And I OK.
Make sure you write the same keyword, what you see here.
Exactly here and put them between arrows, if you do like this, then behave, treat this as a barometer.
Right.
And now when you run the scenario, given the details with these two, Aspendale, I'll write whenever
it sees Arrow, then it will immediately come to the role, what it is executing, and it will try to
match once a match found, it will take that value and place it here.
Similarly, when it's IAL because it is in arrows, it will again search in the same room and when the
rule matches, it will take this number and place it here.
So this way from here you can send these values to your definition and write the logic there.
OK, so right now we don't have the same definition implementation for this because this is a new method
which we just did.
Right.
So let's add that I'll come to some definition.
Let's not disturb this.
For that, I will create another given.
Given.
Yeah, the book details right here, you have two cats with curly braces, so the value want to have
provided they're ISBN will just come and sit in this cuddly bracers value here, right?
Let me show you let's try it amateur here so you can use a the same def.
Step, Bill, you can you see same name doesn't matter only thing which is here is this one.
So fast parameter should be context by default, because context value is past now two values you have
to give here.
One is Isbin and aisle, because this line is sending you two parameters to your meter.
Right.
So these two parameters are coming from your feature file because supertitles like this, this will
feed with these two values.
So once these are freed it now, those two values will come here and from here.
This will fit into your method in these locations.
I aspinwall exactly same word.
Give it here.
So the value, what it comes from feature will come here and you can use all this inside now.
So you have a combination of SBN and I'll with you and that's all.
If you have these details, you can just directly reuse this code.
OK, and instead of this, instead of hard core values, you can send ISBN somewhere else.
So this is how you can write a generic script which big the values of Isbin and able to create new book
ideas from your feature file only.
OK, so now if you go back to your future file now the book.
These two values are constructed from the values of your past, from your future file.
You understand, right, how we connected all this from this add also connected and from it's coming
here from here to here and then here to actual matter.
And once you get into this matter, we are again feeling it in our dictionary object.
And from there we are sending the body.
So this is how everything is connected.
But we are doing it nicely from frontin with these values.
And if you provide another layer like this, the same scenario will repeat a second time so that with
multiple datasets now your book will be added.
OK, let's do one thing.
Let's run this and see how this goes.
This time it has to run through scenarios.
This is one scenario.
And here with the two rows, two different scenarios with two different datasets total three scenarios
has to them.
After every scenario, we have a condition to go and delete that book.
Right.
So it looks good.
Is there any changes what we need to do here?
Let's see.
Nothing, these two are common matters, adding the book and book is deleting it can be commonly used
because once you have your all contact details, it will just take the values here.
OK, let me run this time and see how that goes.
OK, execution is going on good, as I told total three scenarios around this time, if you see feature
file.
Because this ran two times with two different data sets, total nine steps for.
Three here, three plus three, six plus three main steps and nothing is fail, and you can see every
time it created a new first time, it's the data which is directly present in their definition and it
is deleted.
And next time you'll see that the device.
That is that, yeah, FBI eight four eight nine four, and this is the beginning because the logic of
creating it is a combination of ESPN and I right to see that book is at it and it is deleted.
Similarly, there is another book with the word seven six three is atter and deleted in.
Clean up environment.
So this is how you can data drive your test cases with the different data and you can also parametrized
them using examples, keyword and scenario outlaying.
If you don't mention all Glenden parameterization will not happen here.
You have to make sure that you write this line and give me a number of photos.
If you have 100 datasets, you want to run your test, then provide 100 Russia and that's Cucumber's
or behave takes care of running it 100 times.
You'll see that without writing any follow ups are conditions.
We are able to achieve it simply by writing in plain English.
So that's the beauty of reality brainwork.
All right, let's continue the next lecture.
Thank you.