All right, so in this lecture, I will show you how to add to tagging mechanism in the frame, but
let's say there are hundreds of desolating and scenarios and if you want to run only a set of tests
to get us out of 100.
So how would you differentiate them so you can tag them appropriately and you can tell you what to behave
to run only those tag the scenarios.
So now, for example, let me tag this with a small test, and this is a regression.
Actually, we have to do this in regulation, we will run with the different data sets, but with smoke
you will just run one dataset, just assume like this.
So you'll have hundreds of tests here and filters automatically with smoke.
Field tests are marked with regression so that you'll know when to execute what.
So if you were scenario is to run only test guesses, which are a mark of as regression.
So right now there are two, right?
So if you want to run only test with the smoke or regression, then there's a simple way and be able
to do that.
To do that.
So you already gave him.
And which futures you want to run, you can give that filenames locks for no capture and then you can
give banks back sequels too, and you can tell which dog you want to run.
Let's say I want to run only smokestack.
And now when you run this command, it will execute only Fuster scenario and it will skip the scenario
which is tied up to this lecci.
So output this time should be only one scenario past.
You see that only one scenario passed and two are skipped.
Watch out here.
Two other scenarios.
Also, we have here regression, right?
These are two because we are running with two different data sets.
It's clearly telling that I ran only one.
I skipped two because you asked to run only smoke related tax.
OK, so similarly, if you want to run only a regression, then you can just mention the only regression
and this time it will run those two scenarios.
You see two scenarios, only one is skipped, which is the smoke, so if you see the outputted.
Exactly.
And this so this I think is very, very important.
Guys, in real time, you will have it on at least 50 to 60 death cases.
And it's not that every time you run all the gas cases, let's say you are working in this ajai sprint
of two weeks and the sprint you call a Sprint 15, then you mark those test cases as Sprint 15.
So whatever test cases you add newly in this sprint, you are Sprint 15.
So before Sprint goes to the list, you want to just check that all the functionalities of the sprint
are currently working fine.
If not so, you will just go and you can just go and run.
Only those scenarios every day will come blindly here and give that back one sprint 15, that's all.
It will just go and pick up those discuses which are tagged with this sprint 15 and those only will
get executed.
Restante will be Skemp.
And this is very frequently used in real time automation projects.
And it's very simple and easy concept.
Right.
You just need to remember how to tag with Aderet and how to give that tag equal to regression here.
Stanning OK, I hope you are clear with this functionality.
Thank you.