Welcome back.
So let's create our future file, so instead of an ebook I want to showcase now and another topic,
because from that topic, I want to explain new concept here.
So we have seen data driven parameterization that are still another way of doing data, which I will
talk now.
And we also saw backs and hooks which are environment python files, and we will see how to set up and
deal down matters with combination of tags and hooks.
Now, so far that I can demonstrate you with another example.
So let's go back to our airplane called what we have written earlier.
And so there is a GitHub stuff we have done right using session.
So let's do this now.
I will create another feature file for this.
And let's call it as a.
Get help.
OK, now you can give that to me here.
It's up to you.
So featured name here is.
It helped.
AP evaluation and scenario, you can save session management, check something like this.
And you want to give your steps here, start with given.
You have to have your credentials with you.
You think I have GitHub, you need to have credentials.
So what do you want to do when?
Remember that it should always be gaps when I hit Get Raipur, because that's what we used here is slash
user slash, right.
So let's call it as it gets.
So when I hit get triple AIPA of GitHub, then what happens then?
Let's verify that status called.
Of response should be two hundred, so this is what we want to verify.
OK, so this is the feature file in American language now of you have to write the actual implementation
by defining that in step definitions file.
OK, so I don't want to write it from scratch.
So what I will do so behave in features.
I will just ask to run get that feature then.
We did not have any step methods for this.
Right.
So this complaint me with the logs saying that you have to implement all this so that I can blindly
copy all of this and write the actual implementations.
So syntax is ready.
You have already here.
So let's go to the standard definition file.
And here.
That's right, there are some.
OK, so given I have GitHub credentials, so let's bring that actual record of having that credentials.
So let me copy all these authentications stuff and then we can partition this just like we have done
earlier for our Arabic.
OK, so let me and I did hear.
So we are now creating one session.
Requests darte session.
And.
These are the authentication details.
So what we need not need this.
OK, let's remove all this.
Basically, this is the court we want to check.
So we created such an object and for that session we are authentication and then we directly call this
GitHub user you and we are seeing this data skorton if it is 200 or not.
So this is the code what our get confused file system.
So now let's partition this.
So this step is about having GitHub credentials, so make sure you as an object is set up with all the
details.
OK, so what you need here is just an authentication.
So you have certain authentication here and you create a decision and the next step is a hip GitHub
repo.
So that means this one is the don't get is what is actually hitting that to then get upset about it.
And you get a response back and once you get a response back, you have to print that and make sure
that status code is 200 Zinder so you can write it here, state a score and you can have an assertion.
Check that a third respon star status for 200.
All right, now let's fix the issues, what we have here, context we have to make.
So we are creating a session and we are using that session to make a call.
So this session is not shared with multiple steps.
So you have to store that bit of context to not see.
So same thing.
You have to do it here.
OK, and you all, too.
So why is this here generally all the what we are writing it in some files here, right?
I think resources.
Yeah.
Here where we are writing that resource files.
Right.
I would say GitHub.
Rapport equals two, right?
This is what you are in.
So you can call that directly in your step implementation, just like how you call a resources start
and book, so.
If resources start, get habitable perfect and you can get rid of this, you.
And Sishen, we can call it with context, darte session douget, and you get a response back and response
also, you should store it in context variable so that you can access this response.
And then finally, you can make sick perfect, I think we have fixed all the issues and you see how
cleaner our core looks like now.
OK, so if you go back to a future, fine, given I have odd credentials.
Yes, we have loaded our station object nicely with all the credentials of what we have and the next
we are hitting that API request.
Yes, the is made and the finally the future.
What we have is check status quo should be two hundred and see that we are seeing stereoscope should
be two hundred so we can generalize this as well.
Now for example, STADA scored here.
You can give any number here, let's say, if you want to check state escort four zero four, then you
need not right again in your definition here.
So I will show you how to make it generic.
So I'll put 200 here.
And in my definition file, I'll have this.
And this is like this.
So let's call this as a status quo.
OK, so this way, we are not recording that 200 number.
We are driving it through a variable.
So 200 is an integer, right.
So for integer you have to be so that it treats it as an integer.
Nice.
So if you have any other status to check, check the status quo is 400 or four of you can still use
this method.
Now, for example, the state scored what you think 200 number will come here member will be, let's
call this a C and I can use this here.
Perfect.
So this method is not genetic.
This can check any status, but it can be two hundred four hundred two, not one four, not four.
If you have any code.
We are just checking the status quo.
You can still use this.
Now, for example, here, the status quo should be two hundred.
Right.
I can reuse this in book AIPA then book is successfully added.
You can have and if you have multiple validations you can use any operator and you can write that step
here.
OK, it will be still treated as part of then only because you are using convection with it then isn't
it.
So here it's giving us two zero zero as a response, but let's still put to zero one and see what happens.
It will fit.
OK, remove this then.
Then is the keyword.
Right now I am reusing this step again here.
It is not complaining.
That's the definition is missing.
If I click on this link, it is still taking me to this method because we made this data score genetic
so that I can reuse it anywhere.
You just it's the status Kotick.
OK, but if I don't make a genetic like if I say it should be two hundred only by hard coding here like
this.
So for every state I scored I will end up writing a letter like this.
So I had made it genetic here.
So this way if it is two zero zero two zero one four four for any record, I will blindly reuse this
step and then change the number.
OK, now what book?
API feature.
I'm using two zero one here.
Let's see what happens.
But it returns to zero zero, so it should report as a failure.
And also one thing you have to remember here, if you go to the STEM definition file.
So the state has scored a divorce verifying for Pondexter dot response, so GitHub is giving you that
response property so it gets the status quo out of it.
But if you want to reuse this for any other methods like Adblock, make sure that ad will also written
in context dot response only.
But here it is reading different response, context, dot and underscore response.
OK, so if your response is getting stored in this property called ad book and direct response, so
how will you how will you utilize that here?
Because this is looking for a status called front response property, not from the ad book underscore
response property.
So if you want to reuse, you have to maintain some consistency in your framework.
So for every response you get, let's keep some convention that it should always look like this context
dot response.
So make sure you update everywhere for your ad council.
So this way you can use it for other definition methods as well.
I hope you understand if you try to run this without changing book, let's see what is the error we
get so that, you know, you will get some confidence on the things you are doing.
All right, so behave.
Very that no captivities book being.
So it should fail.
And capturing the response, OK, you'll see that these guard failed why they failed at line number
51 and here it is.
Why why it is failing at number 51, because this context to object have no attribute called response.
Correct, only.
Right.
Because we did not store any response properties here.
What we saw this to underscore response.
OK, so that's why you are not able to reuse it with the method which we used to get help so far, that
you have to maintain some consistency in that framework.
So use context, dot response everywhere for any response you get for any AIPA.
So this way you can reuse some methods without recreating it for every test.
I guess.
So context.
Our response here is we are using it.
I think that's all right.
OK, this looks good now and when you read it now, this time it will pass if you have two zero zero.
But this time you wrote us two zero one.
Right.
It will fail here saying status code is 200, but you are trying to give to zero.
Lexi, but before you go and make sure you update us, I told you no, because we have added a book,
but before deleting that book, it failed, isn't it?
So this is the feature file, right.
So after completing all these lines, you were delayed.
Book scripts will run from enviornment, that python file, but it failed at this length.
So that whole file did not run.
So this book got already stalled.
When you try to rerun, it will complain that book is already there with some issues.
OK, so make sure you put it on unit one and let's run this one more time.
And this time it has to give proper error.
OK, so one failed and the reason this time here assertion, and this is what we need, because it 200
baht in your record, you are saying today went to zero.
So this way I am reusing this in my book, AIBA Asphalt and the same method I am using here as well
with the 200.
Right.
So that's how we did a framework help us to avoid duplication of court by rewriting that definition
methods.
You can use the future Vilem.
Exactly so that you can use these methods.
So that's why make sure you don't hardcourt anything here.
Parametrized they don't drive these values from your feature file only.
OK, from here.
Let's continue running this in our next lecture.
Thank you.