All right, so let's run this feature file, which we have implemented in the last lecture.
So will this pass if I run?
So just think for a minute, will this pass?
Do you think that we have written everything correctly here?
And also to remember to check all other files as well, and we don't mind feature file step implementation,
if you consider all these files, then you will know that this test will fail.
Let's see.
Let me and I hope you got that idea right now.
So let me do one thing.
I will run all the test cases.
I will just use behav keyword.
So this should trigger all tests.
Right.
So I'll just use behavioral capture.
If I don't mention any feature file folder names, it will default when everything.
All right, so let's see, Tuffield, so obviously get will fail and there is another failure book about
feature.
Oh yeah, this is obvious because data scores should be 200.
That's why it failed.
So then why did it have that feature failed?
OK.
Let's investigate, and this is saying that who elab?
Do you remember that we have written something here that after every scenario, it has to go and delete
the book?
So obviously for this scenario, also session management, it's trying to delete the book.
There is the book.
Both are different apps.
Right.
Where is the book concept here?
So that's why when it is trying to delete, it did not have any book I attribute.
So that's what it complaint's context.
Object has no attribute card book.
OK, so remaining a feature files have the attribute because when we ran them we are creating one book
attribute so that becomes a deadlock us.
So how should we refactor our after scenario then.
So.
If you have some scenarios which are not related to your scenario, after all scenarios, you can actually
smartly skip them using tax.
Now, for example, for book AIPA, let's write back as a library because this belongs to library areas.
Right.
So whenever you encounter in new library a scenario, there will be obviously we will add some book
or we need to clean that data.
And at the end.
Right, let's assume so.
This is a getups scenario.
OK, I don't want to add any tax here.
But I can tell now to my environment fame that run this scenario only when you encounter a tag called
library, OK, so it will come right and execute this only when it encounters library time.
That's how you should give the knowledge.
So this way, this will skip GitHub feature because GitHub scenario does not have library tag.
So we can ask you to skip that.
Right.
That's how you need to build logic.
OK, it's very simple.
Guys, let's do that now.
If.
What is our technium debate?
Let's get that Diagne library.
If library back is in what scenario, if you carefully observed there is one object and variable passed
as a parameter to this method.
So this parameter will have the knowledge of the scenario, what it just ran.
OK, so in what case we will reach here after we execute any scenario successfully, then our control
reaches here.
OK, when it reaches here, that scenario information will be holding in this object so you can select
this scenario.
So this scenario object calls all the details of that scenario, so scenario dark bags, so that will
get that tag of the scenario, what you just ran, because some scenarios should bring you here in the
end.
So that scenario information will be here.
So when you see a scenario that tags.
So which scenario brought to you that let's say you went there after this scenario, so then use a scenario
that tax liability will be extracted so that all the information will be automatically passed to this
object.
And as we have this as an argument you can use like this, if not if library, is that bag present in
the scenario what you executed, then go and execute this.
This is how we have to build the logic.
OK, so let's take care of this cord indentation that these mandatory.
OK, so when you close this method, everything gets closed.
So that means you have successfully implemented indentation as well.
Great.
OK, so this one step will solve all our problems now.
So get up when the scenario is executed.
Yes, obviously it will reach this because that's how we define.
But when it's a scenario, not tax library, library is not that here.
So it will simply skip this because this complete code will execute only in this if condition matters.
Right.
So this if conditions do not match up, so it will not execute anything in 30 days.
So this is how we are solving the problem of executing the scenarios which are not related to your test.
OK, so I hope you now understood how to integrate tags and hooks.
That's what I mentioned here in my document.
So Bill set up and tear down methods with military tax and the combination of these two is required
when you build this, because not every scenario will rely on these hooks.
Right.
And forget get if you have another book, you can write another method after scenario.
OK, so if you have a tackle, get help, then you can get how is in this one this on in the film and
then you can have another live condition.
If you encounter it back then that will run that specific goal.
OK, so this is how you can bring intelligence to human after scenario method.
All right.
So I will run one more time.
And before that, during and when it failed here, isn't it, if it fails, so it did not run after
2010.
So you have to, again, change and give the latest name for this.
So that it will be unique.
OK, so let me run this became no captor, so this time it has to learn all the scenarios present in
this fetus folder.
Look here, everything is past.
There are total four scenarios.
Yes.
To inform of example three here and one is giving up.
Everything looks past.
And with this examples, you understood many important concepts of BGT framework.
You know how to drive and integrate.
You will feature five scenarios to start definition's.
You also know how to date and drive by sending the values and how to reuse the same method.
If you by writing same gurkin language so that you can use this data score here and also here by writing
generic methods, you'll also know how to parameterize.
You want to test with multiple datasets.
We have also seen what are tags and how to use them effectively and we also saw what is what on different
hooks available and how to integrate backs with hooks.
And at the same time, we also understood the importance of context variable and the also importance
of having consistent variable names so that you can reuse in other methods.
So that's pretty much about the cucumber concepts.
But still, there is one reporting part left which obviously never makes later.
All right, thank you.